SAM: [Voiceover] When you love someone, you've gotta trust them.
当你爱一个人，你必须相信他
There's no other way.
别无它法
You've got to give them the key to everything that's yours.
你得将掌管生命中一切的那把钥匙给他
Otherwise, what's the point?
要不然有什么意义？
And, for a while, I believed that's the kind of love I had.
一直以来，我深信我拥有的是这样的爱
SAM: Before I ever ran a casino, or got blown up...
在我开赌场及被炸之前…
Ace Rothstein was a hell of a handicapper.
艾斯罗斯坦，可是最诺娜马预测者
I can tell you that.
我告诉你
I was so good that whenever I bet, I'd change the odds...
我旺到每次只要我下注，全国的赌盘赔率…
for every bookmaker in the country.
都会随着改变
I'm serious, I had it down so cold...
不盖你，我对赛马的研究精湛到…
that I was given paradise on Earth.
让我晋升人间天堂
I was given one of the biggest casinos in Las Vegas to run, the Tangiers...
我被升为拉斯维加斯最大赌场之一《坦吉乐》的管理人…
by the only kind of guys that can actually get you that kind of money.
唯有聘请我的那帮人才能如此大手笔
$62, 700, 000.
六千两百七十万美元
I don't know all the details.
我不知道细节
NICKY: [Voiceover] In fact, nobody knew all the details...
老实说，没人知道细节…
but it should've been perfect.
原本应该很完美的
He had me, Nicky Santoro, his best friend, watching his ass...
他有我这好友尼奇山多罗挺他…
and he had Ginger, the woman he loved, on his arm.
他手中也揽着他爱的女人，金吉儿
But in the end, we fucked it all up.
到头来，我们全搞砸了
It should've been so sweet, too.
原本应多完美
It turned out to be the last time that street guys like us...
结果，我们这样的小混混…
were ever given anything that fucking valuable again.
在这次之后就再也无缘搞油水这么丰富的大生意了
SAM: Vegas was a place where suckers...
那时的赌城，是蠢蛋们…
flew in every year on their own nickel...
一毛一毛存足了钱飞来…
and left behind about a billion dollars.
直到输光了家当才走人的地方
But at night, you couldn't see the desert that surrounds Las Vegas.
在夜晚，你看不到包围拉斯维加斯的沙漠
But it's in the desert where lots of the town's problems are solved.
但城里许多的问题却都是在沙漠里解决的
NICKY: Got a lot of holes in the desert...
沙漠里的坑洞可多着呢
and a lot of problems are buried in those holes.
里面埋藏了很多问题
Except you gotta do it right.
只是程序要对
You gotta have the hole already dug...
你得先把洞挖好…
before you show up with a package in the trunk.
再将货从汽车后车箱载来
Otherwise, you're talking about 30 or 45 minutes of digging.
要不然你就得在沙漠挖上个30到45分钟
Who knows who's gonna be coming along in that time?
谁又知道期间会有什么人出现？
Before you know it, you gotta dig a few more holes.
不知不觉中，你又得多挖好几个洞
You could be there all fucking night.
搞不好一整晚都得耗在那儿
THE STRIP - LAS VEGAS TEN YEARS EARLIER
精华地段-拉斯维加斯，十年前
SAM: Who could resist?
谁抗拒的了？
Anywhere else, I was a bookie, a gambler...
在别处，我只是个登记赛马的一个赌徒…
always looking over my shoulder, hassled by cops, day and night.
老是得小心翼翼，成天被条子们骚扰
But here, I'm Mr. Rothstein.
但在这儿，我可是罗斯坦先生
I'm not only legitimate, but running a casino.
不但不偷鸡摸狗，还管间赌场
And that's like selling people dreams for cash.
那就像是将梦想换为现金
I hired an old casino pal, Billy Sherbert, as my manager, and went to work.
我聘任了赌场的一个老朋友 比利雪伯当经理，然后开始工作
And this is Ronnie, who takes care of the card room.
这是负责牌室的罗尼
SAM: For guys like me, Las Vegas washes away your sins.
像我们这种人 拉斯维加斯洗去了我们的罪孽
It's like a morality car wash.
像是道德洗车场一样
It does for us what Lourdes does for humpbacks and cripples.
它对我们的效用就像法国露德 对驼背和残障的人一样
SAM: And along with making us legit...
不但让我们重见天日…
comes cash, tons of it.
还带来了现金，数不尽的钱
What do you think we're doing here in the middle of the desert?
不然你以为我们没事 跑到这沙漠中央干嘛？
It's all this money.
就是为了这些钱
This is the end result of all the bright lights...
这是所有炫目的灯光…
and the comped trips, of all the champagne...
所有的招待、香槟、免费住宿…
and free hotel suites, and all the broads and all the booze.
女人与喝不完的酒 最终所造成的结果
It's all been arranged just for us to get your money.
全都是为了 让我们弄走你的钱
That's the truth about Las Vegas.
这就是赌城的真面目
We're the only winners.
我们是唯一的赢家
The players don't stand a chance.
赌徒们一点机会都没有
And their cash flows from the tables...
而他们的钱从赌桌上…
to our boxes through the cage...
流入我们的收银柜再进入保险笼…
and into the most sacred room in the casino.
最后流入全赌场最神圣的房间
The place where they add up all the money...
他们计算钱的地方…
the Holy of holies, the count room.
注意-请勿进入 万物之首，计算室
Now, this place was off-limits.
这儿可不是闲杂人等可进出的
Even I couldn't get inside.
连我都进不去
But it was my job to keep it filled with cash. That's for sure.
当然，但我的工作是让它保持 满满的状态
NICKY: They had so much money in there...
里头的钱多到…
you could build a house out of stacks of $100 bills.
可让你用百元大钞砌栋房子
And the best part was that upstairs...
最棒的是…
the Board of Directors didn't know what the fuck was going on.
上头董事会什么屁都不知道
To them everything looked on the up-and-up.
在他们看来一切都干净俐落 没人动手脚
Right? Wrong.
不是吗？当然不
Verify $5,000.
确认五千元
NICKY: The guys in the counting room...
在计算室的那些人…
were all slipped in there to skim the joint dry.
都是被派进去将里头吸干的
They'd do short counts, they'd lose fill slips.
他们会少算钱，将计单弄掉
They'd even take cash right out of the drop-boxes.
甚至直接从箱里拿走现款
And it was up to this guy right here...
全是靠这家伙…
standing in front of $2 million...
站在两百万元前的这位…
to skim the cash off the top without anybody getting wise...
在被国税局或任何人发现前…
the IRS or anybody.
把钱摸走
Notice how in the count room nobody ever seems to see anything.
在计算室里 好像都没人在看
Somehow, somebody's always looking the other way.
不知怎的，大家都视若无睹
Look at these guys. They look busy, right?
看看这些家伙 他们看来真忙，不是吗？
They're counting money. Who wants to bother them?
他们在算钱，谁会吵他们呢？
I mean, God forbid they should make a mistake and forget to steal.
我的意思是，天晓得他们会不会 犯了错而忘记偷钱
Meanwhile, you're in and you're out.
这期间，你可来去自如
Past the jag-off guard who gets an extra $100 a week...
走过那些鸟事不干的警卫 每礼拜还多拿一百元…
just to watch the door.
只为了看门
It's routine. Business as usual...
一如往常一样规律…
in, out, hello, goodbye.
走进、走出、你好、再见
That's all there is to it.
就这么简单
Just another fat fuck walking out of a casino with a suitcase.
就只是个拎着皮箱 走出赌场的肥猪
Now, that suitcase was going straight to one place:
但那口箱子 会直接送往一个地方
right to Kansas City, which was as close...
堪萨斯市，那里是…
to Las Vegas as the Midwest bosses could go...
中部的老大能离拉斯维加斯 最近的地方…
without getting themselves arrested.
而不用怕被逮捕
That suitcase was all the bosses ever wanted.
堪萨斯市 老大们要的只是那口箱子
And they wanted it every month.
每个月都要
Now this old Mormon fuck here...
这个摩门教的混蛋…
he had to fly in with suitcases once a month, nice and easy.
他每个月都得拿着箱子飞来
-Something smells good. -They made us something to eat.
-什么东西这么香？ -他们做了好料的
NICKY: The bosses would come from all over:
老大们会从各地飞来…
Detroit, Cleveland, Milwaukee...
底特律、克里夫兰、密尔瓦基…
all over the Midwest...
整个中西部…
and they would meet in this produce market in Kansas City.
他们都会在这个位于 堪萨斯市的市场碰面
Nobody even knew it.
根本没人会知道
One of the guys made his mother do the cooking.
有一个让他妈做菜
Do you ever see that guy Jerry Steriano?
你有看到杰瑞史塔瑞欧吗？
NICKY: These old greaseballs might not look it...
这些老头们看来可能不怎么样
but believe me...
但相信我…
these are the guys who secretly controlled Las Vegas.
他们才是赌城的秘密操纵者
WOMAN: Mama, that man's here again.
妈妈，那男人又来了
NICKY: Because they controlled the Teamsters Union.
因为他们控制着 全美卡车司机工会
And that's where you had to go to borrow money to buy a casino.
而要开赌场非得到那儿去借钱
WOMAN 2: Would you put in shrimp? WOMAN: I would.
-你要放虾吗？ -我会的
NICKY: Nobody got a Teamsters' loan unless the guys in this room...
要是这些家伙们每月拿不到 这只小箱子…
knew they were gonna get their little suitcases.
那谁就都别想贷到款
Guys like this antique over here, out of Detroit.
像这从底特律来的老家伙
Or especially guys like Remo Gaggi, the outfit's top boss.
或尤其是像利蒙盖吉 这群人的首脑
You got a round figure on it?
有大概数字吗？
NICKY: Definitely the most important guy in this room.
绝对是这房里最重要的人物
FRANK: About 20 pounds. Around $700,000. REMO: Good.
-十公斤，那就差不多七十万了 -很好
STONE: It's a little early for Las Vegas...
虽说对拉斯维加斯还有点早…
but I want to welcome the ladies and gentlemen of the gaming industry....
但我想邀请赌博游乐业界的 先生与小姐们…
SAM: As far as the world was concerned...
就以世界所知…
Andy Stone, head of the Teamsters' Pension Fund...
安迪史东卡车司机工会 退休基金会的负责人…
was a legitimate guy.
是个清白的人物
A powerful man.
有权力的人
He played golf with the President.
他与总统一同打高尔夫
ANDY: On behalf of the Teamsters' Pension Fund...
代表卡车司机工会退休基金会…
I'm glad to present... SAM: But he also took orders.
-我很高兴将这… -但安迪也听命于人
When he was told to give a pension-fund loan to Philip Green...
当他被指示将基金贷款 贷给菲立浦葛林…
...this check for $62,700,000...
六千两百七十万的支票…
for the new Tangiers.
给全新的坦吉乐
...he did what he was told.
他就会乖乖听话
NICKY: Here was the perfect front man.
他可是最完美的傀儡
What the fuck else could he be? He didn't know too much.
他还能干嘛呢？ 他什么都不知道
He didn't want to know too much...
也什么都不想知道…
especially that the bosses made the Teamsters lend him money.
尤其是老大们让工会借钱给他
He wanted to believe they gave him the money because he was smart.
他想相信他们是因为 他的才智贷款给他
I say that knowing just how much competition we have in this city.
我了解这城市的竞争性有多大 才会说出此话
NICKY: And where they got Green from?
他们从哪儿找来葛林的？
Who the fuck knows?
谁知道啊？
All I know is that he was an Arizona real-estate hustler...
我只知道他在亚利桑那州 是个房地产经纪…
who barely had enough gas money to come and pick up his fucking check.
却连开来拿支票的油钱 都差点付不出来
And it was the bosses' man...
美国中部 卡车司机工会退休基金 是由老大的人…
Andy Stone, who gave all the orders.
安迪史东下所有的命令
Not the Chairman of the Board, Philip Green.
并不是由董事会主席 菲立浦葛林
I understand.
我了解
NICKY: Now all they needed was...
现在只缺…
someone they could trust to run the casino.
一个可信任的人来管理赌场
And who better than Ace? He was already in Vegas a couple years...
有谁比艾斯更适合？ 他已经在赌城混了几年…
and he had the fucking place clocked.
他对这儿t若指掌
But typical Ace, give him a shot to run a casino...
艾斯的一贯作风 你给他个管理赌场的机会…
and he tries to talk you out of it.
他还推三阻四
I don't know if I could do this.
我不知道自己行不行
The Gaming Commission would never give me a license.
赌博游乐委员会绝不会 发执照给我的
I have at least 24 gambling and bookmaking pinches on me.
我最起码有两打以上 赌博与赛马被逮的前科
You don't have to have a license to work in a casino.
在赌场工作不需要执照
All you gotta do is apply for one.
你只需要去申请
The State law says that you can work in a casino...
州法律允许你在申请期间…
while they process your application.
在赌场做事
ANDY: They got a 10-year backlog.
他们文件进度现在落后十年
What happens when they do find out?
若他们发现了怎么办？
ANDY: Why would they want to find out?
他们为什么会想发现？
We're putting $100 million here. Why would they lock us out?
我们在这儿投资了一亿 他们何必赶我们走？
ANDY: They'll never find out. All you gotta do is keep changing your job title.
他们不会发现的 你只需要一直改变职位头衔
Like, from Casino Executive to Food and Beverage Chairman.
像从赌场执行长改到 餐饮主席
Then they put your application at the bottom of the pile.
然后他们又会将你的申请表 摆到最下面去
I know guys who've worked there for 30 years don't have a license.
我有大把的员工 已经工作三十年了还没执照
It's a tough proposition, Andy.
这不是容易的决定，安迪
If I did it, I'd have to run it my way.
若我去做，得让我用我的方式
ANDY: You got it.
没问题
I'm serious. No interference.
我说真的，不能有干涉
Nobody's gonna interfere with your running the casino.
没有人会干涉你管理赌场
I guarantee it.
我保证
NICKY: And that's how they got Ace to take over.
艾斯就是这样接手的
They wanted him because Ace ate, slept and breathed gambling.
要艾斯是因为 他不管是吃喝拉撒睡时都在赌
They worked out a real cute job title, too...
他们还给了他个很可爱的头衔…
Tangiers Public Relations Director.
坦吉乐公关理事
But the only thing he ever directed was the casino.
但他只管赌场
He made his first bet when he was 15, and he always made money.
他从十五岁时第一次下注就没输过
He didn't bet like you or me.
他不像你我那样赌
Having some fun with it, shit like that.
就为了他妈的好玩
Where did you learn how to deal?
你在哪儿学当庄家的？
NICKY: He bet like a fucking brain surgeon.
他下注时就像是脑部外科医生一样
SAM: Place the checks properly.
筹码得摆对
-That's the way you do it. -Yes, sir.
-像这样 -是的
NICKY: He had to know everything.
他得洞悉一切
He'd find out the inside stuff nobody else knew...
他知道没人晓得的内幕…
and that's what he'd put his money on.
他会根据此下注
BACK HOME YEARS AGO Even back home, years ago...
在老家时 就连在老家时
when we first hung out, he'd know if the quarterback was on coke...
当我们刚认识的时候… 他都知道四分卫有没有吸可卡因
I'll take Columbia for $20,000.
我赌哥伦比亚两万
...if his girlfriend was knocked up.
或他的女友是否怀孕
He'd get the wind velocity so he could judge the field goals.
他会去测风速 只为了预测射门得分
He even figured out the bounce you got off different kinds of wood...
他算出了篮球场上…
on college basketball courts.
不同木材质地板的弹性
He'd be working on this day and night.
他从早到晚都在做这些
He knew everything about a game he would bet on.
他对他要下注的赌局 t若指掌
Ace got down at $6,000. Get me down at $6,000.
艾斯下了六千 我也跟下六千
NICKY: Season after season...
一季又一季…
the prick was the only guaranteed winner I ever knew.
那小子是我唯一认识的绝对赢家
But he was so serious about it all...
但他那么认真下注…
that I don't think he ever enjoyed himself.
在我看来他从不放轻松享受享受
But that's just the way he was.
但那就是他
Back then, the bosses didn't give a fuck whether he enjoyed himself or not.
当时，老大们也不会在乎他享不享受
To them, he was a cash register.
对他们而言，他像是棵摇钱树
All they had to do was ring the bell and take money.
他们只要摇一摇就可拿钱
Especially Remo...
尤其利蒙…
who was a fucking degenerate gambler who always lost.
他是个逢赌必输的衰客
All those fucking sweeps.
靠，这么多满贯
NICKY: Unless Ace made his bets. Enough now!
-除非艾斯下注 -真是够了！
NICKY: Ace made more money for them on a weekend...
艾斯一个周末为他们赚的钱…
than I could do heisting joints for a month.
比我抢劫一个月的还多
Whatever Ace picked up on the street, he told Remo.
艾斯将他听到的小道消息 都告诉了利蒙
Fixed fights, doped horses...
内定的拳赛，下了药的马…
crooked fucking zebras, locked-in point spreads.
买通的裁判，预定的分数
He told fucking Remo everything.
他什么屁都告诉了利蒙
And, to tell you the truth, I don't blame him.
说真的，我也不能怪他
Keeping Remo happy with money...
用钱财让利蒙快乐…
was the greatest insurance policy in the world.
是世上最好的保险
Son of a bitch!
王八蛋！
How did you get Oklahoma-Michigan?
你怎么知道是 奥克拉荷马或密西根
Nobody ever had Oklahoma.... How'd you do it?
根本没人猜到奥克拉荷马 你是怎么办到的？
That's why they paid so well.
所以他们才赔得高啊
REMO: You see? Never tells me nothing.
你看吧？ 什么都不跟我说
What do we got on for next week?
下礼拜的怎么样？
It's a little too early. I'll know by Thursday. Is that all right?
现在还太早了 我得要星期四才知道，可以吗？
REMO: You'll come by the house? SAM: I'll come by.
-你会来家里吗？ -我会绕过来的
At 7:00.
七点
REMO: Good job, my boy. Keep it up.
做得好，小子 继续啊
REMO: Hey, Nick.
嘿，尼克
I'll be right out.
我马上去
See that guy? Keep a good eye on him.
看到那家伙了吗？好好看着他
He's making a lot of money for us.
他为我们赚了很多钱
And he'll continue making money for us, so keep a good eye on him.
他会继续为我们赚钱 所以你得好好看着他
Not like the fucking Feds out there, without brains.
不像你外面那群没脑的政府关员
REMO: Okay? NICKY: All right.
-好吗？ -没问题
Want me to take this?
要我带走吗？
NICKY: Now, on top of everything else...
所以这么多事之外…
I gotta make sure nobody fucks with the Golden Jew.
我还得担保 没人会动我们的大红人
Couple of shooters for the ladies.
帮小姐们倒几杯酒
SAM: Yeah, we made a great pair.
我们真是好搭挡
I made book and Nicky made sure we always collected.
我下注而尼奇负责收钱
The old men loved us, and why not?
老头子们爱死我们了
They all made money with us.
他们全靠我们赚钱
How did Nicky collect?
尼奇怎么收钱？
Don't ask.
别问
Then where the fuck is the money? I don't see it.
钱他妈的在哪儿？ 我没见到
-Hi, Melissa, Heidi. -Hi, Sam.
-你们好，玛莉莎，海蒂 -你好，山姆
Who's this guy?
那是谁？
MAN: Get the fuck out. I laid nine. NICKY: It was eight.
-去你的，我下九 -是八
NICKY: Ace, tell him the line on the Bears game.
艾斯告诉他芝加哥小熊队的注
-Eight. -If he don't know, nobody knows.
-八 -他要不知道，就没人知道了
NICKY: It was eight. MAN: How come I laid nine?
-是八 -那我怎么算成九？
'Cause you're a jag-off.
因为你是个蠢才
-Excuse me. -What?
-对不起？ -什么？
-Isthis your pen? -Yeah, that's my pen. Why?
-这是你的笔吗？ -是我的，怎样？
It's nice. I didn't know whose it was.
很好看，我不知道是谁的
I didn't want it to get lost.
我不想它弄丢
Thank you. Why don't you take that fucking pen...
谢谢 你为什么不拿那只笔…
and shove it up your ass, you fucking jag-off?
捅到你屁眼里去，你这蠢才
-Well, I was just offering-- -Asshole.
-我只是… -王八蛋
MAN: Look out, Joe.
小心，乔
What's that? You hear a little girl?
那是什么？ 你有没有听到女孩哭？
Is that a little fucking girl?
是个小女孩吗？
What happened to the tough guy...
刚叫我朋友捅什么的…
who told my friend to stick it up his fucking ass?
那个硬汉呢？
Nicky, take it easy.
尼奇，够了
SAM: While I tried to figure out why the guy said what he said...
我还在想那人 为什么这么说时…
Nicky just hit him.
尼奇就动手了
No matter how big a guy might be, Nicky would take him on.
不管一个人多大个子 尼奇都会跟他拼命
You beat Nicky with fists, he comes back with a bat.
你拿拳头打他 他就会拿球棒回你
You beat him with a knife, he comes back with a gun.
你拿刀捅他 他就会用枪射你
If you beat him with a gun, you'd better kill him...
你若拿枪射他 那你最好是杀了他…
because he'll keep coming back and back...
因为他会一直不停的回来…
until one of you is dead.
直到你挂了为止
NICKY: With me protecting Ace...
由我保护艾斯…
he made a fortune for the bosses.
他为老大们狠狠赚了一票
That's what got him to Vegas.
这就是他来赌城的原因
He was a money machine.
他根本就是印钞机
A tremendous earner for these guys.
为这些家伙赚大钱
As soon as he took over, he doubled the fucking drop.
他一来就把供金增加了一倍
With Ace, the casino never saw so much money.
艾斯来后，赌场从就没见过 那么多的钱
And the bosses, they couldn't be happier.
老大们当然是笑不拢嘴
SAM: In Vegas, I had to keep a few juiced-in local cowboys working.
在赌城，我还得跟附近有关系的 一些牛仔找事做
They were close to the good old boys.
他们与老家伙们很熟
Without us, these guys would still be shoveling mule shit.
要不是我们 那些家伙现在都还在铲驴粪
You've got to keep a cleaner station.
场子得保持干净
If you need Mr. Clean, page him.
需要清洁工就呼叫他
Won't happen again, Sam.
下次不会了，山姆
SAM: Mr. Rothstein. MAN: It won't happen again, Mr. Rothstein.
-罗斯坦先生 -下次不会了，罗斯坦先生
Is this guy just another dumb fucking white man, or what?
这家伙又是一个蠢白人吗？
-You need this guy. -Can't get rid of him?
-你需要他 -弄不走是吗？
He's juiced in. He's the County Commissioner's cousin.
他有关系的 他是县辅导的表兄弟
SAM: I wouldn't give the bum a mop job.
我连清洁工都不会给他做
I had no choice. I had to take care of them.
别无选择，我必须照顾他们
These yokels ran the state.
这些乡巴佬当权
DEALER: Thanks, Senator.
多谢，议员
SAM: They passed the laws, owned the courts. I need a room.
-他们立法，又掌管法院 -我要开房间
SAM: I had dozens of politicians and state officials coming through weekly.
我每周都有十多个政客来访
SAM: Get him what he wants. BILLY: Certainly.
-他要什么都给他 -当然
SAM: Why not make them happy?
何不让他们快乐？
For politicians, like our State Senator up there...
对于政客 例如我们这位州议员…
everything was on the house.
一切都是免费的
These guys won their comped life when they got elected.
他们的招待生涯 在当选时就赢得了
Why not take advantage of it?
何不加以利用？
Still, the politicians came cheap. We could handle them.
政客还是小事，我们解决的了
It's a whale, like K.K. Ichikawa...
是像市川那种…
who plays $30, 000 a hand in baccarat.
百家乐一把下三万的豪赌客
That's the one you really gotta watch.
这种才该看紧
He plays fast and big. He has the cash and the credit...
他下注动作快，玩得大 他的资金雄厚…
to turn out your lights.
足可把你玩垮
A year ago he cleaned out a couple of casinos in the Cayman Islands.
一年前他让开曼群岛上 好几家赌场洗底
Downstairs he takes us for $2 million...
他从赌场赢了我们两百万…
and upstairs he takes free soap, shampoo and towels.
又从酒店套房拿了免费的 肥皂、洗发精与毛巾
Another billionaire cheapskate who loved his free rooms...
又是一个 喜爱免费套房…
free private jets and $2 million of our money.
免费私人飞机又赚得我们两百万 的亿万富翁小气鬼
But we got him back.
我们也不好惹
I had our pilot tell him the plane was on the fritz.
我让机师告诉他飞机故障
ICHlKAWA: What went wrong? BILLY: I'm awfully sorry.
-发生什么事？ -非常抱歉
These mechanical things happen.
是机械故障
Better here than up there.
在这儿总比在上面好
SAM: Then he missed the flights connecting with Japan.
然后他赶不上回日本的飞机
I can't believe there's no room.
竟然没有空房
SAM: We got him back with a whole floor of rooms to himself.
我们给了他一整楼的房间
-Sorry you missed your plane. -You'd like some of my money back.
-真抱歉让你赶不上飞机 -你想要赢回我的钱啊
Oh, no. No gambling.
不，不赌了
SAM: And once he was back, he played small.
他回来后开始下小注
He bet $1,000 a hand, instead of his usual $30,000 a hand.
一把只赌一千 而不是平常的三万一把
But I knew the trick with whales like Ichikawa...
但我知道这些豪赌客的习性…
was that they can't bet small for long.
他们不可能一直下小注的
He didn't think of it as winning $10, 000...
他不觉得是赢一万…
he thought of it as losing $90, 000.
他会想成是输九万…
So, he upped his bets.
所以他开始加码
Until he dropped his winnings back and gave up $1 million of his own cash.
直到他将赢得的输光 再加上自己一百万的现金
In a casino, the cardinal rule is to keep them playing...
在赌场里，第一原则就是 让他们一直赌…
and keep them coming back.
也让他们一直回来
The longer they play, the more they lose.
赌得越多就输得越多
In the end, we get it all.
最终钱就都是我们的
In Vegas, everybody's gotta watch everybody else.
在赌城，每个人都得注意着别人
Since the players are looking to beat the casino...
玩家是来赢赌场钱的…
the dealers are watching the players...
庄家得看好玩家…
the boxmen are watching the dealers...
收付赌注得看好庄家…
the floormen are watching the boxmen...
管场的注意着收付赌注的人…
the pit bosses are watching the floormen...
赌区经理看着管场的…
the shift bosses are watching the pit bosses...
值班经理看着赌区经理…
the casino manager is watching the shift bosses...
赌场经理看着值班经理…
I'm watching the casino manager...
我则看着赌场经理…
and the eye in the sky is watching us all.
而监视照相机看着我们大家
Plus, we had a dozen guys...
另外，还有十多个家伙…
most of them ex-cheats, who knew every trick in the house.
大多以前都是老千 他们知道所有的骗术
Yes!
好啊！
-Very nice. -I told you I was hot tonight.
-非常好 -我就跟你说我今天很旺
Looking good.
好样的
MAN: Let's go. This is for Ginger.
来吧，为了金吉儿，快
MAN: Let me have $100 on your hard 10.
一百赌你没老A
Thank you.
谢谢
MAN: Here we go now.
来吧
-Oh, I'm sorry. -The dice.
-对不起 -骰子
Thank you very much.
多谢
I appreciate that.
多谢你
Take care, Steve. Take chances, drive fast.
保重，史蒂夫 要冒险啊，开快车
This $100 is for you, love. Thanks for your time.
这一百给你，甜心 多谢你赏光
-Come on. -What's the matter?
-快点 -怎么了？
I made a lot of money for you, I want my cut.
我帮你赚了不少，我要我的份
What money? I've seen you stealing.
什么钱？我看到你偷钱
"What money?" Look at the stack of chips.
“什么钱？” 你看看这堆筹码
GINGER: I want my half. GAMBLER: I've watched you.
-我要我的一半 -我观察你一夜了
-I want my money. -Your bag is full of chips.
-我要我的钱 -你皮包里全是熟筹码
GINGER: I didn't steal anything from you. GAMBLER: Get lost!
-我才没偷你的东西 -滚吧！
GINGER: Get lost? GAMBLER: Yes!
-滚吧？ -没错！
-Well, how about that? -Come on!
-这怎么样呢？ -别这样！
SAM: What a move. I fell in love right there.
真酷，让我一见钟情
But in Vegas, for a girl like Ginger, love costs money.
但在赌城，像金吉儿这样的女孩 得花上大钱
I'm gonna go powder my nose.
我去补个妆
SAM: Ginger's mission in life was money. I'll be right back.
-金吉儿的人生目标是钱 -马上回来
DOORMAN: See you. GINGER: Thanks for asking.
-待会见，金吉儿 -多谢你
SAM: She was a queen around the casino.
她在赌场可是皇后
She brought in high rollers and helped them spend a lot of money.
她召来大赌客 并也帮他们花大钱
-Hello. -Hey, Ginger. How you doing?
-你好 -嘿，金吉儿，你好吗？
GINGER: Great. You might have something for me. Got me covered?
好得很，一点小意思 你帮我搞定了吗？
GINGER: Thank you. VALET: Take care of yourself.
-非常感谢 -自己保重喔
I got some lucky pills for you, Andy.
我有些幸运丸给你，安迪
SAM: Who didn't want her? She was one of the best known...
谁不想要金吉儿？ 她是城里名声最响亮…
best liked and most respected hustlers in town.
也是道上最受欢迎的江湖人物
Smart hustlers like her could keep a guy awake...
像她这么聪明的玩家 可以让男人…
for two or three days before sending him home broke...
两三天不睡 然后再让他一文不名的…
to the little woman and his bank examiners.
回到老婆与银行审查主任身边
Any change?
有找钱吗？
Oh, I hit a few games on the way back.
我回来时小赌了几把
SAM: But that was all bullshit. She just pocketed the cash.
那根本是胡扯 她把钱收起来了
GINGER: How you doing tonight? CASHlER: Good.
-你今天好吗？ -不错啊
CASHlER: How are you? GINGER: Beat.
-你呢？ -衰死了
SAM: Ginger had the hustlers' code. GINGER: Take one for you.
-金吉儿洞悉玩家们的习性 -给你一百
CASHlER: Thank you. SAM: She knew how to take care of people.
-多谢 -她懂得如何买通他人
That's what Vegas is all about.
这就是赌城的座右铭
CASHlER: $6,800. GINGER: Thanks.
-六千八百元 -谢啦
SAM: It's kickback city. GINGER: Have a good night.
-这里是讲究回扣的城市 -晚安
SAM: She took care of the dealers...
她罩庄家…
pit bosses, floor managers...
赌区经理，管场经理…
but, mostly, the valet parkers...
但尤其关照停车小弟…
the guys who could get you anything and take care of anything.
他们能帮你找到任何东西 也能帮你解决任何事
Ginger took care of the parkers...
金吉儿搞定了停车的…
who took care of the security guards, who took care of the cops...
他们搞定警卫 而警卫会摆平警察…
who let her operate. I need that stuff tonight.
-让她可继续开工 -我今晚需要那东西
VALET: No problem. GINGER: You are a doll.
-没问题 -你真好
SAM: The valet parking job was such a money-maker...
停车赚的钱多到…
they had to pay off the hotel manager just to get the concession.
得买通酒店经理才能排上空缺
But one thing I didn't understand...
不过有一点我不懂…
was that she had everything under control...
她将一切都控制的好好的…
except for her old pimp boyfriend, Lester Diamond.
却被她那拉皮条的男友 莱丝特戴蒙德吃得死死的
I got other people in this. I got partners.
我得顾到其他人，我的搭挡们
I'm looking out for you in this thing, okay?
在这事上有我罩你，知道吗？
You'll get yours back, and you'll get it back first. Okay?
你将获你应得的 而且第一个拿到，好吗？
-All right. -Where you going?
-好的 -你去哪儿了？
Where are you? You're in that place.
你在哪儿？ 你又飘走了
-I'm here. -No, you're not.
-我在这儿 -不，你不在
Where are you?
你在哪？
I'm always here for you.
我永远在你身边
-You are. -I am.
-真的 -是啊
SAM: The Ginger I knew wouldn't even look at this creep.
我所认识的金吉儿 根本不会多看这怪胎一眼
-Good luck. -Yeah.
-祝你好运 -是啊
SAM: He was a moocher, a card cheat...
他是个老千，专作假牌…
a country club golf hustler, a scumbag...
老在高尔夫俱乐部招摇撞骗 一个瘪三…
-chasing dentists for a few bucks. -Careful.
-为了几块钱追着牙医屁股跑 -小心点
SAM: He was always broke. He always had a story.
他永远都没钱，永远都有藉口
Somehow, she could never turn him down.
不知为何，她却拒绝不了他
The way Ginger saw it was that he was just an unlucky guy.
在金吉儿眼里，他只是运气不好
Somebody had to take care of him.
总得有人照顾他
BACK HOME
在老家
But nobody had to take care of Nicky.
但尼奇可不需要人照顾
You find any cash in there, we'll whack it up with you.
你找到现金的话 我们就跟你平分
SAM: He took care of himself only too well.
他把自己照顾得太好了
That's why every badge back home wanted to nail him.
这也是为什么老家的条子 都想抓他到案
I folded these things beautifully. I would appreciate a little respect.
我将这些都折得好好的 能不能放尊重点
Don't look at me, pal, I gotta live with her.
别看我，兄弟 我还得跟她同床共枕
SAM: Even after a vacation, they hassled him at the airport.
就连去渡个假 他们在机场时都不放过他
Frank Marino was there to meet him. So were the cops.
法兰克玛雷诺在那儿等他 条子们也在
They wanted to pinch him...
他们想逮他…
-for a diamond burglary in Antwerp. -Help me fold these.
-因为一宗在安特卫普的钻石窃案 -帮忙折吧
SAM: They were ready to blame him for anything, no matter where.
他们随时愿意嫁祸于他 不管是在哪儿发生什么事
They were usually right.
他们通常是对的
Because Nicky enjoyed being a gangster.
因为尼奇很喜欢混帮派
And he didn't give a damn who knew it.
他也不在乎有谁知道
GINGER: There we go. Look at that. Beautiful!
看看，美极了
SAM: I mean that's what worried me...
让我担心的是…
'cause it turns out, Nicky was about to be sent to Vegas.
尼奇似乎要被派来拉斯维加斯
JENNlFER: All right, we're clear. NICKY: There's more.
-好了，就这样 -还有
NICKY: There's a couple stuck in there.
一定还有些卡在里面
-I'm telling you, they're out! -Come on.
-我告诉你都拿出来了 -快
Don't get so defensive, it could be stuck in your hair.
别急于辩护 可能还有些卡在你头发里
What's that?
那是什么？
There's no more. Thanks.
没有了，谢谢
NICKY: I couldn't wait to get my hands on Vegas.
我迫不及待想去拉斯维加斯
But the bosses didn't send me out to have a good time.
但老大可不是送我去玩的
They sent me out to make sure that nobody fucked with Ace.
他们要我去确保 没人找艾斯的麻烦
And nobody interfered with the fucking skim.
也确保没人干扰每月的抽头
-Hey. -Hey, how you doing?
-嘿 -你好吗？
Hey, Sammy.
嘿，山姆
-Boy, look at this place. -Incredible.
-天呀，瞧瞧这地方 -不可思议
SAM: Welcome to Vegas.
欢迎来赌城
NICKY: Okay, Sammy. SAM: Something, huh?
-好样的，山姆 -不错吧
Ginger.
金吉儿
Holy shit. What've you been doing out here?
靠，你都在这儿干嘛？
SAM: Honey, come here.
甜心，过来
This is Jennifer and Nick. They're dear friends of mine.
这是珍妮佛与尼克 我的好朋友们
-Hi, Jennifer. -A pleasure.
-你好，珍妮佛 -幸会
Okay, Sammy.
好样的，山姆
SAM: After we ate, we left Jennifer and Ginger...
晚餐后，我们让珍妮佛 与金吉儿一块儿…
and we took a ride to talk.
我们俩则出去谈话
And then, he hit me with it.
然后他对我丢了颗炸弹
What do you think about me moving out here?
你觉得我也搬来如何？
You got a problem with that?
有问题吗？
No, of course not.
当然没有
You mean I have your permission?
你是说你允许罗？
Sure, you do. But I just gotta tell you...
当然罗 但我得告诉你…
it's no joke out here.
在这儿可不能开玩笑
You gotta keep a low profile.
你得保持低调
It's not like back home. They don't like guys like us.
不像是在老家 这儿他们不喜欢我们
This sheriff's a real cowboy.
警长是个不折不扣的牛仔
Even coppers aren't afraid to bury people in the desert.
连巡警都不怕在沙漠里埋人
I don't care. I want to get away from back home for a while.
我不在乎 我只想离开老家一阵子
I'm tired of that shit back there.
我厌倦了那里
Look at this place. It's made of money.
看看这地方，简直是钱砌的
You know what the best part is?
知道最诺氖鞘裁矗
Nobody's gonna know what we're doing.
没人知道我们在干嘛
There's nobody here to see us. Everybody's back home.
没人看着我们，大家都在老家
I got pinched twice for no reason.
我无缘故被逮了两次
I really gotta be careful.
我真得小心了
I'm running a licensed place. Everything's legit.
我管理的地方是有执照的 全是合法的
Don't worry about it. I'm not gonna do anything.
别担心，我什么都不会做的
I'm especially not gonna involve you in anything.
我尤其不会拖你下水
NICKY: Ace saw Vegas one way...
艾斯看赌城的观点…
NICKY: Call and tell him I'm coming? JACK: Of course.
-你跟他说过我要来吗？ -当然
...but I saw it another.
我的看法不同
I saw it as untouched.
我视它为未开发的
They had bookies, pimps, and drug dealers I could shake down.
多的是可勒索的赌马组头 皮条客与毒贩…
Who the fuck were they gonna run to?
他们能找谁靠？
So I started getting everybody in line.
我开始一个一个下手
Best of all, for the first time in my life...
最诺氖牵我这辈子第一次…
I figured out a way not to lose.
发觉了稳赢的方法
SAM: He had a foolproof scheme.
他是有个稳赢之计
It wasn't very scientific, but it worked.
虽然不高明，但起码行得通
When he won, he collected.
他赢时就收钱
When he lost, he told the bookies to fuck off.
输时就叫赌马组头去死
What were they gonna do? Muscle Nicky? Nicky was the muscle.
他们能怎样？逼迫尼奇？ 尼奇就是逼迫者
-Hey, how you doing? -How you doing?
-你好吗？
-You got that thing for me? -What thing?
-你有东西给我吗？ -什么东西？
Nicky, I thought you was laying.
尼奇，我以为你是来下注的
I was laying? No, I'm taking it.
下注？不，我来收钱
-You sure? -I'm positive.
-你确定？ -非常
-I'm a little confused. -You're a little confused?
-我搞混了 -你搞混了？
Maybe if I stick your fucking face through this window...
或许在我把你的脸砸过这窗户后…
you'll get unconfused.
你就会清楚点
-Give me the fucking money. -I'm sorry.
-把钱他妈的给我 -对不起
I didn't mean anything by it.
我不是故意的
That's why you had it ready. You thought I was laying it.
所以你连钱都准备好了 你他妈的以为我要下注
-My fucking head. -Smarten up.
-我的头 -放聪明点
And now Nicholas Santoro will come up and tell us about our first President.
而现在尼可拉斯山多罗 要来跟我们说第一总统的故事了
George Washington was born--
乔治华盛顿出生在…
SAM: But still, it was nice and quiet for a while.
但最起码还风平浪静了一阵子
We presented Nicky and Jennifer all over town...
我们带着尼奇与珍妮佛满街亮相…
like regular Ozzie and Harriets.
像是明星似的
COACH: You got a beautiful swing.
你棒挥得很好
NICKY: Ace got Little Nicky involved with Little League. It was great.
艾斯让我儿子，小尼奇 参加市区青少棒，真的很好
Turned out that one of the other coaches was a metro intelligence cop.
结果其中的一位教练 是市立警察局情报单位的
But it didn't matter. It was all about the kids.
不过无所谓，这纯粹是孩子的事
He's gotta realize everything can't be a home run.
他得明白不是每棒都能挥出全垒打
That's exactly what I tell him, but that's the kind of kid he is.
我也是这样告诉他 不过那小子就是这样
SAM: And Nicky being Nicky, he made his presence known.
尼奇就是尼奇 他总是引人注目
Especially at the casino where he definitely did not work...
尤其是在他不工作的赌场
people got the message.
大家都明白
NICKY: Me, that's why the bosses sent me out here.
就是我，这也是老大为何派我来
I was to make sure no other crews robbed the joint.
我是来确定 没有其他人在拿这儿的钱
Like these two fucking balloon heads over here.
像在那边的那两个蠢才
They were gonna try to bang us out of $200, 000.
想从我们这儿骗走二十万
Yeah, right, I'm sure.
走着瞧
How are you? What are you doing here?
你好吗？你怎么会在这儿？
I'm over here now.
我到这儿来了
-You're over here? -Yeah, I'm over here with them.
-到这儿来？ -是啊，跟他们一起
We're waiting on Carmine.
我们在等卡尔曼
Yeah, we're looking for Carmine.
是啊，在等卡尔曼
He was here before. He had a suitcase, and then he left.
他本来在这儿 拿了口箱子后来就走了
Carmine left?
卡尔曼走了？
He's gone?
他走了吗？
He's not here?
他不在这儿？
Carmine's out?
他出去了？
I think he went across the street or somewhere else or something.
他好像过了马路还是什么的
Well, listen, good luck with the joint.
是喔，听着，祝你在这儿好运
-Thanks, Eddy. -Lots of luck.
-谢啦，艾迪 -非常好运
Good luck to you, too.
也祝你好运
CASHlER: They forgot to sign their papers.
他们忘了签名
They don't need those anymore.
他们不需要这个了
SAM: Out of respect, guys from other crews got away with a warning.
因为基本尊重 我只给别帮家伙一点警告
Everybody else, watch out.
其他的人可得小心了
Like these yokels here...
像这群乡巴佬…
who never heard of Nicky or the bosses back home.
从没听过尼奇或他老家的老大们
They're the morons who give you the most trouble.
这种王八蛋最麻烦了
We'd catch them and they'd try to sneak back...
被我们抓到后又会溜回来…
with beards and wigs and fake noses.
戴着假胡子、假发、假鼻子
You can spot these assholes by watching the way they bet.
只要看这些王八蛋下注的方式 你就可辨认他们
Like this guy. He's betting lavender chips...
像这家伙，以紫筹码下注…
at $500 each with only one little problem.
每次下五百，不过只有个小问题
He's always guessed right.
他每次都猜对
If he wasn't so fucking greedy, he'd have been tougher to spot.
要不是他这么贪心 可能还不会这么明显
But in the end, they're all greedy.
不过到头来，他们每个都贪
I saw that the dealer was weak, but he wasn't in on it.
我看到庄家很弱 但他们并不是一伙的
He just wasn't protecting his hand.
他只是没保护好自己的牌
He was lifting his hole card way too high.
他把底牌掀得太高了
Here's this guy reading the dealer's hole card...
有个家伙在看庄家的底牌…
and signaling his buddy at this table.
再对他坐在桌上的兄弟打手势
And that's just what these hustlers look for.
这些在外混的就是这样
They cruise from casino to casino looking for weak dealers...
他们从一家赌场到另一家 找寻着弱庄家…
the way lions look for weak antelope.
像是狮子们找着弱小的羚羊
Operator, this is Mr. R.
接线生，这是罗先生
Get me Armstrong and Friday over to Pit 2 right away.
立刻叫阿姆斯壮 与佛莱迪来二号赌台区
BJ 19, second base, the beard.
二十一点第十九桌 第二个位子的那个大胡子
Operator, I need Mr. Happy. Loud.
接线生，来段生日快乐曲 要大声点
WAlTRESSES: [Singing] Happy birthday to you
祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday, dear Jeff
亲爱的杰夫
GUARD: Man down!
有人倒下！
Go get medical. We got a cardiac arrest here.
叫救护车，有人心脏病发
He's fine, folks. Just give us some room, please.
他没事了，大家 麻烦给我们一点空间
SAM: They never know what hit them.
他们根本搞不清状况
If and when they do find out they got zapped by a cattle prod...
若他们真的发现是被电击棒电到…
they wish they really did have a heart attack.
他们会希望自己其实是心脏病发
Turns out this guy and his fucking pals were knocking this place dead for years.
结果发现这两个家伙已在这儿 招摇撞骗好多年了
GUARD 1 : He's wired. HUSTLER: What are you doing?
-他身上有窃听器 -你在干嘛？
GUARD 1 : There it is. That's it.
在那儿，就是它了
GUARD 2: Cheater's justice. HUSTLER: Oh, God!
-老千的正法 -我的天！
No!
不！
SAM: I wanted everybody to know that things were changed around here.
我要所有人知道这儿跟以往不同了
We had to make an example of these pricks that the party was over.
我们得用这些家伙来让大家知道 他们的好日子不长了
I'm just curious.
我很好奇
I saw you shuffling your checks with your right hand.
我看到你用右手玩筹码
-Can you do that with both hands? -No.
-你两只手都可以这样吗？ -不
SAM: You can't do it with both hands? HUSTLER: No, sir.
-不能用两只手吗？ -不能
-Can you do it with your left hand? -I never tried.
-左手可以吗？ -我从没试过
-So, you're a righty. -Yeah.
-所以你是右撇子 -是
Now you're gonna have to learn with your left hand.
那你现在得学习用左手罗
-It's $100,000, $1 10,000 I think. -Yes, it is.
-十万，不，十一万吧 -是啊
Okay.
好的
Hi.
嗨
That's a lot of money to be counting out in public.
在大庭广众数这么多钱
Why don't I take him over to the office and verify it?
为何不让我拿到办公室确认？
A little privacy.
多一点隐私
By the way, send over a nice bottle of champagne on ice.
顺便叫一瓶好香槟来
CASHlER: Sure will. BILLY: Real special.
-没问题 -要很特别的
By the way, I'm Billy Sherbert, casino manager.
对了，我是赌场经理 比利雪伯堤
BILLY: Having a good time? HUSTLER 2: Yes.
-还玩得愉快吗？ -是的
You want to count the money in privacy.
你在较有隐私的地方算比较好
HUSTLER 2: I have a plane to catch. Can I get my winnings?
我得赶飞机去克里夫兰 我可以领取我赢得的钱吗？
Look what they did to my hand, man.
看他们对我的手做了什么
SAM: I'm gonna give you a choice:
我给你一个选择
You can have the money and the hammer, or you can walk out of here.
你可以拿钱然后被锤头砸 或者是从这儿走出去
-What do you want? -I wanna get out of here.
-你要哪个？ -我要走
Tell your friends what happens if they fuck around here.
告诉你那群朋友，他们若来乱搞 会发生什么事
-I'm sorry, I made a bad mistake. -You're fucking right.
-对不起，我犯了大错 -你真他妈的说对了
SAM: If you come back, either one of you, we'll break your fucking heads.
你们要是再敢回来 我会敲烂你们的头
You see that fucking saw? We're gonna use it. We don't fuck around here.
你看到那锯子没？不是放着好看的 我们不是在开玩笑
SAM: Got it? HUSTLER 2: Yes.
-懂吗？ -是
-Get out of here. -Thank you.
-给我滚 -谢谢你
Throw him out in the alley. Tell the cops he got hit by a car.
把他丢到后街去 跟条子说他被车撞到了
SAM: Within no time, everything was set in place.
不到一会儿，一切就都搞定了
We got rid of the freelance scamsters, the pro was way up...
我们弄走了那些老千 盈利上扬好多…
the gods were happy, or as happy as the gods can ever be.
上头老大高兴极了
And I decided to complicate my life.
然后我决定将生活复杂化
For a guy who likes sure things...
对不爱冒险的我来说…
I was about to bet the rest of my life on a real long shot.
我用我的下半辈子 下了笔胜算不大的赌注
We're not getting any younger.
我们也不年轻了
Don't you think it's time?
你不觉得是时候了？
Aren't you getting tired of all this shit? Banging around, hustling around?
你对这些不厌烦吗？ 这边睡、那边混？
-Are you trying to handicap me? -I'm gonna do you one better.
-你想要妨碍我吗？ -我想给你更好的
I'm trying to marry you.
我想娶你进门
SAM: You wanna marry me?
你想嫁我吗？
SAM: I'm serious.
我说真的
I wanna settle down. I want a family.
我想定下来，想有个家
You got the wrong girl, Sam.
你找错人了，山姆
I'd be a good father, you'd be a good mother.
我会是个好爸爸 你也将是个好妈妈
You don't know me.
你不知道我
You've known me two, three months. What do you know?
你才认识我两、三个月 你了解什么？
I'm 43 years old. I don't want to wait.
我已经43岁了，我不想再等了
I know you well enough to know that I really love you very much.
我对你的了解深到 令我自己知道我非常爱你
I can't think of anybody better to be with.
你是我心目中最理想的人
I don't feel like waiting anymore.
我不想再等了
You know a lot of happily married people? 'Cause I don't.
你见过很多婚姻美满的人吗？ 我可没见过
I know all that.
这我都懂
I care about you.
我在乎你
But I just don't have those kind of feelings for you.
但我对你没有那种感觉
I'm sorry. I'm not in love with you.
对不起，我并不爱你
SAM: All right. GINGER: Understand?
-好的 -懂吗？
GINGER: I'm sorry.
对不起
No....
不…
That can grow.
那可以培养
As long as there's a mutual respect, that kind of thing can grow.
只要互相尊重 感情是可以培养的
I'm realistic. I can accept that.
我很现实，我可以接受
SAM: What is love anyway?
爱到底是什么？
SAM: It's a mutual respect. It's a devotion.
不就是互相尊重 不就是一心一意
It's a caring from one person to another.
是一个人在乎另一个人
And if we could set up some kind of foundation...
若我们可以设立一个基础…
based on that mutual respect...
以相互尊重为底…
I feel that eventually you would care enough about me...
我觉得迟早你会对我有情…
that I could live with that.
这样我能接受
If it doesn't work out...
若行不通的话…
if it doesn't play out, then what happens to me?
若行不通的话 那我怎么办？
I'm doing well now. I'm gonna do even better.
我现在做得不错 往后会越来越好
So whatever happens...
不论如何…
if it doesn't work out between us...
就算我们俩行不通…
I'll make sure you're okay for the rest of your life.
我都会确保你下半辈子的生活
If there are kids, especially...
尤其如果有了孩子…
I'll take care of you better than you'd imagine.
我会给你今生最好的照料
GINGER: What are you pitching me? SAM: Just what I said.
-你葫芦到底卖什么药？ -我都明讲了
You'll be set up for the rest of your life.
你下半辈子都不用愁
That I can promise you.
这我可保证
Want to take a chance?
要不要试试？
SAM: When I married Ginger, I knew all the stories...
我娶金吉儿时就听过她的一切往事…
but I didn't give a fuck. I'm Sam Rothstein, I said.
但我不在乎 我是山姆罗斯坦
I can change her.
我能改变她
NICKY: It was typical Ace.
这是典型的艾斯
He invited the biggest people in town. He knew they'd show.
他请了城里所有的大人物 他知道他们都会出席
He knew they all wanted something from him.
他知道他们都有求于他
With Ace, nobody ever got a free ride. Even Ginger.
艾斯绝对不可能不求回报 连金吉儿也不例外
With her, he still covered his bets.
一切还是依他行事
They had to have the baby first, before they could get married.
他们在结婚前得先有孩子
He even made us watch Amy for a few days...
他甚至还托我们帮忙看艾美几天…
when they went on their honeymoon.
好让他们去渡蜜月
I didn't mind, we loved the kid.
无所谓啊 我们爱死那孩子
LESTER: Can you feel my eyes on you?
你感到我的眼神？
Can you feel me look into your heart?
你感到我看透你的心吗？
Can you feel me in the pit of your stomach?
你能感到我躺在你肚皮上吗？
Can you feel me in you?
你能在体内感受我？
In your heart?
在心里？
Don't make me come there.
别等我过去
Answer me.
回答我
GINGER: [Crying] I love you.
我爱你
Baby, do you know that I love you, too?
宝贝，你知道我也爱你吗？
GINGER: No, Lester. LESTER: Do you know that?
-不，莱斯特 -你知道吗？
GINGER: Yes.
知道
This is the best thing I can do for my life right now.
这是我目前能为自己做的 最好的事
That's right.
没错
So it's going to be okay.
所以会没事的
Promise?
你发誓？
I wish you all the luck in the world.
我希望你幸福
GINGER: You do? LESTER: Yeah, I do.
-真的？ -是，我真的这么想
It's the best thing you can do right now.
这是你目前能做的最好的事
I mean this.
我说真的
You have real security.
你生活会很安稳
Sweetheart, you're gonna be situated just right in Vegas.
甜心，你将坐在赌城最有利的位子
Come on. This is great for us.
这对我们来说再好不过了
I'm always gonna be here for you. I ain't going no place.
我会一直都在你身边的 我哪儿都不会去
I'm looking at you right now.
我现在就在看着你
I'm seeing you for the very first time, right this minute.
仿佛生平第一次见到你似的
I'm saying I can feel my heart click.
我可听到我的心悸动
I see you 14 years old.
我看到你十四岁时
I see you the first second I ever saw you.
我在见你的第一秒就看到你了
I see you, long-legged little colt...
我看到你，像匹长腿的小马儿…
stupid braces on your teeth.
还戴着蠢蠢的牙套
Okay, then. LESTER: Every time I see you, that's what I see.
-好吧 -我每次见你时都看到这些
Talk to you later. Bye.
再聊罗，再见
-You all right? -Yeah.
-你还好吗？ -嗯
Why are you crying?
为什么哭？
I'm not crying.
我没有哭
-Maybe you shouldn't drink so much. -I'm okay.
-别喝这么多了吧 -我没事
You just have to understand.
希望你能理解
I've been with Lester since I was a kid.
我自小就跟莱斯特在一起
I just wanted to say goodbye.
我只是想道别
I just....
我只是…
I think I have a right to do that.
我想我有权这样做
GINGER: Okay?
好吗？
It's all right.
没关系
That part of your life is over with.
你那段人生已经完结了
SAM: Right? GINGER: Yeah.
-不是吗？ -是的
You're with me now.
你现在跟我
-Yeah. -Right?
-不是吗？
SAM: You're sure? GINGER: Yeah.
-你确定吗？ -是的
SAM: Want to go? Let's go back in. GINGER: Okay.
-要走了吗？我们回去吧 -好的
GINGER: It's great.
很好
GINGER: It's all my stuff. Oh, my God.
都是我的东西，天呀
You brought all my stuff!
你把我的东西都带来了！
I can't....
我不能…
Try it on. It's yours.
试试看，这是你的
You're kidding.
别开玩笑了
My God.
我的天
-What is it? -It's chinchilla.
-是什么毛？ -是龙猫
It's so soft.
好软喔
Nice, isn't it?
很好喔？
No one's ever been so nice to me.
从没有人对我这么好
GINGER: Oh, my God!
我的老天！
Do you think it's too much if I wear these all on the same day?
我要是在同一天将它们全都戴上 会不会太过火啊？
You can do whatever you want.
你想怎样就怎样
Do I keep my promises or do I keep my promises?
我有没有实现我的诺言啊？
You're so wonderful. The jewelry's not so bad either.
你太好了 这些珠宝也不错
We shouldn't keep this in the house. We gotta put it in the bank.
我们不应该把这些放在家里 应该摆到银行去
Come on. Can I keep this one in the house?
我不能留一副在家吗？
Pay attention to me.
仔细听好
What I'm gonna tell you is very important.
我要告诉你一件重要的事
All this stuff doesn't mean anything.
这全部都不算什么
Money, this, doesn't mean anything without trust.
钱财珠宝 如果没有信任就毫无意义
I have to be able to trust you with my life.
我得要信任你到可将生命交给你
SAM: With over $1 million in cash and jewels tucked in a bank in Vegas...
总价值超过一百万的现金与珠宝 锁在赌城的银行里…
only for Ginger, she was secure and happy.
全归她所有 金吉儿非常有安全感
She loved that shit.
她最爱那些
But a guy in my line of work has to have a lot of payoff cash around.
但在我这行里 手上得有许多流动的现金
Crooked cops and kidnappers, they don't take checks.
贪污的条子与绑匪 他们都不收支票
Need any help with that, Mr. Collins?
考林先生，需要帮忙吗？
SAM: So I put $2 million cash in a Los Angeles bank...
所以我在洛杉矶的银行里 也摆了两百万…
under the name of Mr. and Mrs. Tom Collins.
用考林先生与夫人的名义
This was strictly my shakedown and kidnapping money.
这纯粹是我个人的赎金与保金
Since I'd be in jail or locked in a closet when I needed the money most...
因为在我最需要这笔钱时 我不是蹲在牢里就是被关在衣柜…
I gave Ginger the only key to the cash that could get me back alive.
所以我将这笔钱唯一的钥匙 给了金吉儿好让我能保命
This is just a signature card.
这是签名卡
Once she signs, she'll be the only person...
她签了之后就会是世上…
to have total access to the box, no one else, including myself?
唯一可以开保险箱的人 连我都开启不了？
BANKER: That's right. That's the way you wanted it.
是的，这是你的要求
Sam, let me ask you a question.
山姆，我问你个问题
You must really trust your wife.
你一定很信任你老婆
Sure I do. Why?
是啊，怎么啦？
It's good. It's just unusual.
很好啊，只是很少见
To tell you the truth, so many of my clients don't.
实不相瞒 我有很多客户都不信任
SAM: With Ginger and the money in place, I felt covered.
将金吉儿还有钱的事解决后 我安心多了
To play it safe, I switched job titles again...
为了安全起见，我又将头衔…
and made myself Food and Beverage Director.
换成餐饮董事
This way nobody would bother me about a license.
这样一来就没人可以 为执照的事找我麻烦
Vegas was like a dream for me.
赌城对我来说像是个梦
Trouble was Nicky was dreaming of his own kind of Vegas.
问题是尼奇也梦想着 他自己的赌城
NICKY: I put money out on the street charging three points a week.
我将钱放出，每天三分利
Juice to the dealers.
庄家高利贷
-Don't make us look for you. -You won't have to look for me.
-别逼我们找上门 -你不会需要这样的
I appreciate it. Thanks, Nicky.
多谢了，尼奇
NICKY: They were degenerate gamblers, coke freaks.
他们不是烂赌鬼就是烂毒鬼
In no time, I had half the dealers in the Tangiers in my pocket.
没多久，坦吉乐一半的庄家 都在我手掌心里
Then, the next thing I did, I started busting out high-stakes poker players.
下一步，我开始出千骗大赌客的钱
SAM: It was so obvious.
好明显
All of Nicky's half-assed mechanics, they were signal-happy.
尼奇所有的小把戏 全都是靠手势
I'm gonna open for $500.
我下五百
SAM: Signaling back and forth.
互相打手势
Nicky thought nobody was watching him. But he was wrong.
尼奇以为没人注意到他 但是他错了
I didn't want any of those agents near my place.
我不想要那些探员在我的地盘
-Four aces. -I can't believe this.
-四条A -我不相信
GAMBLER 2: If I didn't have bad luck, I wouldn't have any luck.
我唯一的运气好像就是手气背
SAM: I wished Nicky and his whole crew would just get lost.
我真希望尼奇与他那票人 可以马上消失
What am I gonna do? Go back home and start a war?
但我能怎样？ 回老家去挑起场战争？
Nicky's a made guy and I'm not. I can't do that.
尼奇在帮里算是有头有脸的人物 我不能那么做
Gaming agents are all over the place.
到处都是赌博游乐公会的探员
I'm not allowed to get lucky in this place?
这儿不允许手气旺的人吗？
You've been lucky all week. They're looking to nail you.
你已经旺了一个礼拜了 他们在找机会逮你
NICKY: Ace was so worried about his casino...
艾斯太在意他的赌场…
he forgot what we were doing out here in the first place.
他忘了我们当初为什么而来
A million times, I wanted to yell in his fucking ear:
最少有一百万次 我都好想在他耳边大喊…
"This is Las Vegas.
这儿是拉斯维加斯
"We're supposed to be out here robbing, you dumb fucking hebe. "
“我们本来就是来抢钱的 你这个蠢犹太人”
I don't give a shit who he's connected to.
我才不在乎他有什么关系
Tell him to take his feet off the table.
叫他把脚从桌上拿下来
Does he think this is a goddamn sawdust joint?
他以为这儿是什么廉价的地方？
Sir, would you mind taking your feet off the table...
先生，麻烦你将脚放下…
and put your shoes on, please?
并将鞋穿上，好吗？
Yeah, I would mind. I'm having a bad night.
是，是很麻烦 我今天已经够背了
Fucking asshole won't budge.
那王八蛋动都不动
Call security.
叫警卫
How are you?
你好吗？
Good. How are you?
好，你呢？
Do me a favor. Want to take your feet off the table and put your shoes on?
给个面子，把你的脚放下去 然后把鞋穿上好吗？
Fuck you.
去你的
I want you to exit this guy off the premises, off his feet...
我要你把这家伙从赌场架着丢出去…
and use his head to open the fucking door.
用他的头来开门
Sir, you're gonna have to leave. You mind coming with us outside?
先生，你得离开 麻烦你跟我们出去
Bullshit. I ain't going anywhere with you.
妈的，我哪儿都不跟你去
GUARD: Bullshit. You're out of here. MAN: Fuck you!
-妈的，你给我滚 -去你的！
MAN: You know who you're fucking with? Do you?
你知道你在招惹谁吗？ 你知道吗？
You fucking faggot! Do you know who you're fucking with?
你他妈的王八蛋！ 你知道你招惹了谁吗？
MAN: Leave me alone!
别碰我！
GUARD: Come on! MAN: You gotta be kidding me!
-喂！ -别闹了！
SAM: Sure enough, an hour later, I get the call.
不出所料，我一小时后就接到电话
Ace, what happened over there? Did you know that guy was with me?
艾斯，那边怎么了？ 你知道那家伙是跟我的吗？
I didn't know that. You know what he did?
我不知道，你知道他做了什么吗？
I walked over to him politely, and he tells me to fuck myself.
我很有礼貌的走过去 他却叫我回家吃自已
SAM: Then he called me a faggot. NICKY: What?
-还骂我是臭玻璃 -什么？
SAM: I threw that cocksucker out. NICKY: Come here.
-我把那王八蛋踢出去了 -过来
You called my friend a faggot? Told him to go fuck himself?
你骂我的朋友臭玻璃 还叫他回家吃自己？
Is that what you did? Tell him to go fuck himself?
你这样说？ 叫他回家吃自己？
NICKY: [On phone] You fucking hick, you!
你这个死乡巴佬！
NICKY: You go over there. You apologize.
你给我过去道歉
NICKY: You better hope he lets you back in.
你最好求他让你进去
If you get out of line again, I'll smash your head so hard...
你要再敢没大没小 我会将你的头打到…
you won't be able to get that cowboy hat on. Fucking hick.
你连那牛仔帽都戴不上 死乡巴佬
Listen, this guy obviously doesn't know who he was talking to.
听着，这家伙压根就不知道 自己在跟谁说话
He doesn't know that we're dear friends.
他不知道我们是好兄弟
He's already very sorry.
他非常抱歉
But if you could do me a favor and let him back in...
但如果你可买我个面子 让他再进去…
I swear he'll never get out of line again.
我发誓他再也不会乱来
If he does it again, he's out for good.
若他再敢乱来，就别想再踏进这儿
I'll never let him in the place again.
我永远都不会再让他进门
NICKY: I'm sorry about this.
真是对不起
All right, Ace? Thanks, pal.
好吗，艾斯？ 谢了，兄弟
You took your boots off? You put your feet on the table?
你把鞋都脱了？ 把脚放在桌上？
You shit-kicking, stinky, horse-manure-smelling motherfucker, you!
你这全身马粪骚的浑蛋！
You fuck me up over there, I'll stick you in a hole in the desert.
你要敢再去丢我的脸 我会在沙漠里将你埋了
NICKY: Go over and apologize. MAN: Nicky, I'm sorry.
-快给我去道歉 -尼奇，对不起
NICKY: Ace could be a very touchy guy.
艾斯可是个很敏感的人
Especially when he got bigger in town.
尤其是当他在城里越来越出名后
Like when he hired Jonathan and David away from the Palace...
像他将强纳森与大卫 从凯撒宫挖角来时…
by building them a new stage and giving them a silver Rolls-Royce.
他为他们盖了全新的舞台 还给了他们一人一辆劳斯莱斯
But, I tell you, he knew how to bring in the crowds.
但我得说 他真的知道怎么吸引群众
He knew all the fucking angles.
他懂得一切门路
He brought the whole Femme Fatale show from Paris...
他将整个蛇蝎美人的秀 从巴黎搬来…
but he forgot how lazy them European dancing broads can get.
但他却忘记那些欧洲跳舞妹有多懒
He had to weigh them once a week so they wouldn't blow up like balloons.
他还得每周为她们秤体重 她们的身材才不至于像吹气球
You're still eight pounds over.
你还是4公斤过重
-What's the reason for this? -Mr. Rothstein, sir--
-为什么会这样？ -罗斯坦您…
Never mind the "sir." Why is she eight pounds over?
别在那儿您了 她为什么会超重4公斤？
I'm trying to use respect.
我只是尊重您
Mr. Rothstein is good enough for you.
罗斯坦先生就可以了
Well, sometimes when you put that pressure point on them--
嗯，有时当你给她们 太多的压力…
All you do is give me answers. Just give me the right answer.
你只需要给我答案 给我正确答案就好
I don't know why. She's frightened if she doesn't lose weight she'll get fired.
我不知道，她害怕要是不减肥 她就会被解雇
That's right, she will get fired. Send her back to Paris--
没错，她会被解雇 送她回巴黎…
-It's been our policy-- -Stop everything.
-我们一贯的做法是… -停
AGENT: She's an institution. SAM: That's the problem. She's lazy.
-她很出名 -这就是问题，她太懒散
NICKY: I gotta give the guy credit.
我得佩服这家伙
I mean, he does the most obvious thing.
我的意思是 他做了最明显的事
This is the only town in the country where a bookie joint is legit.
这里是全国唯一可以合法签注的地方
So why not take advantage, right?
为什么不加以利用呢？
So he took bookie joints off the street...
所以他把签注从街上…
and opened them up inside the casino.
开到赌场内
Within a few years, he had...
没几年后…
every casino on The Strip trying to copy off of him.
精华地段的每家赌场都想抄袭他
SAM: Between my innovations...
我的创意…
and Nicky's dedication to his job...
加上尼奇对工作的投入…
I soon had the best operation on The Strip.
我的赌场很快就成为 精华地段中最好的赌场
Watch yourself. There's a lot of heat on you.
小心点，你最近很引人注目
Why, somebody is complaining?
怎么，有人抱怨吗？
I'm hearing things from security. They're all ex-cops.
我从警卫那儿听来的 他们以前都曾是警察
The sheriff wants to put you in the Black Book.
警长已将你放入黑名单了
That Black Book is a bunch of bullshit.
那黑名单根本就是个屁
There's two names in it for the whole country...
全国只有两个人的名字在里面
and one of them is still Al Capone.
教父艾尔卡邦就是其中之一
They put you in that book, you're gonna be in trouble.
你上了名单麻烦就大了
You won't be able to walk into a casino.
你将进不了赌场
I'm trying to make a living, that's all.
我只不过是在养家活口罢了
I'm just telling you. Don't say I didn't warn you.
我只是跟你讲一声 别说我没警告你
PHOTOGRAPHER: Mrs. Rothstein, straight ahead. Very nice. Thank you.
罗斯坦夫人，请看前面 很好，谢谢你
PHILIP: For his hard work and dedication...
因他的努力与认真…
and the new life blood he has instilled in Las Vegas...
与他为拉斯维加斯带来的新生命…
Sam has established himself as an indispensable member...
山姆将自己建立为赌博游乐业界…
of the gaming community.
不可缺乏的成员
As the head of the Tangiers Gaming Corporation...
以坦吉乐赌博游乐集团 董事长的名义…
it's my pleasure to welcome Sam Rothstein...
我很容幸为你们介绍 山姆罗斯坦…
to the Vegas Valley Country Club.
维加斯谷乡村俱乐部新成员
SAM: Back home, they'd put me in jail for what I'm doing.
要是在老家，我所做的 早就让我蹲牢房去了
But out here, they're giving me awards.
但在这儿，他们却颁奖给我
It is with great pleasure that I accept this certificate of appreciation...
我很荣幸能获得…
from the Charitable Foundations of Greater Las Vegas.
拉斯维加斯慈善基金会 颁发的嘉许奖状
Congratulations, sweetheart.
恭喜你，甜心
Sam raised more than we've ever raised before.
山姆募得了有史来 最多的捐款
SAM: But my greatest pleasure was watching my wife work the room.
但我最爱的还是看着我老婆 金吉儿周旋全场
They all loved her. How could you not love her?
他们爱死她了 但你又怎能不爱她？
She could be the most charming woman you ever saw.
她是世上最有魅力的女人
People loved to be around her.
人们都喜欢在她身边
You've got to bring Amy to Sasha's birthday party.
你一定得带艾美来参加 莎夏的生日派对
LADY: We'd love to have her there. 3:00, Saturday.
星期六下午三点 我们很希望她能来
-Yes, okay. -Great.
-好的 -太好了
SAM: She made everybody feel good.
她让大家都开心
-Congratulations, Sam. -Thanks.
-恭喜你，山姆 -谢谢
Hello, Mrs. Rothstein. How are you?
嗨，罗斯坦夫人，你好吗？
You're one of the most gorgeous women I've seen. You're a lucky man, Mr. Rothstein.
你是我见过最美丽的女人 罗斯坦先生，你真是个幸运的男人
Thanks for that compliment.
多谢夸奖
SAM: He was a young kid from the casino. Nice kid. Bright boy.
他是赌场里的小伙子 挺好又聪明的小子
What balls on this fucking kid. The next day I fired him.
这小子真他妈的带种 我第二天就炒了他
Ginger had that effect on people. I think she even encouraged them.
金吉儿对人就是有这种魅力 她甚至鼓励他们这样
GINGER: Do you wanna see this one?
你想看看这件吗？
GINGER: Daddy gave me all this jewelry because he loves me so much.
爸爸帮我买了这么多珠宝 因为他好爱我
SAM: But as much as they loved her...
但不管他们多爱她…
GINGER: Fabulous.
真美丽
...they didn't know what really moved her.
他们都不知道什么让她感动
GINGER: Look at this.
看看这个
GINGER: Daddy gave me....
爸爸给我的…
SAM: With Ginger happy, I was able to concentrate on what I knew best.
金吉儿快快乐乐的 我才能专心去做我所专长的…
Loose machines are right back over there.
较松的机器都在后面
What are they doing back there? You can't even see them.
它们在那儿干嘛？ 看都看不到
Okay.
好吧
What about the progressives with the high jackpots?
那最大累积奖金的那些呢？
These are our best machines. They bring all the action.
这些是我们最好的机子 都是靠它们
No wonder the drop is off. The action is in the front.
难怪盈收变少了 重头戏都在前面
-Bring them up front. -All right, I will.
-摆到前面去 -好的，我会
Listen carefully. There are three ways of doing things here.
听好了 在这有三种做事方法
The right way, the wrong way, and the way that I do it.
正确的、不正确的 和我的方法
-Understand? -I do understand. I'll get right on it.
-懂了没？ -我懂了，马上去办
-Thank you. -Don't thank me. Just do it.
-谢谢 -别谢我，去做就是了
You're the slots manager. I shouldn't have to tell you this.
你是吃角子老虎机的经理 我不应该还需要告诉你这些
Dang, you are right. I'm so sorry.
唉，你说得真对 真是抱歉
SAM: So I ended up working 18-hour days.
我一天得工作18个小时
Ginger was the one who wound up enjoying the best of Vegas.
金吉儿反倒是成为 真正享受赌城的人
Come with me, please. I have a better table for you.
请跟我来，我带您去更好的桌
What did you say to that fucking jerk, anyway?
你到底跟那王八蛋说了些什么？
I told him that I was Mrs. Sam Rothstein.
我跟她说我是罗斯坦夫人
You might as well get something out of it.
当然得加以利用罗
SAM: It wasn't long before what I was afraid was gonna happen, happened.
不久后我所担心的事就发生了
Nicky managed to get himself banned from every casino in Vegas.
尼奇把自己搞到成为 全赌城的拒绝往来户
From then on, I couldn't be seen talking to him anywhere in or near Vegas.
闲置马刺-97公里到拉斯维加斯 从那时起，我在赌城完全不能 被人看见与他交谈
NICKY: What the fuck is that supposed to mean?
这他妈的是什么意思？
"...detrimental to gaming and...
因对业者有害…
"he will be ejected from any casino in Las Vegas.
“他将被禁止进入 拉斯维加斯中任何赌场”
"And the casinos can be fined as much as $100,000...
“违反此规的赌场 在他每次出现时…”
"every time he shows up."
“都将被罚款逾十万元”
-You believe this shit? -Yeah, you got banned.
-你相信吗？ -是啊，你被禁了
"Because of notorious and unsavory reputation."
“因为众所周知的恶名昭彰”
Motherfucker.
那些浑蛋
-Is there any way around this? -No, there's no way.
-有什么可摆平的方法吗？ -不，没办法
Let's say, for instance...
例如说…
I want to go into the restaurant, which happens to be in the casino...
我去了家刚好就附设赌场的餐厅…
to get one of those sandwiches I like?
为了想吃它的三明治呢？
Forget it. You can't even set foot in the parking lot.
别想了，你连停车场都踏不进去
That's how serious it is.
就是这么严重
-in other words, I'm fucked? -in so many words, yes.
-换句话说，我玩完了？ -换几句话都是这意思
SAM: It didn't sink into his head about the Black Book and what it meant.
他完全都没了解那黑名单的意义
Not being able to go into a casino is just one thing...
不能进赌场只是其一…
but being in this book etched your name into the brains of every cop and FBI agent.
这名单会将你的名字刻在 每一个联邦调查员的脑海里
You're listed in there with Al Capone. But Nicky didn't care.
你与芝加哥教父是一样的 但尼奇不在乎
I gotta do something. They ain't getting rid of me.
我得想想办法 他们赶不走我的
They're not getting rid of me. I'm staying here. Fuck them.
我要待在这儿，去他们的
NICKY: So once they pulled that shit...
所以他们一开始这鸟规矩…
I started doing my own things in Vegas nobody had thought of doing.
我就开始做自己突发奇想的事情
To keep an eye on things, I brought in my kid brother and some desperados...
为了多点眼线 我将我弟弟与些恶汉从老家带来…
from back home and started knocking over high rollers, casino bosses...
开始抢劫一些赌场豪客、赌场老大…
bookmakers, anybody right here in town.
下注组头等等，全部一网打尽
I had a good fucking crew going for me, I'll tell you that.
说真的，我这队人马还真是不错
I had Sal Fusco, a great second-story guy.
我有沙尔福斯寇 最擅长从二楼进屋偷东西
Jack Hardy worked for a safe company before he did a six-year bit.
杰克哈迪在被关六年前 曾在保险箱制造公司工作
Then there was Bernie Blue. This guy could bypass any alarm for me.
还有本尼布卢 这家伙不论什么警铃都能解除
It was like old times.
就像以前一样
I opened up my own jewelry store, too. The Gold Rush.
我也开了自己的珠宝店 叫做掏金热潮
Sometimes I used to go along on a heist, just for the fun of it.
有时我会为了刺激好玩 而参与偷窃
I didn't like the people I was ripping off looking at me...
我不喜欢被我偷的人看着我…
so I turned their fucking pictures around.
所以我都将他们的照片转过去
NICKY: What's taking so long? JACK: This is a motherfucker!
-为什么这么久？ -这东西真他妈的！
It's working. NICKY: Learn to open these instead of taking them.
-在动了 -学会怎么开就不用整个搬走了
NICKY: These stones got a lot of niggers in them.
这些宝石的瑕疵真多
If that fucking Pepe's switching stones on us...
那该死的皮皮要是私下偷换钻石…
he better take a fucking camel back to Nigeria.
他最好给我骑骆驼回奈及利亚
-They're in Penthouse "K." -Check in alone?
-他们在总统套房K -单独登记吗？
-They checked in alone. -Are they out now?
-是的 -他们出去了吗？
-Yes. Don't worry. -All right. Thanks.
-是，别担心 -好的，谢啦
SAM: He had tipsters all over town. Bellmen...
我们在整城里都有线民 从旅馆侍者…
-You got to hurry. -Okay.
-得快点 -好的
-...valet parkers... -They're just checking in now.
-停车小弟… -他们正在登记
-I'll tell him. -...pit bosses...
-我会告诉他 -赌区经理…
Room 1230 at the Scirocco.
在西洛可的1230房
-1 230. Right. -...secretaries.
-1230房，收到 -还有秘书
-Mint condition coins. -Mint condition? All right.
-完美状况的硬币 -完美状况吗？收到
SAM: They all got a piece of the score.
他们当然都有一份
MAN: Car's coming.
车来了
SAM: They were very careful.
他们都很谨慎
They always bypassed the alarms, or else, if not...
他们每次都先解除警铃 要不然…
they'd drill enough holes to knock through the walls with a sledgehammer.
就在墙上打洞然后凿墙而入
Nicky was grabbing everything he could.
尼奇能偷的都偷了
Nobody out there was expecting a guy like him.
外头根本没有人想到 会有像他那样的人
For Nicky, Las Vegas was the fucking Wild West.
对尼奇来说 拉斯维加斯就像是蛮荒西部
I just got a shipment of diamonds from Israel.
我才刚拿到一批从以色列来的钻石
NICKY: What the fuck did they expect from me? I had to earn, didn't I?
他们他妈的想要我怎样？ 我得赚钱，不是吗？
-This diamond has flaws in it. -There's no flaws in it.
-这些钻石有瑕疵 -没有瑕疵
Don't tell me. I'm doing this for 25 years.
别告诉我怎么做 我在这行已经25年了
You better clean your loupe, because there's no flaws in this diamond.
你的放大镜最好擦干净点 因为这批钻石没有瑕疵
NICKY: When we got local merch...
通常要是附近来的货…
we'd usually send it to Palm Springs, or Arizona, L.A.
我们都会送到棕榈泉市 或是亚利桑那州与洛杉矶
I had a couple of sand niggers out there. You know, Arabs.
我有几个熟识的中东佬 你知道，阿拉伯人
Are you gonna have a meeting or buy some diamonds?
你们是要开会还是要买钻石？
I know his language. I'm talking with him.
我懂他的语言，我跟他讲讲
$40,000, you buy the whole package.
全部四万块
$20,000. That's my final offer.
两万，不要拉倒
He suddenly talks English. Let's talk turkey. $25,000.
他突然会说英文了 别玩游戏了，两万五
NICKY: I actually turned my bedroom into a bank vault where I kept the choice stuff.
我将我的房间改为保险箱 保留一些我特选的好东西
I couldn't leave it at the Gold Rush in case we got raided by the cops...
因为警察可能会突然临检 所以不能将其留在店里…
or if my crew got cute.
也防止我手下手痒
I had the only key. Jennifer didn't give a fuck.
我保有唯一的钥匙 珍妮佛才不在乎
She fell asleep on the couch watching TV every night.
她每晚都在沙发上 看电影看到睡着
This stuff was all mine. I didn't send any of this back home.
这些全是我的东西 我一样也没送回老家
Actually, I couldn't, because I wasn't supposed to be doing it.
其实我也不行 因为我根本不应该做这些
The bosses were making so much money with the casinos...
老大们光是赌场就赚饱了…
that they didn't want anybody making any waves.
他们不希望有人惹是非
You've all given your crew a piece of that?
你的人马每人都分到了吗？
I took care of everybody.
我大家都罩好了
NICKY: That's why there was no real organized street stuff in Vegas before I came.
这就是为什么在我来之前 拉斯维加斯并没有犯罪集团
But how much cash could I bury in my closet, right?
但我家衣柜里又能藏多少钱呢？
You have to understand, and I'm sure you do...
你必须要了解 而我也相信你了解…
that in a venture of this kind...
做这种风险大的投资…
you must be prepared to take some kind of loss.
要有可能亏损的心理准备
NICKY: I put some money in legitimate deals with Charlie Clark, Ace's banker.
我将一些钱交给查理克拉克 艾斯的银行经理，做一些正当投资
-You will try to push it through, won't you? -Yes.
-你会尽力而为，不是吗？ -是的
You got to understand, I'm giving you $50,000 cash.
你得了解我现在 给了你五万元现金
NICKY: Then I put more money in some legitimate places, like my restaurant.
然后我将更多钱投入正当的投资 例如我开的餐馆
DOMINICK: Is that the last one? COOK: Yeah.
-剩这个了？ -是
NICKY: I had my kid brother, Dominick, run it.
我让我小弟，多明尼可经营
Fuckers.
王八蛋
DOMINICK: Here you go, guys.
在这里
-Thanks a lot. -Enjoy it. Have a good time.
-谢了 -慢慢享用
-Choke on it, motherfucker. -Hi, Dom.
-噎死你，王八蛋 -嗨，小多
How you doing?
你怎么样？
SAM: Yeah, Nicky loved restaurants. He was a real restaurant buff.
是啊，尼奇很喜欢餐馆 他对开餐厅也很拿手
And over the years, he always made money with them.
这么多年来，他逢开餐厅必赚
In Vegas, he had the Leaning Tower. It was a very popular spot.
他在拉斯维加斯开了比萨斜塔 很受大家欢迎
He had politicians, showgirls and movie stars hanging out all over.
常有政客、脱衣舞娘 还有电影明星光顾
That show at The Flamingo gets better and better.
佛罗明哥的那场秀越做越好罗
By the way, Sammy said whenever you have a minute, give him a call.
对了，山姆说 请你有空时打个电话给他
-Made you a messenger, too? -I'll do anything for a buck.
-你也变传话的了啊？ -有钱我什么都做啊
-He does it to everybody. Enjoy your dinner. -Thanks.
-他对每个人都这样，好好享用晚餐 -谢啦
SAM: I got to tell you, the thing Nicky liked most was the showgirls.
尼奇最喜欢的 当然就是脱衣舞娘
To them, Nicky was the movie star.
对她们来说，尼奇像是电影名星
-You walk past me? -This is Shelly.
-你就这样走过？ -这是雪莉
-Hi, Shelly. How are you? -Hi.
-嗨，雪莉，你好吗？ -嗨
This is Stacy.
这是史黛希
-This is Nick. Wanna have dinner? Come on. -All right.
-这是尼克，想吃晚餐吗？一起吧 -好啊
Let's check the kitchen first. Excuse us one second.
我带你去厨房看看 失陪一下
NICKY: Come on, I'll show you. I fly stuff in fresh every day.
来吧，我带你去 我每天都空运新鲜的东西进来
I get bread from back home. I get fish from California.
我从老家运面包 从加州运鱼
You can always tell a great kitchen like ours because of the milk-fed veal.
光从我们用奶喂食的小牛肉就看得出 我们绝对是好餐厅
That's the secret. See, milk-fed veal is pure white.
这就是诀窍 奶喂小牛的肉是纯白色的
Out here, they got that pink veal. Slide over, honey.
其他餐馆都用那种粉红色的小牛肉 过去点，甜心
Now, pink veal you can pound for two days.
粉红色的那种小牛肉 你就算是追个两天两夜
NICKY: It'll never ever get tender. You know what I mean?
它还是不会变嫩 你懂我的意思吗？
AL: I left here with the money. Got muscled on the street.
我从这儿拿钱离开时 在街上被抢了
A couple guys, I owe them. So I gave them the money.
是几个我欠钱的家伙 所以我把钱给他们了
-That's what I did. -Yeah?
-就是这样 -是吗？
You call yourself a man?
你还敢自称是男人吗？
You know you're a lying lowlife, motherfucking gambling degenerate prick?
你知道你是个撒谎的杂碎 他妈的烂赌的狗东西吗？
You know that's what you are? Two small kids at home.
你知道自己是什么东西吗？ 家里有两个小孩
I gave you money to pay the fucking rent...
我给你钱付房租…
and buy groceries, put the heat on.
买菜、开暖气
You know your wife called Frankie and told him the fucking heat's off?
你知道你老婆打给法兰克 说家里连暖气都被停了吗？
You didn't gamble that money? Can you tell me that?
你没拿钱去赌吗？ 你敢这样跟我说吗？
-No, you didn't? -I didn't.
-你没有吗？ -没有
Don't fuck with me, Al! Don't make a fuck out of me.
别耍我，艾尔！ 别把我当傻子
You wanna make a fool out of me? You didn't gamble?
你当我是傻子是吧？ 你没去赌？
Tell me you gambled the money and I'll give you the money to put the heat on!
告诉我你把钱拿去赌掉了 我就给你钱回去交电费！
Did you gamble?
有没有赌？
Fucking degenerate, you.
真是他妈的狗东西
Fucking kids at home.
孩子在家里
Here. Get the fuck out of here.
拿去，给我滚
AL: Thanks, Nick. NICKY: Yeah, thanks.
-谢了，尼克 -是啊，谢了
If I find out you fucked up, I'll leave you where I find you.
若被我知道是你搞砸的 我会把你扔在我找到你的地方
NICKY: How many of these you gonna eat? NICKY JR.: Two.
-你要吃几个？ -两个
SAM: At around 6:30 a.m., when he finished his day...
但早上六点半，当他下班时…
no matter where he was or what he was doing...
不管他在那里或是在做什么…
he always went home to make breakfast for his son, Nicky boy.
他都会回家为儿子，小尼奇做早餐
NICKY: I know you like this.
我知道你喜欢
NICKY: A little butter, right? Not a lot. You know why, right?
一点点牛油，对不对？ 不要很多，你知道为什么，对不对？
NICKY: Why? NICKY JR.: 'Cause it clogs up your heart.
-为什么？ -因为会堵塞心脏
What a smart kid you are.
你真是聪明的孩子
NICKY: Okay, eat.
快吃吧
NICKY: Every couple of weeks, I sent Marino back to the bosses...
每隔几个礼拜我就会派玛雷诺 去老大那儿…
BACK HOME with a piece of what I made. Not a big piece, but what did they know?
在老家 也分他们一份 当然不是很多，但他们哪知道？
They were 1,500 miles away, and I don't know anybody who can see that far.
他们在2500里外，天高皇帝远
Their drop was a truck stop garage...
收货地点是个修车场…
where Remo and the guys used to hang out and count their millions.
利蒙他们以前常在那儿数钱
The cops knew, but they didn't give a fuck. They worked it out.
条子们也知道，但他们不在乎 他们早协议好了
Nicky sends his warmest regards.
尼奇向你们问好
NICKY: I knew how to keep the bosses happy.
我知道怎样让老大们服服帖帖
Whenever they gave me little jobs to do, you know, to send a message...
每当他们有些小事需要我做 例如传个话之类的…
I would carry things out to a "T."
我一定做到完美
Like the time Tony Dogs, who was supposed to be the new maniac tough guy in town...
就像那次东尼道格 那个听说是城里的新硬汉…
shot up one of Remo's bars.
在利蒙的一家酒吧乱开枪
Here's a fucking guy who kills two of Remo's guys...
这浑蛋打死了两个利蒙的手下…
and a poor fucking waitress who was just working on her night off.
还有一个代班的倒霉女侍者
This guy's just begging to be made an example of.
这家伙根本就 等着被我们杀鸡儆猴
I want the names of all the other people he had with him.
我要知道当天有谁跟他一起动手
I don't care what you have to do to them to get them. You understand?
我要你不择手段去查 懂不懂？
FRANK: I'll take care of it.
我搞定，利蒙
NICKY: To be truthful with you, I had to admire this fucking guy.
说真的，我还蛮佩服这浑蛋的
He was one of the toughest Irishmen I ever met.
他真是我所遇过 最硬脖子的爱尔兰人
This son of a bitch was tough.
这家伙真是个硬汉
For two days and two nights, we beat the shit out of him.
我们痛殴了他两天两夜
We even stuck ice picks in his balls.
还用冰锉刺他的G丸
NICKY: Hope he gives me a name, or I'll give him yours, Frank.
他最好快吐个名字出来 法兰克，要不然我就递你的上去
FRANK: Thanks a lot.
谢谢喔
NICKY: But he never talked.
但他守口如瓶
NICKY: I know you would've ratted by now.
我知道你要供早就供了
NICKY: In the end, I had to put his fucking head in a vice.
最后，我还得他妈的把他的头 摆在夹板里
NICKY: Can you hear me?
你听到了没？
Listen to me. I got your head in a vice.
听好，你的头在夹板里
I'll squash your head like a grapefruit if you don't give me a name.
再不给我个名字 我就夹爆你的头
NICKY: Don't make me do this. Please, come on.
别逼我这么做，拜托你快说吧
Don't make me be a bad guy.
别逼我当坏人
Fuck you.
去你的
Motherfucker. You believe this? Two fucking days and nights.
王八蛋，你相信吗？ 他妈的两天两夜
Fuck me? You motherfucker!
去我的？你这个王八蛋！
Fuck my mother? Is that what you're telling me?
去我老母？ 你是这意思是吧？
You motherfucker!
你这浑蛋！
Oh, God. Give me the fucking name!
天呀，给我一个名字！
Charlie M.
查理
-Charlie M. -Charlie M?
-查理 -查理？
You make me pop your eye out your head...
你逼我将你眼珠都爆出来…
to protect that piece of shit?
就为了保护这狗屁名字？
You dumb motherfucker!
王八蛋加蠢才！
Kill me, you fuck!
杀了我啊，浑蛋！
You motherfucker!
你这王八蛋！
Frankie, do him a fucking favor.
法兰克，你帮帮他吧
SAM: Word got around that finally...
镇上流传着…
there was a real gangster in town.
说这儿终于出了个真的帮派份子
Nicky was the new boss of Las Vegas.
尼奇成了拉斯维加斯的新老大
SAM: Four reels, sevens across. Three $15,000 jackpots.
四个轮，一排七个 三个一万五的奖金
You have any idea what the odds are?
你知道这机率是多少吗？
It's gotta be in the millions. Maybe more.
要好几百万，可能更多
Three jackpots in 20 minutes?
二十分钟内三个大奖？
Why didn't you pull the machines? Why didn't you call me?
你为什么没停机？ 为什么没通知我？
It happened quick. Three guys won. I didn't have a chance.
发生得太快，一下就三个人赢 我还没机会
You didn't see the scam?
你没看到出千吗？
There's no way to determine that.
这无法确定
Yes, there is. An infallible way. They won!
有，绝对有 他们赢了就是最好的证据
It's a casino. People gotta win sometimes.
这里是赌场，总会有人赢的
You're pissing me off. You're insulting my intelligence.
你气死我了 你在污辱我的智慧
You think I'm an idiot?
你认为我是白痴？
Somebody had to get into those machines and set the reels.
一定有人对转轮动了手脚
The probability on one machine is a million and a half to one.
一台机的机率是一百五十万比一
On three machines in a row, it's in the billions. It can't happen.
连续三台的机率是好几兆比一 这根本不可能
SAM: What's the matter with you?
你到底是怎么了？
Didn't you see you were being set up on the second win?
你难道不知道你被骗了吗？
-You didn't see that? -I think you're overreacting.
-你没看到吗？ -我觉得你有些反应过度
Listen, you yokel, I've had it with you.
听着，智障，我受够你了
I've carried your ass ever since I got here.
我从到这儿时就一直罩你
Get your things and get out of here.
把东西收收走吧
-You're firing me? -I'm firing you.
-你开除我？ -我就开除你
-You might regret this. -I'll regret it if I keep you.
-你可能会后悔 -留你我一定后悔
-This is not the way to treat people. -If you didn't know about the scam...
-不应该这样对人 -若你不知道有人出千…
you're too dumb to work here. If you did, you were in on it.
你就蠢到不配在这儿工作 若你知道，你就是共犯
Either way, you're out. Go on.
不管怎样，你都得走
The guy is history as far as I'm concerned.
在我看来那家伙已经被炒了
You can't fire him. His brother-in-law is County Commissioner.
你不能开除他 他的姐夫是县辅导
Everyone out here with cowboy boots is a commissioner or related to one.
这里每个穿马靴的不是辅导 就是辅导的亲戚
I'm sick of this.
我受够了
This is his state. His uncle's Chief Judge.
这是他的州，他的叔叔是大法官
His brother-in-law runs the County Commission.
他的姐夫管理县委员会
There's gotta be a way to work him back in.
一定有方法让他回来
You're in the finances, upstairs. You don't see what's going on.
你是搞帐目的，在楼上 你看不到下面发生的事
I've got thousands of players. I got 500 dealers.
我有上千的赌客 却只有五百个庄家
They're all looking to rob me blind 24 hours a day.
他们每天24小时都在想着 怎么将我抢空
I have to let them know I'm watching all the details all the time.
我必须要让他们知道 我随时都在注意每个细节
That there is not one single thing I will not catch.
我不会漏掉任何一样事情
SAM: Look at yours. Look at that.
看你的，看
SAM: Look at this. There's nothing.
再看这个，什么都没有
Look how many blueberries your muffin has.
你看你的蓝莓那么多
-I have nothing. -What are you talking about?
-我一个都没有 -你在说什么？
If you don't do it yourself, it never gets done.
自己不动手做就弄不好
PHILIP: Where are you going?
你要去哪儿？
SAM: From now on, I want you to put an equal amount of blueberries in each muffin.
从现在开始 我要你全都放同份量的蓝莓
Do you know how long that will take?
你知道那多花时间吗？
I don't care how long it takes. Put an equal amount in each muffin.
我不管要多久 每个松饼的份量都要一致
Just a little. That a girl.
再吃一点，乖
SAM: Wanna go to Mommy? GINGER: Wanna come to Mommy?
-你要找妈妈？ -来妈妈这儿？
It's all right, sweetheart.
好的，甜心
GINGER: I need to talk to you. I need some money.
我要跟你谈谈，我需要点钱
-What do you need? -Got her?
-你要什么？ -抱好了吗？
I need a lot. I need more than usual.
我需要很多，比平时要多
Why don't you take it out of your account?
为什么不从你户头领呢？
I would, it's just that...
我本想，只是…
I need more than that. I need $25,000.
我需要更多，我要两万五
$25,000?
两万五千元？
-For yourself? -Yeah.
-你自己要？ -是啊
SAM: Why do you need that much?
你为什么要那么多？
What's the difference? I just need it.
有什么差别？我需要就是了
I gotta ask you. That's a lot of money. It's not a box of popcorn.
我一定得问啊 那很多钱耶，又不只是一盒爆米花
We don't have to turn this into a big deal.
我们不用将这变成件大事
We don't have to have a fight.
我们不用吵架
GINGER: It was important to me. Forget it. Something I wanted to do.
只是对我很重要，算了 有些想做的事罢了
Who's fighting? Tell me what it's for.
谁在吵架？ 告诉我钱的用处
Why can't you tell me what it's for?
为什么不能告诉我？
Now I want you to tell me.
现在我要你告诉我
My wife comes to me and asks me for $25,000. Do you want a coat?
我老婆跑来问我要两万五 你想买大衣吗？
GINGER: No. SAM: If you want a coat, you got it.
-不 -如果想买大衣，就去买啊
It's not the money. It's just, why do you want it?
不是钱的问题 只是，你为什么要？
Am I not entitled to ask that?
我无权过问吗？
I've been independent all my life. I never had to ask anybody for anything.
我一辈子都很独立 我从不为任何事求人
Now you're making me beg you for this.
现在你要我求你是吧
-What are you talking about? -Okay? And you're embarrassing me.
-你在说什么？ -好，你还羞辱我
Why make me feel so bad? SAM: You're asking me for $25,000.
-为什么得让我如此难受？ -你问我要两万五
I'm not out to make you feel bad. I want to just be able to trust you.
我不是要让你难堪 我只是希望能信任你
It's about trust.
是信任问题
I have to be able to trust you with my life.
我必须要连性命都能交托于你
Do you understand?
你懂吗？
Can I trust you?
我能信任你吗？
Can I trust you? Answer me.
我能吗？告诉我
You can trust me.
你能
Good. So then you can tell me what the money is for.
好，那你就可以告诉我 钱要拿来干嘛
She's leaving the bank now.
她现在正离开银行
I'll follow her.
我跟着她
LESTER: What is that?
那是什么？
I know that look. What does that look mean?
我知道那神情，那表情是什么意思？
GINGER: It means I got the money.
意思是我有钱
How are you doing? It's Lester, right?
你好吗？是莱斯特吧？
From my recollection, aren't you the card shark...
我记得你不是玩牌老手…
the golf hustler, the pimp from Beverly Hills?
高尔夫球骗子 比佛利山庄的皮条客吗？
SAM: If I'm wrong, correct me.
若记错了，请纠正我
I never knew you to be a heist man.
我从不知道你也是个小偷
But if you are, you know what?
不过如果是的话，这样吧
Here, take mine, too.
我的也拿去吧
Take it. You already have hers.
拿吧，反正你已拿了她的
She's my wife.
她是我老婆
SAM: Look at me.
看着我
You did know that, didn't you? You knew she's my wife?
你知道吧？ 你知道她是我老婆吧？
SAM: Look at me. LESTER: I know that.
-看着我 -我知道
SAM: You do, yeah?
知道啊？
If you ever come back again...
你下次若再想回来…
to take her money, next time bring a pistol.
拿她的钱，记得带枪
That way you got a chance.
这样你才有机会
Be a man, don't be a fucking pimp.
当个男人，别做皮条客
Now, you want to do me a favor? Get out of here.
现在，卖我个面子 快滚吧
I wanna be alone with my wife. Get the fuck up and get out of here.
我想跟我老婆独处 给我他妈的滚
SAM: Fucking piece of shit.
浑蛋狗杂种
Remember when you called him that night and said goodbye to him?
记得那晚你打电话跟他道别吗？
He didn't say, "Don't get married. I'll be right down."
他并没说：   “别结婚，我马上来”
-He didn't say that, did he? -No, he didn't.
-他没这样说吧？ -不，没有
What did he say?
那他说了什么？
"Fuck him. Take him for everything he's got."
“跟他睡，捞光他的钱”
Come here. I want to show you something.
过来，我给你看样东西
GINGER: Make them stop it!
叫他们停！
It's not his fault! It's my fault!
不是他的错！是我的错！
THUG: Piece of shit.
没用的狗杂种
LESTER: Do it yourself, you chickenshit cocksucker!
自己来吧，你这没胆的浑蛋！
He's such a prick.
他太可恶了
He had some guy from the hotel beat him up.
他叫旅馆的人揍他
He didn't want to do it himself.
他自己不想动手
He didn't want to get his own hands dirty.
他不想将手弄脏
Why did he have to do that?
他为什么要这样？
Tell me.
告诉我
NICKY: It wasn't a nice thing to do-- GINGER: No shit.
-那不是件好事… -废话
You gotta understand it. He doesn't know if this guy is shaking you down.
你得了解，他并不知道这人 是不是在骗你的钱
I told him all about this guy before we got married.
我在结婚前就告诉过他这个人了
-This is no fucking surprise. -You did? I didn't know that.
-这并不是什么新鲜事 -是吗？我并不知道
He's just a friend of mine I was trying to help. So what?
他只是我的朋友 我想要帮他，有什么大不了？
The first time I ever saw you guys together...
我第一次看到你们俩在一起时…
I never saw him so happy.
我从未见他那么快乐过
NICKY: I know he's a crazy Jew fuck and everything...
我知道他是个犹太疯子…
but I never seen him act like that with anybody else.
但我从未见过他跟别人一起时这样
I think he's crazy about you. He really loves you.
他为你疯狂 他真的很爱你
NICKY: He does. GINGER: Come on.
-他真的是 -拜托
I went into this with my eyes open.
我是睁着双眼走进这关系的
GINGER: I knew the bottom could drop out any time.
我知道随时都可能变卦
I'm a working girl. You don't think I'm gonna go into a situation like this...
我也混过，你真以为 我在没有保障的情况下…
if I don't think I'm covered on the back end?
会走这条路吗？
Sure, I can see that.
是啊，我可以了解
So he put aside some jewelry for me. A lot of jewelry.
他买了好多珠宝给我 好多好多
A lot of expensive jewelry? About how much?
很多贵重的珠宝？ 大概值多少？
You want to steal it?
你想偷吗？
No. I'm just curious. I was wondering...
不，只是好奇 我是在想…
how much he would put into a thing like that.
他会在那种东西里 投入多少钱
I'm told it's worth about $1 million, maybe more.
他跟我说大约一百万 可能更多
NICKY: There you go. What does that tell you?
那就是罗 这说明了什么？
$1 million in jewelry.
一百万的珠宝
Does that tell you he is crazy about you?
这不说明了他爱你爱到疯了吗？
I should have never married him.
我根本就不该嫁给他的
He's a Gemini. Triple Gemini. Duality.
他是双子座的，双子加三级，两面人
Gemini is the snake, you know. You can't trust a snake.
双子座就像条蛇 你不能相信蛇
I mean it.
我说真的
I know what you mean. Listen, Ginger.
我懂你的意思，金吉儿，听着
This is probably not.... I don't have the answers anyway.
这可能不是… 我也没有答案
-This is probably not what you want to hear. -I do.
-这可能不是你想听的 -我想
You're a little upset, and I understand that.
你不高兴，我可以理解…
But try to make the best of it now. Go slow. See what happens.
但先撑着点吧 慢慢来，看看会发生什么事
He could've killed him!
他差点杀了他！
He didn't have to hit him. I'm not sleeping with the guy.
他用不着打他 我又没跟他上床
He makes me sneak around to see my own friends.
他让我得偷偷摸摸的 跟我的朋友见面
What the fuck is that all about?
这算什么呢？
I guess it's 'cause he loves you so much, he's jealous and worries.
我想是因为他太爱你了吧 他吃醋又担心
Who gives a fuck what I do?
谁会在乎我做什么？
I'll try to find out what the hell is going on.
我会试着问问到底怎样
-When I see him, I'll talk to him. -Okay.
-遇到他时我会跟他谈谈的 -好
-All right? -Yeah.
-可以吗？
Thanks...
谢了…
for putting up with me.
忍受我唠叨
Take it easy with this shit. This can only make matters worse.
别喝这么凶吧 这只会让情况更糟
You're a beautiful girl. Don't ruin that.
你是个美女，别搞砸了
I've seen a lot of girls get shot to hell from this stuff.
我看过太多漂亮女孩 因这个变丑八怪
You're so nice.
你真好
Come on, now. I don't wanna see you unhappy.
好了啦 我不想见你不快乐
Thanks.
谢了
It's all right.
没事啦
County Commissioner Pat Webb is here to see you.
县辅导派特委布来见你
-Give me a minute. -Okay. Just a minute.
-等一下 -好的，请稍候
RECEPTIONIST: Can I get you anything?
你需要什么吗？
No, thank you, little lady.
不，谢谢，小姐
Send him in and call me four minutes after.
让他进来，然后四分钟后打给我
Mr. Rothstein, I'm Pat Webb.
罗斯坦先生，我是派特委布
How do you do?
你好吗？
-It is a pleasure. -I heard a lot about you.
-幸会 -我常听起你的事
PAT: Thank you, sir. House is doing well.
过奖了，庄家最近还过得去
All that money is rolling in.
那么多钱滚滚而来
I appreciate you taking the time to see a poor old civil servant.
我很感激你愿意见我这老公仆
SAM: Why don't you have a seat? PAT: Thank you, sir.
-不如坐下吧？ -谢谢您
PAT: I come here personally to smooth over...
我是来亲自化解…
any fracas about a certain matter.
一些小误会的
Maybe you didn't know it...
你可能不知道…
but Don Ward is a very well-liked man in this town.
但道恩华德在镇上挺受欢迎的
He's got lots of friends. His family and their money go back many years.
他有许多朋友 他们家族及产业也很久了
Friends vote, family and money votes.
朋友是选民 家人与金钱都能助选
That's important to me and you.
这对你我都很重要
If you'll think about our little problem along them lines...
若你从这个角度 来看我们这个小问题的话…
and you'll forgive me for saying it...
很抱歉我得这么说…
maybe he did not deserve to be fired.
但他可能不该被开除
He knew about our getting hit...
他非常清楚我们…
on three big machines in a row, and he did nothing about it.
在一瞬间被赢了三个大奖 但他却袖手旁观
Either he was in on it or, forgive me, he was too dumb to see it.
他要不是跟他们一伙 那很抱歉，他就是蠢到看不见
Either way, I cannot have a man like that working here.
不论如何，我都无法让一个 这样的人在这儿工作
Before we point the dirty end of the stick at old Don...
在将过错都推给道恩前…
we better be sure we can prove them charges.
我们得先确定有证据这样指控他
Believe me, if I could prove it, he'd be under arrest.
相信我，要是有证据 他早就被逮捕了
Are we certain that you want the Gaming Control Board...
你确定要让赌博游乐委员会…
eyeballing your record and your gangster pals like Nicky?
过目你与你的帮派朋友 尼奇的记录吗？
I think you're way out of line talking to me like that.
我觉得你这样跟我说 有点太过份了
What you're saying is libelous. You're in no position to challenge my expertise.
你所说的几乎是毁谤 你无权怀疑我的专业
I went way out of my way to be helpful and courteous to that kid.
我已尽我所能去 帮助并善待那孩子
He's weak. He's incompetent. He jeopardizes the whole place.
他太弱了也很无能 他使这地方濒于险境
There's not much more I can do for him.
我对他真的无能为力
You have got me there.
这倒是真的
Old Don is as useless as tits on a boar.
道恩就像公猪身上的奶头一样无用
But he is my brother-in-law...
但他还是我的小舅子…
and I would look on it as a personal favor...
我会当是我欠你的一个人情
if you'd think some more on hiring him back.
若你愿意考虑重新聘用他
I can't do that.
我不能
I appreciate the fact that he's your brother-in-law.
我知道他是你的小舅子
I do want to help you and I like to do favors.
我也想帮你更喜欢卖人情
And I know who you are. But I cannot do that.
我也知道你的地位 但我真的不能这么做
Could there be any position...
日后是否会有其它较适合的…
farther down the trough?
职位呢？
I'm sorry. I can't do anything.
抱歉，并没有
He's too incompetent. The bottom line is he cannot be trusted.
他太无能了 最终还是他不能被信任
SAM: Okay, thanks a lot.
好吧，谢谢
That's it. I'm sorry.
抱歉
Mr. Rothstein, your people never will understand...
罗斯坦先生 你们这帮人永远都不会懂…
the way it works out here.
这里的世界如何运作
You're all just our guests.
你们只不过来此地做客
But you act like you're at home.
但却喧宝夺主
Let me tell you something, partner. You ain't home.
让我告诉你，老兄 这并不是你家
But that's where we'll send you if it harelips the Governor.
家是我们州长生气时 送你们回的地方
-Thank you for your time. -No problem.
-多谢你空出时间见我 -没问题
-Sorry. -You bet.
-对不起 -当然
SAM: What happened to my pills?
我的药呢？
Isn't it bad enough you drink too much? You're taking my pills, too?
你喝那么多酒还不够吗？ 你还要吃我的药？
GINGER: I didn't take your pills.
我没吃你的药
For my ulcer, I take a half of one of these.
我因为胃溃疡，才吃半颗
That's when I have extreme pain.
而且是痛到无法忍时才吃
I had a three-month supply. What did you do with them?
我本来有三个月份的 你弄到哪里去了？
GINGER: [Crying] You didn't have to beat him up.
你用不着打他的
SAM: What?
什么？
GINGER: I was just trying to help him.
我只是想帮他
GINGER: Like I'm sleeping with the guy.
好像我跟他上床似的
Yeah, how do I know?
是吗，我哪知道？
GINGER: You can't make me stop caring about people.
你不能让我完全不关心别人
SAM: What? GINGER: I said...
-什么？ -我说…
you can't make me stop caring about people.
你不能让我完全不关心别人
SAM: Listen...
听着…
I'm trying to make the best of everything here.
我只想让一切比较好
I mean, you're my wife, for Christ's sakes.
老天啊，你是我老婆
People look up to you in this town.
镇上的人都很看重你
You know what, Ace? I don't give a shit.
你知道吗，艾斯？ 那关我屁事
I'm getting out of here.
我要离开
SAM: You gotta get a hold of yourself.
你冷静一点
GINGER: Okay. SAM: If not for me, at least for Amy.
-好 -不为我，也为艾美
SAM: Understand? Your drinking's getting way out of hand.
懂吗，你酒喝得太过份了
I'm gonna get you into a program. They got plenty of good ones.
我帮你安排去做治疗 这儿有很多好疗养所
-I don't need one. -Yes, you do. It's very discreet.
-我不需要 -你需要，那很隐密的
There's no names in the papers.
姓名也不会被公布
That's all you care about.
你只在乎名誉
GINGER: You don't care about me.
你不在乎我
SAM: Yes, I do. GINGER: No, you don't.
-我在乎 -不，你不在乎
How could you say that?
你怎能这样说？
You're a beautiful woman. You're destroying yourself.
你是个美丽的女人 你在摧残自己
You don't need that stuff, that fucking leech living off you.
你不需要那些 你现在芒刺在背
I know you better than you know yourself.
我比你还要了解你
You're a tiger. You're stronger than I am.
你像只老虎，你比我还坚强
When you set your mind on doing something, you do it better than anybody.
只要你下定决心的事 你就做得比任何人都要好
You're gonna do it.
你一定得去
Oh, God.
天啊
I'll try.
我试
GINGER: I will.
我会的
Don't be mad at me, okay?
别生我气，好吗？
NICKY: No matter what the problems were outside the count room...
不管在计算室外有多少问题…
it was all worth it.
都是值得的
The cash kept rolling in...
现金滚滚而来…
and the suitcases kept coming and going.
皮箱也不停的进出
And let me tell you, the fucking bottom line here is cash.
让我告诉你 除了钱还是钱
The only problem was that after a while...
唯一的问题是过了一阵子后…
the bosses noticed that the suitcases were getting a little light.
老大们发觉皮箱越来越轻
Wait a minute. You mean to tell me...
等一下，你是说…
that the money we're robbing is being robbed?
我们抢的钱被人抢？
Somebody's robbing from us?
有人抢我们？
We go through all this fucking trouble and somebody's robbing us?
我们这么大费周章 竟有人在抢我们？
Like I said, it's part of the business. It's considered leakage.
如我所说，这就是这行的一部分 就当做是遗漏的
Leakage, my balls. I want the guy who's robbing us.
遗漏，狗屁 我要找到抢我们的人
NICKY: Even John Nance, that's the guy who ran the scam...
就连约翰南斯 主导这骗局的人…
he knew there wasn't much he could do about it.
都知道自己无能为力去阻止
You gotta know that a guy who helps you steal...
你得知道一个肯帮你偷钱的人…
even if you take care of him real well...
就算你把他照顾得好好的…
he's gonna steal a little extra for himself.
他还是为自己多偷一点
Makes sense, don't it? Right?
很合理不是吗？
You go try and make these hard-headed old greaseballs understand that.
试着让这些固执的老头们了解吧
What's the point of skimming if we're being skimmed?
如果自己抽完还要被别人抽 还有什么意义？
It defeats the whole purpose of what we're doing.
这样我们根本就在做白工嘛
They take this money because they're my guys, so give them some leeway.
他们是我的手下才帮我们拿钱 就睁只眼闭只眼吧
NICKY: But the bosses never believed in leeway...
但老大们从来就不相信这理论…
so listen to what they do.
听听他们做了什么
They put Artie Piscano, the underboss of K. C...
他们将艾题派斯康 堪萨斯市的二佬…
in charge of making sure nobody skimmed the skim.
调来管理 确定没有人抽头
BOSS: What were you doing? I was with my cumari.
-你那时在干嘛？ -我与我马子一起
BOSS: What were you doing with your cumari? I gave her a schiaffo.
-你跟你马子那时在干嘛？ -我打她一巴掌
NICKY: The only trouble was, Piscano was a disaster.
问题是，派斯康是个麻烦
This guy could fuck up a cup of coffee.
这家伙连泡咖啡都可搞砸
BOSS: What you been doing? ARTIE: I'm out there more than I'm here.
-你都在干嘛？ -我在那儿的时间比在这儿多
NICKY: Little did anybody know where this would lead.
当时没人想到 后来会演变为何
If they did, they would've been better off making fucking novenas.
若有人早知道 去做念珠可能都还好些
You gotta go back there and talk to that guy.
你得回去跟那家伙讲
-My expenses weren't paid for the last trip. -What expenses?
-我上次的花费都还没补给我 -什么花费？
I'm laying money out of my own pocket, and I never get anything back.
我一直自掏腰包 却什么都拿不回来
You gotta go back out there.
你得再回去
From now on, I'm gonna start keeping records.
从今开始 我得开始做记录了
What are you gonna do with records, pay taxes?
你要记录干嘛，缴税吗？
I can't keep laying out my own fucking dough for these trips.
我不能一直这样自己出钱 跑来跑去
What the hell are we doing over here?
我们他妈的到底在那儿干嘛？
You're going to Las Vegas and having a good time at my expense.
我花钱让你去赌城玩
What the fuck? I mean, after all....
我靠，我是说…
SAM: No matter how many novenas you could make...
不论你做了几符念珠…
nothing was gonna stop what came up next at the casino.
都无法阻止接下来 在赌场发生的事
PHILIP: I can't believe you're doing this. ANNA: We made a deal.
-我不相信你会这样做 -我们有协议
SAM: It turned out Phil Green, "Mr. Integrity"...
结果菲立浦葛林，   “老实先生”…
had a partner nobody knew about...
有个没人知道的搭挡…
and when she showed up and demanded money from Tangiers...
当她出现并向坦吉乐要钱时…
-Why are you doing this to me? -Because you're wrong.
-你为什么这样对我？ -因为你错了
ANNA: I'm not. PHILIP: You are.
-我没错 -你有
No, I am not wrong.
不，我没错
...Green tried to stonewall her.
葛林试着搪塞她
ANNA: I will see that you don't get away with this.
我不会这么轻易的放过你的
So, she sued him in court.
所以她一状告到法庭去
The court will now hear the matter of Anna Scott...
本庭现在将开始审理 安娜史考特…
against Tangiers Corporation and its President, Philip Green.
对坦吉乐集团与其总裁 菲立浦葛林
OBERON: Oberon on behalf of Mr. Green. LOGAN: Logan on behalf of Anna Scott.
-葛林先生将由欧伯伦辩护 -安娜史考特的律师则是罗根
JUDGE: Mr. Oberon, you can proceed. OBERON: Thank you.
-欧伯伦先生，可以开始了 -谢谢，大人
I believe he was fair, and I'm delighted with the decision.
我觉得判决很公正 而我也对判决非常满意
We got a problem.
有麻烦了
It didn't go too well. Green has to open up the books...
官司结果不理想，葛林得呈交帐簿…
has to show how he got the financing.
他得解释钱是怎么来的
That's not good.
这可不好
NICKY: She was doing pretty good with her lawsuit.
她官司还打得不错
But before she could start counting her money...
但在钞票还未落入她口袋之前…
the boys back home decided to settle the case out of court.
老家的老头子们就已决定庭外和解
So they sent me.
因此他们派我
REPORTER: Any comment on the murder of Anna Scott?
你对安娜史考特的谋杀 有什么想法吗？
What are you talking about? REPORTER: She was found last night shot in the head.
-你在说什么？ -她昨晚被人发现中弹身亡
MAN: Was this just a real estate partnership?
只是有关房地产合伙问题吗？
MAN 2: Her lawyer said you were partners.
她的律师说你们是搭挡
We were involved in minor real estate deals many years ago.
我们是在多年前 在一些小房地产交易上合作过
It was never a partnership.
称不上是搭挡
MAN: Did you ever hear of the.22 caliber killer?
你听过.22口径杀手吗？
SAM: Now, Instead of the cops only looking at Nicky...
现在条子不只是盯尼奇…
they started looking at Green, too.
他们也开始盯葛林
And he was supposed to be our squeaky-clean front man.
他本是我们的正派门面
I had to start giving interviews to make sure everybody knew...
我得接受访问 让大家都知道…
the casino was on the up-and-up.
赌场没有牵涉到案子
So how often do you really fill in for him?
你多常帮他代班？
Green's here about two or three times a month...
葛林一个月大约来个两、三次…
and he's busy with other real estate deals, and things.
他还有其他房地产交易 和别的事要忙
So in Green's absence, then, you're the boss?
所以葛林不在时 你就是老大罗？
I serve at the pleasure of the Chairman of the Board.
我很荣幸能为董事会的主席服务
My responsibilities are to run the day-to-day operations.
我的责任是管理赌场的日常运作
So day-to-day, then, you're the boss?
所以平常日子你就是老大？
Well, in a sense, you could say that I am the boss...
可以这么说吧…
when Mr. Green is away.
当葛林先生不在时
You could say that.
可以这么说
PAT: Have you read this?
你看了没？
About Mr. Rothstein.
关于罗斯坦先生
It says, "The Midwest bookmaker with mob ties...
上面说：   与黑道有关连的 中西部下注者…
"says that he is the real boss of the $100 million Tangiers casino empire."
“说他才是价值一亿的坦吉乐赌场 真正的老板”
PAT: Do you believe that? OFFICIAL: Did he really say that?
-你相信吗？ -他真的这么说？
Why, of course he really said that. It's right here.
他当然是这么说的 这儿不都写了吗
Has that man even filed for his license yet?
这家伙申请执照了没？
I don't know. We have to check the files.
我不知道，得查查
Without getting your shorts in a knot, would you do that?
去查查看吧，用不着太激动
And check closely, 'cause we may have to kick a kike's ass out of town.
查仔细点，我们也许能 将这死犹太人踢出城了
PAT: Thank you.
谢谢
A Gaming Control Board investigation of Tangiers executive...
赌博游乐委员会开始调查 坦吉乐的高层主管…
Sam Rothstein's application for a gaming license is underway.
山姆罗斯坦的赌博游乐执照 还没核发下来…
Rothstein, who heads the Tangiers casino operation and is a boyhood friend...
罗斯坦负责管理坦吉乐赌场的运作 并也是赌城黑手党老大…
of Las Vegas mob boss Nicky Santoro...
尼奇山多罗的儿时好友…
could lose his ability to work in the casino....
他有可能会失去 在赌场工作的权力…
Hello?
喂？
I gotta meet Charlie the Banker right away at your house, okay? I gotta meet Clean Face right away. What about the Chez Paris?
我要去你家见见银行经理，好吗？ 我得见见清洁工 在小巴黎如何？
You gotta make a reservation. It's all booked up.
你得要订位，一定客满了
NICKY: No, it's okay.
不用，没关系
I don't want a meeting at my house. It's impossible. It's booked up, and it's very difficult to get in.
我不要在家见客 不可能啦，绝对客满 而且很难进去
I'll come in from the golf course side. See you at six. It's okay, I'll use the service entrance. I'll see you at nine.
我会从高尔夫球场过来 六点见 没关系，我走后门 九点见
All right.
好
The battle between state gaming officials and Tangiers casino boss...
州政府赌博游乐处官员 与坦吉乐高层…
Sam "Ace" Rothstein is heating up.
山姆“艾斯”罗斯坦之战正如火如荼
Tonight, a look at Ace Rothstein's attempt to get state licensing...
今晚，看看艾斯罗斯坦如何 尝试取得州立执照…
despite law-enforcement allegations of Rothstein's organized crime connections.
虽然面对警方的指控 怀疑罗斯坦与犯罪集团有勾结
Will Sam Rothstein's friendship with organized crime figure, Nicky Santoro...
山姆罗斯坦与黑道人物 尼奇山多罗之间的友谊…
keep Rothstein from running the Tangiers casino?
是否会阻碍罗斯坦 管理坦吉乐赌场呢？
And can the integrity of state gaming laws be jeopardized by a boyhood friendship?
而州政府的赌博游乐法规 是否会因儿时友谊而受到威胁呢？
SAM: Why don't you take it easy on that stuff?
你少喝点吧？
Come on. Let me help you down.
来，我扶你下楼
We're talking about some stuff.
我们在谈话
NEWSCASTER: At 6:00, will a boyhood friendship...
今晚六点，儿时的友谊是否…
unseat Rothstein as the Tangiers casino boss?
会让罗斯坦失去坦吉乐 老大的位子？
Exclusive on the KBBO special news report.
KBBO独家专题报导
Go down. Just go downstairs.
下楼去，到楼下去
You can't let this concern you, Ace. Don't worry about that stuff.
你不能让这影响你，艾斯 别管这些了
It's just a political witch hunt.
只是政治圈找替死鬼游戏
SAM: Do you want something to drink?
你要喝什么吗？
-Charlie, you want a refill? -Yeah, that would be great.
-查理，你还要吗？ -好啊
I don't want nothing. Hi, Mr. Clark. I've been trying to reach you.
我什么都不要 嗨，克拉克先生，我一直在找你
-You're tougher to get than the President. -I've been busy.
-你比总统还难找 -最近比较忙
Yeah? At least you could return my phone calls, though.
是吗？但你至少也该 回我个电话吧
Listen, Nicky, we talked about this.
听着，尼奇，我们谈过这个
And I explained to you that you might have to take some kind of loss.
我也跟你解释过 你可能会有亏损
I think I want my money back.
我想把钱拿回来
What are you gonna do, strong-arm me?
你是要威胁我吗？
I think you've gotten the wrong impression about me.
我想你可能误解我了
I think, in all fairness...
我觉得为公平起见…
I should explain to you exactly what it is that I do.
我应该告诉你我打算怎么做
Tomorrow morning I'll get up nice and early, take a walk to the bank...
明天一大早我就会散步去银行…
and walk in and see, and if you don't have my money for me...
走进去看看 若还没把我的钱准备好的话…
I'll crack your fucking head wide open in front of everybody.
我就会在众人面前爆开你的头
And just about the time that I'm coming out of jail...
而当我服完刑出狱时…
hopefully, you'll be coming out of your coma.
希望你也能从昏迷中苏醒
And guess what? I'll split your fucking head open again.
知道吗？ 我会再爆开你的头
'Cause I'm fucking stupid. I don't give a fuck about jail.
因为我是个傻子 我完全不在乎坐牢
That's my business. That's what I do.
这就是我的职业 我会做的事
We know what you do.
我们知道你的职业
You fuck people out of money and get away with it.
你把人的钱骗走 然后大摇大摆的走开
You can't talk to me like that. NICKY: You fat Irish prick!
-你不能这样对我说话 -你这只爱尔兰肥猪！
You put my money to sleep. Get it, or I'll put your brain to sleep.
你害我领不到我的钱 你最好把它弄出来，不然我要你好看
Never mind Sam. This is personal.
山姆别看，这是我们的事
I'll be there in the morning. You can try me, fatso.
我明天早上一定到 你试试看啊，肥猪
-You think he got the point? -What are you doing?
-你觉得他懂了吗？ -你在干嘛？
He's a square guy, for Christ's sakes. He's gonna run to the FBI.
他是个老实的生意人 他会去找联盟调查局的
That prick's been dodging me for three weeks.
这浑蛋躲了我三个礼拜了
-You're trying to tell me what to do? -I'm not trying to tell you what to do.
-你在告诉我该怎么做吗？ -我没有要告诉你该怎么做
You're way out of line. Where's your head?
你太过份了，你的脑哪里去了？
Where's my head? Where's your fucking balls?
我的脑？ 你的种又去了哪儿？
I'm trying to put something big together. You know what I'm talking about.
我有更大的计划 你知道我在说什么
If you're acting like this now, how can I depend on you?
如果你现在就这个样 我还怎么指望你啊？
A lot of things gonna change. If you wanna be there with me...
很多事都要改变了 你若要跟我一起…
you're gonna have to go my way.
你就得听我的
You got to understand my situation. I'm responsible for thousands of people.
你得体谅我的处境 我得对上千名员工负责
SAM: I got $100 million a year going through the place.
我每年都得经手一亿元
It's all over if I don't get that license.
我若拿不到执照就玩完了
Believe me, if it goes bad for me, it's gonna go bad for a lot of people.
相信我，我若玩完了 很多人就会跟着完蛋
Forget about your fucking license.
去他妈的什么烂执照
I plant my own flag out here, you ain't gonna need a license.
到时候我说的就是法律 你根本不需要什么执照
I don't know what it is, but the more I talk to you...
我不知道为什么 但越和你说话…
the more I feel like you just don't want to go along with me.
我越觉得你不会挺我
-No, I don't want to come along with you. -All right.
-不，我不打算和你一起 -好
I don't want to be involved in anything you're talking about, okay?
我不想涉入你所说的任何事，好吗？
I want to run a square joint. I just want my license.
我只想好好经营赌场 我只要我的执照
I want everything quiet. That's it!
我只想一切都安静下来
Quiet like this? "I'm the boss"? That's quiet?
这样叫安静？ “我是老大”这样叫安静？
It's taken out of context. I had no control.
他们扭曲了意思 我根本控制不了
Ronnie and Billy will tell you exactly what happened.
罗尼与比利可以告诉你整个经过
Back home that looks bad.
这在老家很难看
Looks bad? Every time you're on television, I get mentioned. That looks bad.
难看？每次只要你上电视 就会提到我，这才叫难看
What the fuck happened to you?
你到底怎么了？
-What happened to you? You lost control? -I lost control?
-你怎么了？整个失控？ -我失控？
You're fucking walking around like John Barrymore.
你他妈的像个电影明星似的走来走去
A pink robe and a fucking cigarette holder? I lost control?
穿粉红色的浴袍还拿烟盒？ 是我失控？
I don't wanna bring this up, but you treat people with disrespect. Even your own wife.
我本来不想提的，但你不尊重人 连你老婆都不例外
My wife? What does she have to do with this?
我老婆？关她什么事？
She was upset about a lot of things, especially that Lester Diamond incident.
她为了许多事不高兴 尤其是莱斯特戴蒙德那档
You're the shoulder to cry on? Did you tell her about your role in that?
你是她哭诉的对象？ 你没告诉她那事你也有份？
No, that's not the fucking point.
没有，那不是重点
The point is, she's upset, and you've got a problem.
重点是，她不快乐 你也有问题
I'd appreciate it if you'd stay out of my personal life.
我希望你不要干涉 我的私生活
You wouldn't like it if I did it to you.
若我这样你也会不爽吧
She came to talk to me. Was I supposed to throw her out?
她来找我说话的 我该赶她出去吗？
Stay away from her. It's none of your business.
离她远一点 不关你的事
A week ago it was. Now it's not. When you need me, you need me.
一周前就是我的事，现在就不是 你需要我时，我就得到
Right, the way you need me to vouch for you as a citizen.
是啊，就像你需要我 帮你做担保一样
I'm gonna have to straighten out what you did with this guy.
我得去解决你刚刚对那人 所做的事情
This guy's gonna run to the FBl.
他会去找联邦调查局的
NICKY: Your head's bigger than your casino. That's your problem.
你的自尊比你的赌场还大 这就是你的问题
SAM: I knew what he wanted and I didn't want any part of it. He wanted to take over.
我知道他想做什么，但我不想参与 尼奇想自个儿当老大
He wanted to go after Gaggi, the skim, everything and everybody.
他想干掉盖吉 抽头，还有一切
He also stopped asking permission from back home for every little thing.
他不再每件小事都要老家批准
A casino boss and his wife were killed. The bulls questioned Nicky.
一位赌场大亨与他老婆被杀了 调查员侦问了尼奇
A dealer from the Scirocco. They questioned Nicky.
一位西洛可的庄家 他们也询问尼奇
Stool pigeons wound up in the trunks of their cars. They questioned Nicky.
几个线民死在自己的后车箱里 他们也追问尼奇
A lawyer.
一个律师
They questioned Nicky.
他们问尼奇
When some guys who didn't pay their shylocks began disappearing...
当一些拖欠高利贷的人 莫名的开始消失…
Nicky's name was in every newspaper.
尼奇的名字布满每家报纸
Nicky was questioned in two dozen murders, but they always had to let him go.
尼奇因为一堆谋杀案调查被侦讯 但他们每次都放他走
There were never any witnesses.
从来没有目击者
NICKY: The coppers blamed me for everything that went wrong.
条子把所有的不顺 都归昝于我
Watch yourself. You're gonna get runned over.
小心点 你会好看的
NICKY: If a guy tripped over a banana peel, they'd bring me in for it.
若有个家伙踩到香蕉皮跌倒 可能都要带我回局里
Be nice.
客气点
NICKY: The bosses were no better. They complained because things don't run smooth.
老大们也没好到哪儿去 他们抱怨事情运作不顺
In my line of work, things don't run so smooth. I'm sorry.
不过在我这行 真抱歉，事情本来就不会顺
I'm dealing with degenerate animals out here.
我每天对付的可是些三教九流之徒
The bosses, what do they give a fuck?
老大们在乎个屁啊？
They're sitting on their asses drinking anisette.
他们只会坐着喝酒
Meanwhile, I'm the guy in the trenches.
而这期间我得做牛做马
Fucking bosses think it's a fucking free lunch out here.
那些王八老大们 真以为天下的午餐都是免费的
Frankie, they found a guy's head in the desert.
法兰克，他们在沙漠里 找到一个家伙的头
You know about that?
你知道吗？
I heard.
听说了
Everybody's talking about it and making a big deal out of it. It's in all the papers.
大家都在讲，报纸里也有登
What are you gonna do?
你要怎么办？
That's no good.
这可不好
Tell him to take care of things a little better.
叫他做事要小心点
I'll tell him, Remo.
我会的，利蒙
NICKY: Fucking bosses smoking their Di Nobilis...
王八老大们抽着雪茄
and eating trip' and fucking soffrit', fried pigs' guts...
吃着他们的美食…
while if I wanna talk private, I gotta go to a fucking bus stop.
而我若想私下找人谈话 我还得坐在公车站
-What do they care? Long as I send money. -They're complaining.
-他们在乎个屁？只要我拿钱回去 -他们在抱怨了
Let them complain. I'm the one who's here. I do all the work.
让他们抱怨，是我在这儿 活都是我在做
NICKY: Somebody don't like it, fuck them. FRANK: It's up to you.
-有人不喜欢，就去他的 -你决定罗
NICKY: They want a fucking war? I'm ready.
他们他妈的想打仗？ 我准备好了
If I take care of five of those guys, the rest will fall into place.
我只要干掉那五个 其他的自然会水到渠成
NICKY: Peek-a-boo, you fucks, you.
被我抓到了吧，这群王八羔子
I see you, you motherfuckers.
我看到你们了，浑蛋
SAM: Nicky was not only bringing heat on himself, but on me, too.
问题是，尼奇不只是 让自己更受注目，还连累到我
The FBI watched every move he made, but he just didn't care.
联邦调查局盯着他的每一步 但他不在乎
NICKY: If they're gonna watch me, I'm gonna watch them back.
想要盯我，我就盯回去
I spent a few bucks. Top dollar. Who gives a shit?
或许花了很多钱 但谁在乎？
I got the latest anti-bugging equipment from the same places that sell to the CIA.
我买了最先进的反窃听装置 向卖给中央调查局的那家买的
I had all the special police frequency radios, FBI de-scramblers, night-vision cameras....
我有所有的警察特殊频道对讲机 FBI的解干扰器、夜光照相机…
So, the miserable sons of bitches never caught me doing anything I couldn't handle.
这些衰角从未抓到我任何把柄
SAM: I got my job on the line, he's having the time of his life.
我工作都快丢了 但他却玩得不亦乐乎
He has every cop in the state watching him, and he's out playing golf.
全州的警察都在盯他 他却在打高尔夫球
And at the worst possible time for me.
对我来说时期最坏不过
I had my license hearing coming up and I didn't want to leave anything to chance.
我的执照听证会要到了 我不想有一点点失败的机率
If I can't work in Vegas, where am I gonna go?
若不能在赌城工作 那我要去哪儿？
You've been very open with us with the books and papers.
你一直都很合作 从文件到帐簿
That'll mean a lot when you go before the commission.
这对委员会是很重要的
-All I ask is a fair hearing. -This honesty will guarantee it.
-我只希望能有个公正的听证会 -你的诚实会为你赢的
We'll move on to....
接下来…
SAM: I want to hear about Kansas City.
我想听听关于堪萨斯市
What the fuck is this?
这他妈的是什么？
Where's this fucking guy gonna land, in the fairway?
这家伙要停在哪里，球场上吗？
They're fucking agents, Frankie. Look at this.
他们是探员，法兰克 来看看
SAM: The Feds were watching Nicky play golf for so long...
他们盯尼奇打高尔夫盯到…
they ran out of gas.
飞机没油
Just what I needed, right in front of the control board.
还真是我需要的 就在委员会面前
$100, whoever hits the plane.
赌一百看谁先打到飞机
SAM: If things weren't bad enough... in comes Piscano, the Kansas City underboss.
祸不单行，随后就看到派斯康 堪萨斯市的老二
He ran the grocery store in Kansas City where they brought the suitcases.
在堪萨斯市收皮箱的那家超市 就是他开的
Fighting over those suitcases again. You know what that means?
又在为皮箱的事吵了 你知道这代表什么吗？
I gotta take another trip to Vegas. It's gonna cost me another couple grand.
我又得去拉斯维加斯了 又要花我好几千
SAM: He ran it with his brother-in-law...
他和他姐夫一起开店…
but he mostly complained about his trips to Vegas to his brother-in-law and mother.
但他大多都在跟他姐夫与岳母 抱怨他去赌城的事
You gotta lay down the law, or they'll make a fool out of you.
你得表明态度 要不然他们当你是病猫
I write it all down. Every fucking nickel goes down.
我全记下来了，他妈的每一分一毛
-What's the matter with you? -Everything's here.
-你是怎么了？ -全都在这儿
-Since when do you talk like that? -I'm sorry.
-你何时开始这样讲话？ -抱歉
Nance gives me trouble, I'll take the eyes out of his freaking head.
南斯要是找我麻烦 我就将他的眼挖出来
-Again. -I didn't curse, I said, "freaking head."
-又来了 -我没骂粗话
-That's enough. -I'm sorry.
-够了 -抱歉
SAM: What happens next, you can't believe it.
接下来发生的事 简直是出乎意料
Who'd believe the FBI had a wire in the place...
谁会想到联邦调查局 会在里面装窃听器…
looking for information about some old homicide...
为了调查很久以前的一桩命案…
about some guy who was whacked out God knows when over God knows what?
为了一个不知在何时 也不知为何事被干掉的人
What prevents him with the suitcases from taking what he wants?
你怎么阻止拿皮箱的人 拿走他想要的？
Nance brings back two suitcases from the Tangiers. What about three or four?
南斯从坦吉乐拿了两口箱子回来 若其实有三箱或四箱呢？
We've got nobody in the room to watch. That's the law.
我们没有人在计算室里看着 那是法律
We can't even go into the count room to watch our money.
我们甚至连计算室都进不去
He's got his people in there. They could all be in on it together.
他有他的人在里面 他们搞不好根本是一伙的
I'll find out. If it's Green himself, I'll bury that bastard.
若我知道是葛林干的 我会埋了那王八蛋
I never trusted him. I got eyes behind my head.
我从就不相信他 我后脑都有眼睛
They trust that scumbag. I don't.
他们信任那浑蛋，我可不
I'll hit the two of them in the head with a shovel.
我该给他们一人一铲
MA: Take it easy.
冷静点
Ma, I'm sorry. They're beating me left and right.
妈，抱歉 但他们一直跟我玩阴的
ARTIE: I'm sorry. I'm upset. I know, but that's enough.
-抱歉，我很生气 -我知道，可是够了
You know what they're doing to me. I can't take this no more.
你也知道他们在对我做什么 我受不了了
MA: Take it easy. You'll get a heart attack. ARTIE: I know. I'm too upset.
-冷静，别心脏病发 -我知道，我太气了
SAM: The damn thing is, they hear all this stuff...
该死的是，他们听得一清二楚…
about Las Vegas, casinos, and suitcases...
关于拉斯维加斯，赌场还有皮箱…
and that's it.
玩完了
ARTIE: Everything's coming out of my pocket. I gotta pay.
全都是从我口袋里掏 我得付钱
SAM: Would you believe this could happen?
你相信有这么巧吗？
ARTIE: I'm in this to make money, not lose it.
我是来赚钱的，不是亏钱
SAM: Every FBI man across the country had their ears open now.
全国每个联邦调查局探员 都张大了耳朵
ARTIE: If you want something done right you gotta do it yourself.
要将事情办好就得靠自己
SAM: Piscano, this guy, basically sunk the whole world.
派司康这家伙 几乎搞砸了所有人的生活
MA: There are some that are good and some that are bad.
有些好的就有些坏的
COUNSELOR: Members of the Commission...
主席先生 委员会的同仁…
Mr. Rothstein is pleased to be here today.
今天罗斯坦先生很荣幸能在这儿
SAM: When the day finally came, I was ready.
当那天终于来时 我已准备好了
I felt so confident that all I had to do was present my case.
我自信满满的认为 我只需要呈上我的案件
COUNSELOR: We have documents, one of which is a report by retired FBl agents...
我们拥有文件，其中一份是由 一位退休的联邦探员写的…
which completely absolves Mr. Rothstein from any wrongdoing.
上头清楚的记载罗斯坦先生 并未触犯任何法律
-Counselor, before you continue... -I want to have this marked....
-律师，在你继续前… -我要将这呈为…
...this Commission acts on a motion denying the Rothstein application.
本委员会针对是否应 驳回罗斯坦的申请书在此动议
COUNSELOR: Denying? SENATOR: Do I hear a motion seconded?
-驳回？ -有人赞成驳回吗？
Mr. Chairman, I second the motion.
主席先生，我赞成
Do I have a vote on the motion?
还有赞同票吗？
-Aye!
同意！
The ayes have it. This hearing is adjourned.
同意票获胜，听证会结束
-You have to be kidding. -Adjourned? What do you mean?
-开什么玩笑 -什么叫结束？
Senator, you promised me a hearing. You didn't even look at the FBl reports.
议员，你答应我一场听证会的 你连联邦调查局的报告都没看
When you were my guest at the Tangiers Hotel, didn't you promise me a fair hearing?
你来坦吉乐作客时 不是答应我会有公平的听证会？
SENATOR: I was never your guest. SAM: Never my guest? I never comped you?
-我从未是你的客人 -不是我的客人？我没招待过你？
I don't comp you at least three times a month?
难道我一个月 没有最少招待你三次？
I'd like to answer that at this time.
我现在回答这个问题
Mr. Rothstein is being very typical to this point. He's lying.
罗斯坦先生的反应很常见 他在撒谎
The only time I was at the Tangiers was a dinner with Barney Greenstein.
我唯一一次去过坦吉乐 就是巴尼葛林斯坦那次晚宴
Was I at the dinner? SENATOR: You were wandering around.
-我当时在场吗？ -你四处周旋着
SAM: Was I at that dinner? SENATOR: You were wandering.
-我在场吗？ -你四处周旋
SENATOR: You were in the building. SAM: I was in the building?
-你在室内 -我在室内？
You know damn well I was there. You swore I would have a fair hearing.
你很清楚我在那儿 你向我保证会有公正的听证会
Did you not?
没有吗？
Tell me I was at least at the dinner. Allow me that much.
至少承认说我那天在场 这总可以了吧
SAM: Give me that much at least! SENATOR: Yes, you were.
-至少也得说我在场吧！ -是，你在
Thanks for not calling me a liar, you son of a bitch.
多谢你没说我是骗子 你这个狗东西
A routine licensing hearing turned into bedlam yesterday...
一场例行的听证会 在昨晚成了一场闹剧…
when the flamboyant Tangiers Casino executive, Sam "Ace" Rothstein...
当抢眼的坦吉乐高层 山姆“艾斯”罗斯坦…
accused top gaming officials of corruption.
指控赌博游乐委员会高官贪污
...promised me a fair hearing when you were comped at my hotel?
你在我的旅馆接受招待 并答应我会有公平的听证会
And you asked for copies of your bill to put on your expense account.
你还要求将你的帐单挂公帐
In a wild outburst that followed his gaming license denial...
当赌博游乐执照被驳回时大吼大叫…
Bullshit! ...Rothstein followed several...
-狗屁！ -罗斯坦与好几名…
stunned commissioners into the hallway where he continued his harangue...
错愕的委员到走道 并持续着他的指控…
until his own lawyers and friends urged him to leave.
直到他的律师与朋友劝他离开
You have a past. I have a past. My past is no worse than yours.
你有过去，我也有过去 我的不见得比你的糟糕
You guys think you have the right to pass judgment!
你们还自以为有权去判决别人！
NEWSREADER: Long suspected of running Tangiers without a license...
被怀疑长期无照管理坦吉乐…
yesterday's hearing was to determine if someone with Rothstein's history...
昨天的听证会本是要决议 像罗斯坦如此背景的人…
was qualified to officially hold a top gaming post.
是否有资格正式在赌博游乐界 担任如此高的职位
REMO: Fucking hypocrites!
罗斯坦玩完了 王八伪君子！
-What the hell's he gonna do now? -I don't know.
-他现在怎么办？ -我不知道
What's he doing?
他在干嘛？
He knows all those guys he yelled at are friends of ours.
他也知道他大吼大叫的那群人 都是我们的朋友
What's the matter with him, making all this mess?
他是怎么了，搞得一团糟？
Maybe he could run things with another job title.
他或许可以用另一个头衔管事
Won't be the best, but what are we gonna do?
这不是最好的 但我们又能如何呢？
REMO: However he runs things, it's gotta be quiet. Let him hide upstairs in the office.
他不论管什么，都得安静点 让他躲到楼上办公室去
Say he's a janitor. I don't give a shit.
说他是工友，我不在乎
But please, whatever job he takes, make sure it's something quiet.
但拜托，不管他做什么 都得低调点
ANNOUNCER: [On TV] Ladies and gentlemen...
各位先生与女士…
the Tangiers Hotel proudly presents the all-new...
坦吉乐大饭店 非常荣幸能为您介绍…
Sam Rothstein show, Aces High.
山姆罗斯坦秀，   《艾斯的单人牌》
Tonight, taped live from the all-new sports book...
今晚，从最新的球赛赌区 现场实况转播…
we present the premiere showing of Aces High...
我们为您带来《艾斯的单人牌》的 首次演出…
with the Sasha Semenoff Orchestra...
连同莎夏西门诺夫交响乐团…
and the Sam Rothstein dancers!
与山姆罗斯坦舞群！
Mr. Rothstein is a professional gambler and the best U.S. football handicapper.
罗斯坦先生是位职业赌徒 也是全美最棒的美式足球下注者
A man who will take you inside the real Las Vegas as no one has ever done before.
一位能带领你进入 真正的拉斯维加斯的人
Now, the new entertainment director of the Tangiers Hotel Casino...
现在让我们欢迎 坦吉乐赌场新的娱乐董事…
Mr. Sam Rothstein.
山姆罗斯坦先生
Welcome to the Sam Rothstein show. We're happy to have you here this evening.
欢迎来到山姆罗斯坦秀 很高兴你们能参与
The young lady to my left is Trudy...
我左边的这位小姐是特茹蒂…
who is a lead new dancer in our fabulous show from Paris.
她是我们巴黎秀新的首席舞者
Our first guest this evening...
我们今晚的第一位来宝…
is Frankie Avalon.
法兰克艾华伦
PAT: Keep an eye on him. FRANKIE: I've got a large family.
-看好他 -我有个大家庭
SAM: How many kids do you have? I'm very proud to say, eight children.
-你有几个孩子？ -我很自豪的说，八个
-That's amazing. -There's nothing to it. It was my pleasure.
-太了不起了 -没什么，是我的荣幸
PHILIP: Ace, don't do it.
别这样
Jesus.
天啊
He's juggling!
他在耍杂技！
SAM: Let's not take County Commissioner Pat Webb too seriously.
我们别对县辅导 派特委布太认真
I recently challenged him to a debate on this program, and he declined.
我最近本想邀他在节目上辩论的 但是他拒绝了
What are you worried about, Pat? You don't have to send me any questions.
你在担心什么呢，派特？ 你不需要事先给我问题
You can ask me anything you want.
你什么都可以问我
ANDY: What the hell is he doing on television?
他在电视上干嘛？
He's on all night, screaming about taking his lawsuit to the Supreme Court.
他整晚都在上面 喊着要将他的案子告上最高法院
He really must be crazy. He's gonna go to Washington with this?
他真是疯了 他想将这带到华府去？
He's out of his fucking mind.
他简直是疯了
It's a pity we have such hypocrisy. Some people do what they want.
世上有这样的伪君子真是可叹 他们爱做什么就做什么
Other people have to pay through the nose. Such is life.
其他人却得承担后果 这就是人生
Andy, go see him. Tell him maybe it's time he should quit.
安迪，去找他 告诉他辞职的时候到了
SAM: First, what they did was totally unconstitutional.
第一点，他们的所做所为 完全的违反了宪法
SAM: We're on the list to be heard before the U.S. Supreme Court.
我们已在高等法院的等候单上了
These guys don't care about the Supreme Court.
这些家伙才不在乎高等法院
They want things to quiet down. They want you to walk away.
他们要一切平息，要你别再搞了
Walk away? Andy, you can't be serious. Don't you see what's at stake?
别搞了？安迪，你不是说真的 你难道看不到这严重性吗？
The old man said maybe your friend should give in.
老头说你的朋友或许该罢手了
When the old man says "maybe," that's like a papal bull.
当老头说“或许”时 就像是教皇发谕令一样
Not only should you quit, you should run.
你不但该罢手，还该跑路
Every time they mention my name in the papers, they mention Nicky, too.
他们每次在报上提到我的名字 就一定扯到尼奇
How the fuck does that help?
这他妈的有什么帮助？
The heat he brought down is murder.
他带来的注目简直是谋杀
The police department was cooperative.
警察局本来很合作
They're pissed off. Nobody can make a move anymore.
他将他们激怒到 现在大家都动不了
What do you do about that?
你能怎样呢？
-What are you proposing? -I don't know. He doesn't listen to me.
-你想说什么？ -我不知道，他根本不听我的
Maybe he should get lost for a while. Would that be so bad?
或许他才该消失一阵子 这样会很糟吗？
-They ain't sending Nicky nowhere. -If he took a break...
-他们不会调走尼奇的 -若他离开一阵…
it would give everybody time to maneuver.
给大家移动布局的机会
I would forget about the maneuver. I would just get out.
别再搞布局的事 赶紧离开吧
I can't do that.
我不能
SAM: Of course, as soon as Andy got home, Nicky heard about our talk in the car.
当然，安迪一到家后 尼奇就听说我们的谈话
Next morning, bright and early, I get the call.
第二天一大早，我就接到电话
I've got to do some shopping. Want to go?
我得去买点东西，你要不要去？
SAM: Getting a call from Nicky wasn't easy anymore.
连接尼奇的电话都不是件易事
Even the codes didn't work. So we figured out another act.
暗号都没有用了 我们得想新方法
If a phone's tapped, the Feds can only listen in on the stuff involving crimes.
若是电话被窃听 他们只能听关于犯罪的谈话
On routine calls, they have to click off after a few minutes.
例行通话时 他们必须在几分钟后挂断
GINGER: I got a sprained fucking elbow.
我手肘好像扭到了
Meet me at 3:00.
三点见
-At Caesar's? -100 yards further down the road.
-在凯撒宫吗？ -这条路下去再一百码处
-Why? -Don't ask questions. Just be there.
-为什么？ -别问了，到那儿就是了
Suzy Cream Cheese has the same outfit.
苏西克理姆有件一模一样的衣服
GINGER: I saw something.
我看到个东西
Something very cute.
这东西好可爱
AGENT: Okay, he's out. It's the ant. Brown unit.
他出门了，棕组
He's with the bogey. I think it's Frankie.
他带着个替身，应该是法兰克
SAM: Nicky started out before me...
尼奇比我早出门…
because it wasn't that easy for him to get around anymore.
因为他要出门越来越难了
Nicky couldn't even go for a ride without changing cars...
尼奇到那儿都最起码得…
at least six times before he could shake all his tails.
换六次车才甩得掉跟踪他的人
Because of the planes, he had to use underground garages.
因为有飞机 所以他得用地下停车场
SAM: Meeting in the desert always made me nervous.
在沙漠中央会面总让我紧张
It's a scary place.
那是个可怕的地方
I knew about the holes in the desert, of course.
我当然也知道沙漠里的洞
And everywhere I looked, there could have been a hole.
我张望的每一处都可能是个洞
Normally, my prospects of coming back alive...
通常我与尼奇会面 能活着回来…
from a meeting with Nicky were 99 out of 100.
机率是百分之九十九
But this time, when I heard him say a couple of hundred yards down the road...
但这次，当我听他说 离道路几百码外…
I gave myself 50-50.
我想应该还有一半的机率吧
Where the fuck you get off talking to people behind my back?
你他妈的跟别人 在背后捅我是什么意思？
-What people? -Did you think I wouldn't find out?
-跟什么人？ -你以为我不会发现吗？
I don't even know what you're talking about.
我根本不知道你在说什么
You said I'm bringing heat on you? I gotta listen to people because of you?
你说我害你被盯？ 我得因为你被人家念？
You're ordering me out? You better get your own fucking army!
你想搞走我？ 你最好准备好自己的军队？
I didn't order you or anybody.
我没有要搞走任何人
I told Andy Stone that you had heat, and that was a problem.
我跟安迪说你被盯上了 这是个问题
You want me to get out of my own fucking town?
你想要我离开我自己的地盘？
Yeah, let the bullshit blow over so I can run the casino.
是啊，我说等风头过了 我才能好好经营赌场
Anything goes wrong with the casino, it's my ass, not yours.
赌场出了什么事我得负责，不是你
You know that you only have your fucking casino because I made that possible!
你知道你之所以能管那狗屁赌场 都是因为我！
I'm what counts out here.
在这儿我才算数
Not your fucking country clubs or your fucking TV shows.
不是你他妈的什么俱乐部 也不是你那狗屁电视秀
And what the fuck are you doing on TV anyhow?
你他妈的在电视上干嘛？
I get calls from back home every day. They think you went batshit!
我每天都得接老家的电话 他们都觉得你疯了！
I'm only on TV because I gotta be able to hang around the casino. You don't understand that....
我上电视是因为 我必须待在赌场
You could've had the food-and-beverage job without going on TV!
你不上电视也可以拿那餐饮的头衔！
-You wanted to go on TV. -Yeah, I wanted to go on TV.
-是你想上电视吧 -对，我想上电视
That way I have a forum. I can fight back. I'm known. People see me
这样我才有擂台，我才可以反击 我要有知名度
They know they can't fuck around with me like they could if I was an unknown. That's why
若我有知名度他们就不能 随随便便打发我
You're making a spectacle of yourself.
你将自己变成个笑话
I wouldn't even be in this situation if it wasn't for you.
要不是你，我也不会落到这步田地
You brought down so much heat on me.
你让我被盯上
Every time I meet somebody, they ask me if I know you.
我每次遇见个人 他们都只想知道我认不认识你
Sure, now you wanna blame your fucking license on me.
所以你现在要将你执照的那件事 怪到我的头上
When you asked me if you could come out here...
当你请示我你可不可以来这儿时…
what did I tell you? I knew you'd come out no matter what I said. Do you remember?
我是怎么说的？我就知道 不管我说什么你都会来，记得吗？
Back up a fucking minute here. One minute.
等一下，倒退一下
I asked you? When the fuck did I ever ask you if I could come out here?
我请示你？我他妈的什么时候 请示过你我可不可以来这儿？
NICKY: Get this through your head, you Jew motherfucker!
搞清楚点，死犹太人！
You only exist out here because of me! That's the only reason!
你是因我才在这儿！ 只因为这样！
Without me, you personally....
要没有我，你自己…
Every fucking wise guy still around will take a piece of your fucking Jew ass!
在这儿随便哪个还在混的 都可能宰了你！
Then where you gonna go? You're fucking warned.
到时你怎么办？ 我警告你了
Don't go over my fucking head again, you motherfucker, you!
别想再踩在我头上 你这个王八蛋！
Well, we got company.
有客人
Did you see that?
看到了吗？
Dumb Jew motherfucker. Grew up together, and he acts like he doesn't know me.
蠢犹太人，我们一起长大的 他竟装作不认识我
I know we're supposed to avoid each other, but there's ways to do things.
我知道我们应该避免碰面 不过应该有其他办法吧
Fuck him.
去他的
To Abraham Lincoln.
敬林肯总统
Forget about it. Don't let it bother you.
算了，别让这烦你
Does it look like it's bothering me? Why do I give a fuck?
我看来很烦躁吗？ 我为什么要在乎？
Oscar, too. All the money I gave him, that prick.
奥斯卡也是的 我给了他那么多钱，浑蛋
He didn't even look over. What's his fucking problem?
他连看都不看这边 他到底是什么毛病？
-Fucking Jews stick together, don't they? -They're having a good time.
-死犹太人都是一伙的，不是吗？ -他们好像玩得很快乐
So are we.
我们也是啊
Yeah?
喂？
-Sam, we got a problem. -What is it?
-山姆，有麻烦 -怎么了？
BILLY: The little guy. Nobody told him he was eighty-sixed from the joint.
那矮子，没人跟他说 他被禁止进入赌场
We turned our heads and made out like we didn't know who he was.
我们只要都假装不认识他
He's over at the 21 table with his nose wide open.
他现在在21点桌大剌剌的豪赌
He took money out of his own kick. His nose is open for about $10,000.
他从他那份抽头里拿钱 已经输了一万了
Now he's really pissed.
现在他很生气
-He wants a $50,000 marker. -Just give him $10,000.
-他要五万的筹码 -给他一万就好了
That's it. I'll be right down.
就这样，我马上来
He's gonna come up with $10,000 just the way you want.
就如你所要求 他会去拿一万
No, I said fucking $50,000!
不，我他妈的说五万！
Go get it. I don't give a fuck where you get it.
给我去拿 我不在乎你用什么方法
Fuckers. They take it but don't wanna give it back.
王八蛋 只会拿钱却不还来
How the fuck can you grin?
你还笑得出来？
You know how much I'm stuck? Do you give a fuck?
你知道我输多少了吗？ 你在乎吗？
Give yourself a hand, right across your fucking mouth.
给自己点掌声吧 顺便加一巴掌
Look at this beaut they put in now.
看看现在上来的这个怪胎
NICKY: Sherbert send you in here to rob me now?
雪伯提派你来抢我的吗？
Been fucking knocking everybody's dick in all night? Been beating the customers?
你今晚帕撕芫昧税桑坑很多喔？
Jag-off. Hit me.
再来一张
Take this stiff and pound it up your fucking ass.
将这张牌从你后面塞进去
Take this one and stick it up your sister's ass. Hit me again.
这张捅你姐姐后面去，再来一张
Keep looking at him. If you had any heart at all, you'd be stealing for a living.
一直看他干嘛，你要还有良心 你就宁可去当小偷
Hit me again! What the fuck you keep looking at him for?
再给我一张 你他妈的一直看他干嘛？
You fucking.... Look at this, 20 points in a row. Hit me again.
你这，你看看 连二十张公，再来一张
NICKY: You should pay as fast as you collect, you know.
你给钱应该跟拿钱一样快吧
-You gotta get out of here. -Tell this motherfucker to pay that marker.
-你得走了 -叫那王八蛋付筹码
You're not listening. I'm here to help you. You're gonna bury us both.
你没在听，我是来帮你的 你会将我们俩都毁了
-Just give me the money. -I'm gonna okay you $10,000, that's it.
-把钱给我 -我只批准一万，就这样
Then you gotta get out before the cops are all over you.
然后你得在条子找到你之前给我走
$10,000 and that's it.
就一万
What are you staring at, you bald-headed Jew prick?
你在看什么？ 你这秃头的死犹太人
-Come on. Let's get out of here. -Sue me, you Jew fuck!
-快，我们快走 -告我啊，死犹太人！
NICKY: Get out of here? I got a marker coming. Deal.
走？ 我有筹码要来耶，发牌
I know, but everything's changed now. You're talking about a divorce.
我知道，但现在情况不同了 你要求的是离婚
You're asking for alimony payments and child support, and now custody.
你要求你与孩子的赡养费 现在又要孩子的监护权
I just want what any divorced woman would get.
我只要任何一个离婚女人想要的
She's only sober about two hours a day.
她一天不过清醒两个小时
It's usually from 11:00 a.m. to 1:00 p.m.
通常是早上十一点到下午一点
If I gave her her money and her jewels, she's gonna piss it all away in a year.
我要是给她钱与珠宝 她一年内就会浪费光了
Where would you be then? Coming right back to me...
到时你怎么办？ 还不是又回来找我…
or finding some other excuse to come....
或找什么其他的理由回来…
We had a deal. Remember that?
我们有协议，记得吗？
He said if it didn't work out between us, I could get my things and leave.
他说过若我们之间走不下去 我可以拿我的东西走
Look in my eyes.
看着我
SAM: You know me.
你知道我
Do you see anything that makes you think I would ever let...
你看到任何迹象 让你觉得…
someone in your condition take my child away from me?
以你现在的状况 我会将我的孩子交给你？
Do you?
有吗？
You know that won't happen.
你知道这不可能
SAM: And after all this time...
过了这么久…
and as hard as I tried, as much as I wanted...
不管我多么努力，多么想…
I could never reach her.
我始终触碰不到她
I could never make her love me.
我无法让她爱我
I always felt she should have gone for all that money...
我总觉得她会爱我 那么多的钱…
being somebody for the first time in her life, a home, a kid.
第一次在生命中成为一个重要的人 一个家、孩子
That's not what happened. It didn't work out that way.
但事实并非如此 那样做却行不通
Everything all right? SAM: What could we do?
-都好吗？ -我们能怎么办？
After a while, we'd just take breathers from each other. Little separations.
过一阵子后，我们开始放对方的假 短期的不见面
At that time, I remember Ginger took Amy and went to Beverly Hills.
那时，我记得金吉儿 带着艾美去比佛利山庄
She was gonna spend a week shopping.
她要去逛一个礼拜的街
OPERATOR: Yes, Mr. Rothstein. The Beverly Hotel in Beverly Hills.
-是的，罗斯坦先生 -比佛利大饭店
RECEPTIONIST: Hello, Beverly Hotel. SAM: Mrs. Sam Rothstein, please.
-你好，比佛利大饭店 -请找山姆罗斯坦夫人
RECEPTIONIST: Sorry, Mr. and Mrs. Rothstein have checked out already.
很抱歉，罗斯坦先生与夫人 已经退房了
Mr. and Mrs. Rothstein?
罗斯坦先生与夫人？
RECEPTIONIST: Yes, they both checked out. SAM: Thank you.
-是的，他们俩都退房了 -谢谢
Hello.
喂
My wife is with an old friend of hers in L.A.
我老婆跟她一个老朋友在洛杉矶
Some lowlife named Lester Diamond.
一个叫莱斯特戴蒙德的败类
My daughter's with them. They're gonna try and kidnap her.
我女儿跟他们在一起 他们会试着绑架她
SAM: Is there anybody you can send? MAN: We'll take care of it.
-你那边有人吗？ -我们会帮你搞定
We got a number and an address.
查到电话号码与住址了
SAM: Hello. Is this Lester?
喂，是莱斯特吗？
Who's calling?
哪位？
This is Sam Rothstein. I want to talk to Ginger.
我是山姆罗斯坦 我要跟金吉儿讲话
She's not here, Sam.
她不在这儿，山姆
Listen to me very carefully. I want to talk to Ginger.
你给我听好 我要跟金吉儿说话
I want my kid back. I want her put on a plane immediately.
我要我的孩子 我要她马上搭下班飞机回来
SAM: I know she's there. Don't fuck around. LESTER: I wouldn't.
-我知道她在，别玩把戏 -山姆，我没有
You shouldn't do this.
你不应这么做
SAM: You understand? Put her on the fucking phone.
你懂不懂？叫她听电话
Sam, I don't know where she is.
山姆，我不知道她在哪儿
LESTER: So, listen, can I call you back in a few minutes?
听着，我可以待会儿打给你吗？
702-472-1862
702-472-1862
LESTER: I'll call back. SAM: Right away.
-我马上回你 -马上
-Right back. -You got it.
-好的
Schmuck. All right, I just bought us a few minutes.
白痴，好了 我多拖了一些时间
LESTER: You want to get back at this prick?
你想报复吗？
LESTER: You got what, $2 million in that box?
那保险箱里有两百万对吧？
You got a minute? He's got $2 million in the box, right?
喂，耽误你一下？ 他保险箱里有两百万对吧？
You let him keep your jewels. We take the cash...
珠宝就留给他，我们拿走现金…
and the only other thing he cares about. Her majesty.
与他唯一在乎的另一件东西 他的小公主
We go to Europe. You dye your hair.
我们去欧洲，你把头发染了
I don't want to go to Europe. I want to go to see The Elephant Man.
我不要去欧洲 我要去看TheEIephantMan
We're going to Europe. Let the adults talk. You dye your hair.
我们要去欧洲，让大人讲话 你去染头发
You get plastic surgery like we talked about.
像我们所说的去整容
How much you think he'll pay to get this kid back?
你觉得他会愿意付多少赎金？
AMY: I don't want to go to Europe. LESTER: Shut your mouth.
-我不要去欧洲 -你给我闭嘴
AMY: You shut up. LESTER: Want me to come over?
-你才闭嘴 -你要我过来？
LESTER: I'll smack your face. Don't give me your shit!
我一巴掌打死你，别找我麻烦！
This has always been a dream, but now we're going.
这本来是个梦 但现在要实现了
-Lester, he called you here. -Right. Ace was on the phone.
-莱斯特，他打到这儿来 -他刚在电话上
-I just talked to him. -So he knows where you are.
-我刚跟他讲完 -所以他知道你在哪儿
That means he's sending some guys over here now.
这表示他现在就派人过来了
It means he's sitting by the phone, like a dumbbell....
这表示他在电话旁像个蠢蛋…
GINGER: Yeah, he's sitting by the phone waiting for you to call him back!
对，他就像是蠢蛋坐在电话旁 等你打给他！
What are we gonna do? He's probably got guys outside the fucking house!
我们该怎么办？他可能 已经派人在门外守着了！
-It's this fucking bullshit of yours! -Get your bag! Let's go!
-又是你在那儿鬼扯！ -快拿行李，快走！
-What bullshit? You want to talk it over? -Are you done yakking?
-什么鬼扯？你想现在讨论这吗？ -你唠叨完了没？
Go! Get in the car!
快！快上车！
Just relax. Nobody's killing anybody.
冷静点，没人要被杀
GINGER: I think he's gonna kill me. NICKY: Relax.
-他一定会杀了我 -冷静点
Call me back here in exactly an hour on this phone. I'll see what I can do.
一个小时后打这支电话给我 我想想办法
I'll call you back in an hour at this number...
我一个小时后打给你…
-and you'll be there, right? -I'll be here.
-你会接对不对？ -我会在
Listen, don't do anything else crazy. You all right?
听着，别再做什么蠢事了 你还好吗？
Okay, bye.
好，再见
GINGER: Knock it off. LESTER: She started it.
-停止 -是她开始的
She started the whole thing.
都是她开始的
-Don't even think you're gonna drive. -I'm gonna drive.
-你别想开车 -我来开
LESTER: I'm not gonna drive with a crazy woman. You're driving me nuts!
-我可不想坐疯婆子开的车 -你快把我搞疯了！
Get on the passenger side! I'm sending this kid to Bolivia in a box!
滚到旁边去！ 我要将这小鬼装箱寄到玻利维亚去！
Can we....
我们能不能…
Ginger called me.
金吉儿打给我
NICKY: I just told you she called me. SAM: What'd she want?
-我说她打给我 -她想怎样？
She was afraid to call you.
她不敢打给你
She's with that cocksucker again. They got Amy.
她又跟那败类在一起了 艾美在他们手上
She wants to come back, but she's afraid you're gonna whack her out.
她想回来，可是她害怕你会杀了她
They're gonna kidnap my kid. What do you want?
他们想绑架我的孩子 你觉得我会怎样？
I know. Why didn't you come to me? This is family. It ain't business.
我知道，你怎么不来找我？ 这是家务事，不是公事
Meanwhile, you made calls back home. It makes us look bad out here.
你却打电话回老家 这样让我们很难看
Back and forth, this one and that one.
这样来来回回
In the meantime, she's gone anyway. Am I right?
在这期间她也一样会跑了 不是吗？
What am I going to do with this woman?
我该拿这女人怎么办？
SAM: Driving me fucking crazy. NICKY: I think if you...
-快把我搞疯了 -我觉得你…
assure her that she's gonna be all right, she'll come back.
应该保证不会动她，她才会回来
Driving me fucking crazy.
简直被她搞疯了
NICKY: Once you get her here, think about it.
她回来后你再从长计议
Wait till you get the kid back. She wants to come back.
最起码先把孩子弄回来 她也想回来
That's the main thing here.
这才是重点
You want your kid, don't you?
你要孩子不是吗？
SAM: Hello.
喂
Hi, it's me. Just who you wanted to talk to, right?
是我，你迫不及待 想跟我讲话吧？
Listen, I'm not gonna ask you where you are.
听着，我不会问你人在哪儿
Just, please, put Amy on a plane to get her here right away.
只是请你将艾美马上 送上飞机回来
SAM: That's all I'm asking. GINGER: Do you....
-我别无所求 -你…
I mean, I don't think she should go by herself.
我是说，我不觉得 她应该一个人回去
What do you mean?
你这是什么意思？
What I mean is--
我是说…
Do you think if I came back....
如果我回去…
Do you think you could forgive me?
你可以原谅我吗？
I gotta tell you, I don't know.
老实说，我不知道
I understand that.
我了解
I know I fucked up.
我知道我搞砸了
-What about the money? Where's the box? -I gotta tell you...
-那钱呢？盒子呢？ -老实说…
I made some mistakes, and I spent some money.
我做错事了 我花了一些钱
SAM: What's it under? GINGER: Pretty serious.
-少很多吗？ -蛮多的
SAM: How serious? GINGER: It's under $25,000.
-多少 -两万五以下
SAM: It's under $25,000? GINGER: Yeah.
-两万五以下？ -对
SAM: The $2 million is still there? GINGER: Yeah, I got the rest.
-剩下的两百万还在吗？ -在，其他的都还在
Okay, no big deal. That's okay.
好吧，没关系
He got his $25,000.
他拿了两万五
That I'll live with. Any more, I couldn't.
我可以接受，再多就不行了
Okay.
好
All right, all right. Where are you? I'll send a plane for you right away.
好啦，你在哪里？ 我马上派飞机去接你
Hi, Sam.
嗨，山姆
So what'd you do with it?
你拿去干嘛了？
With what?
什么？
With the money.
钱啊
He needed some clothes.
他需要些衣服
$25,000 for clothes?
两万五买衣服？
He wanted a watch, too.
他还要了只表
$25,000 for clothes and a watch?
两万五买衣服和表？
GINO: Good evening, signora. This way.
晚安夫人，这边请
SAM: The good part was I had Amy back.
好事是艾美回来了
So we went home, had the housekeeper stay over, put the kid to bed.
我们回家，请管家来过夜 然后送孩子上床
I calmed myself down, and we went to dinner.
我逼自己冷静 然后我们出门吃饭
I tried to keep things nice and civil...
我试着让一切缓和…
but $25, 000 for three suits?
但是两万五买三套西装？
That doesn't make much sense.
这不太合理
First of all, he's not gonna wear $1,000 suits.
第一点，他不可能穿 一千元一套的西装
Let's say he did, which he won't.
就算假设他穿，虽然他不会
How you gonna get fitted for 25 suits in three days?
三天内怎么可能 量身订做25套西装？
I mean, how could you get fitted that fast?
怎么可能量得那么快？
I can't get fitted that fast, and I pay twice as much.
我付两倍的钱都不可能那么快
I bought him a watch, too.
我还帮他买了只表
But even if you bought him a really nice watch, one that he thought was nice...
就算是买了只好表 一只他认为是好的表…
he doesn't know what the fuck a good watch is.
他根本不知道好表长什么样子
Say you go $5,000 to $12,000 at the most, which is impossible for him.
假设表价在五千 最多一万二，对他来说也不可能
Plus, at the most, three suits, $1,000 apiece. That still leaves what?
加上三套一千一套的西装 还剩多少？
-Around $10,000? -Would you knock it off, Sam?
-差不多一万左右 -山姆，可以停止吗？
SAM: I'm just trying to figure it out. GINGER: There's nothing to figure out.
-我只是想算清楚 -没什么好算的
I'm home. We're working it out.
我回家了，我们在协调
But I've been told before, "We're working it out."
可是我以前也听过 “我们在协调”
You think that you're home...
你以为你回家…
after what you just put me through with Amy, is a favor to me?
在你对我与艾美所做的一切后 算是给我面子吗？
Counting the watch, let's say another $4,000 for expenses this weekend...
加上表，假设你们这个周末 花费了四千好了…
of which you must have had a good time.
我相信你们一定过得很愉快
I know he did. That's for sure.
至少我很确定他很愉快
I know that fucking piece of shit had a good fucking time.
我知道那狗杂种一定很快乐
On my money.
花我的钱
You might as well have fucked him, which you probably did anyway.
你干脆就跟他上床算了 你八成也这样做了
You're looking at me a certain way.
你看我的表情很奇怪
You're teary-eyed.
你热泪盈眶
You're upset. You're a good actress, you know that?
你很难过 你真是个好演员
Good fucking actress.
真他妈的演得好
SAM: You can fucking get pity out of people.
你可让任何人可怜你
I'm not a john. You understand?
但我不是嫖客，好吗？
You always thought I was, but I'm not. And I'm not a sucker.
你一直以为我是 但我不是，我也不是冤大头
That fucking pimp cocksucker.
那可恶的拉皮条狗杂碎
He's lucky I didn't kill him last time.
上次没杀了他是他命好
SAM: Lucky he's fucking living. If you would have stayed with Amy...
他活着是命好 若你们带着艾美…
and you had run away, he would have been dead.
然后走人的话 他就死定了
Both of you. Dead. Dead.
你们俩都死定了
GINGER: No, it isn't fair.
不，不公平
He doesn't come home at night. What is the big fucking deal?
他晚上根本不回家 有什么了不起？
I go.... Listen, I just can't fucking take it.
我走，听着，我真的受不了
Why should I fucking take it? That wasn't the deal.
我为什么要忍受？ 这不是我们的协议
He acts like I'm the only one around here with a fucking past.
他一副好像就只有我有过去的样子
He'll never let me live it down.
他永远都不让我忘记
Well, yes, I have tried. Of course I've tried.
是，我试过，我当然试过
What the fuck do you think I came back here for?
你以为我为什么回来？
No, I'm not. I want to have him killed.
不，我不，我想杀了他
GINGER: I want him killed. I've had it.
对，我要杀了他 我受够了
So are you with me on this?
你要帮我吗？
You want to get rid of me? Here I am.
你想干掉我？我就在这儿
Go ahead. Get rid of me.
来啊，干掉我啊
SAM: Hello. GINGER: Yes, I do!
-喂 -是的！
GINGER: I fucking hate you! I can't take it anymore!
我恨死你了！我受不了了！
Yes, I want to kill you! I hate your fucking guts!
是，我要杀了你！ 我恨死你了！
SAM: You hate my guts? I want you to come with me now!
你恨死我了？ 我要你现在就给我过来！
SAM: I want you out of here!
我要你滚！
Take your fucking bag and get out of here!
拿好行李给我滚！
I'll go, but I want my money right now!
我会走，但我现在就要我的钱！
-You'll get your money! Don't worry. -The arrangement is over.
-你会拿到钱的！别担心 -协议结束了
SAM: No kidding! GINGER: And I still get my money.
-废话！ -我还是拿得到钱
I need some cash now! You can't just put me in the street!
我现在就要一些现金 你不能就这样把我赶出街！
You've never been straight with me ever since I met you!
你从一认识我就没诚实过！
You never even loved me in the first place!
你从一开始就没爱过我！
I need eyes in the back of my head with you, you bitch!
跟你这婊子一起 我连脑后都得长眼睛！
How could I love you? You treat me like I'm your fucking dog!
我怎么爱你？ 你对我像对条狗一样！
SAM: You're lower than a dog! GINGER: Fuck you!
-你连狗都不如！ -去你的！
Here! Is this enough money?
拿去！够了没？
Will it last you two fucking days? Take it!
可以活两天吗？拿去！
-Greedy bitch. Take the fucking money. -I'm going to the bank...
-贪得无厌的婊子，钱拿去 -我要去银行…
-and I'm getting my jewelry, too! -It opens at 9:00 a.m. Be there.
-我还要去拿我的珠宝！ -早上9点开，去拿啊
Don't send your guys down there to stop me! I mean it!
别叫你的人去阻止我！ 我说真的！
I guarantee you, I will not stop you.
我向你保证我绝对不会阻止你
You're not getting rid of me with one fucking suitcase!
你别想以一口箱子就打发我！
Come back tomorrow and get the rest. Just get out of here.
剩下的明天再回来拿吧 给我滚
GINGER: I'm taking Amy. SAM: You're not.
-我要带艾美走 -不行
I am. I'm waking her up right now.
我要，我现在去叫她
SAM: You're stoned. You're a junkie. Get out of here.
你w药了，你这个毒虫 给我滚
I am not! She's my daughter, too!
我不是！她也是我女儿！
SAM: Send my lawyers a letter, god-fucking-damn you!
写信给我的律师吧，去你的！
GINGER: You're not getting away with this! You're not gonna cut me out of my end!
你跑不掉的！ 你别想不遵守你的诺言！
GINGER: Fucker!
王八蛋！
SAM: The funny thing was, after all that, I didn't want her to go.
好笑的是，经过这么多事 我还是不想让她走
She was the mother of my kid. I loved her.
她是我孩子的妈，我爱她
Later, I realized I didn't want to give her the money because if I did...
后来，我发现我并不想 将钱给她，因为我若给了…
I knew I'd never see her again.
我知道将再也见不到她
Have a good day at school, okay?
在学校要开开心心的喔
Okay, angel.
好的，天使
From now on, I have to know where you and Amy are at all times.
从现在起，我随时都得知道 你与艾美在哪儿
SAM: Here's a beeper.
这是呼叫器
I want you to keep it on you.
我要你拿着
It's very light.
很轻
SAM: So I can call you whenever I have to.
让我可以随时打给你
Okay?
好吗？
NICKY: What are you supposed to do? What do you wanna do?
你能怎么做？ 你想怎么做呢？
You want to stay the way you are? You can't do that.
你想就像现在这样吗？ 你也不能啊
Two people don't get along, at some point you gotta call it....
两个人若合不来 总要有人出来说…
It's not my business, but I think that's what you gotta do.
这不关我的事 但我觉得你应该这样做
You're right. I know.
你说得对，我知道
-I was just-- -What?
-我只是… -什么？
-Nothing. -What were you gonna say?
-没什么 -你想说什么？
-I don't-- -Tell me what you were gonna say.
-我不… -告诉我你本来想说什么
Yeah?
真的？
I was thinking maybe you know somebody at the bank...
我在想说你有没有认识 银行的人…
who could help me get my jewelry out?
可以帮我把珠宝拿出来？
There's a lot of money in there.
有很多钱在那儿
I'd be willing to take care of anybody who helped me out.
我愿意重赏任何可以帮助我的人
Let me think about that.
我想想办法
Let me see who I got. Gotta get somebody I can trust.
我看看能找谁 一定得是可以信得过的人
You know he's never gonna give me my jewelry.
你也知道他是不会把珠宝给我的
He holds that key so tight, he's probably got it stuck up his ass.
他把那把钥匙抓得很紧 我看就差没藏到屁眼里去了
You're right. That's Sammy.
说得好，真像是山姆
And he's probably got it there, too.
搞不好真的就在那儿
He's so fucking lucky. I could have buried him.
他真是命大，我本可以埋了他
I could have gone to Europe and taken the baby.
我本可以去欧洲并把孩子带走
Then he'd have tracked me down, and he'd have killed me.
那他可能就会找到我 并把我杀了
No, he wouldn't. I would have.
不，他不会，但我会
-He'd have been right, too. Seriously. -Come on.
-不过他是没错 -别闹了
You don't take a guy's kid and then take off.
你不能就这样把他的孩子带走
I didn't. I did, but then I did exactly what you told me to do, and I came back.
我没有，我本来有 但后来我照你所说的回家了
You did. You're right. I like that.
你是，你照做了，很好
-That's what I like, you did the right thing. -I did what you told me to.
-我喜欢这样，你做对了 -我听了你的话
-Yes, you did. -You always tell me the right thing to do.
-是的 -你总会告诉我正确的做法
He really fucked himself up out here, didn't he?
他真的在这儿把自己搞砸了 不是吗？
-He sure did. -Everything went to his head.
-是啊 -这一切改变了他的想法
Changed.
改变了
-He did. He ain't the same person. -No, he's not.
-他变了，他已不是同一个人了 -不，他不是
-He really thinks who the fuck he is. -Exactly.
-他真的觉得自己多了不起 -的确
He hates me.
他恨我
He hates my fucking guts.
他好恨我
Come on, you're a toughie. You can take this.
别这样，你最坚强了 这不算什么
NICKY: Don't cry. GINGER: I'm not as tough as you think I am.
-别哭 -我没你想像的坚强
Yes, you are.
你有
I'm not, and he scares the shit out of me.
我没有，我好怕他
-I never know what he's gonna do. -Come on.
-我永远都不知道他下步要干嘛 -别这样
-Don't be scared. -I need some help.
-别怕 -我需要帮助
I need some help.
我需要帮助
You gotta help me.
你得帮我
I need a new sponsor, Nicky.
我需要个新靠山
I do. I need a new sponsor.
真的，我需要个新的靠山
-Is that what you want? -Yeah.
-这是你想要的？ -是啊
-A sponsor?
-靠山？ -是的
Okay. Don't worry about it. Nobody will fuck with you anymore.
好，别担心 没人敢动你的
I'll take care of you.
我会照顾你的
GINGER: Thank you. NICKY: It's what you want, isn't it?
-谢谢你 -这是你想要的，不是吗？
MAN: That's Ace's wife.
艾斯的老婆
MAN 2: This is great for the boss.
这给老板看太好了
GINGER: Hi. SAM: Hi.
-嗨
SAM: You didn't answer your beeper. GINGER: I threw it away.
-你没回呼叫器 -我丢了
You threw it away?
你丢了
I tried to do it. I know that you want me to, but....
我试着带着 我知道你希望我带着…
I'm driving down the freeway and the fucking thing beeps.
可是我开在高速公路上时 它也在响
GINGER: I'm in a restaurant, it's embarrassing.
在餐馆也是，很丢脸
I don't want to do it anymore. Where's Amy?
我不要再带了，艾美呢？
SAM: I put her to bed. GINGER: I got your cigarettes.
-她睡了 -我买了你要的烟
GINGER: Oscar wants you to call him.
奥斯卡要你跟他连络
SAM: So who'd you go to lunch with? GINGER: Jennifer.
-你跟谁吃的午餐？ -珍妮佛
SAM: Where'd you go? GINGER: To the Riviera.
-去哪儿吃？ -欧华赌场
What'd you have?
吃什么？
GINGER: I had a salad. SAM: What did Jennifer have?
-我叫沙拉 -珍妮佛呢？
She had the same.
她也一样
Okay.
好
I want you to call Jennifer...
我要你打给珍妮佛…
and I want you to tell her to tell you what you had for lunch.
我要你叫她告诉你 你午餐吃了什么
I'm gonna listen in on the other line.
我从另一线听
-Why do you want to do that? -You know why I want to do it.
-你干嘛这样？ -你知道为什么
-Just do it. -Fine.
-照做就是了 -好啦
I just need to get the bowl for my thing.
我只是需要拿个碗装这个
The line's busy.
忙线中
There's nobody there.
没人在
JENNlFER: Hello? SAM: Hello, Jennifer. It's Sam.
-喂 -喂，珍妮佛，是山姆
All right. I didn't have lunch with Jennifer.
好啦，我没跟珍妮佛吃饭
Who were you with?
那你跟谁？
I was with somebody.
一个人
I know you were with somebody. Who was it?
我知道你有伴 是谁？
I just hope it's not someone who I think it might be.
我只希望不是我想的那个人
I just hope it's not that.
我只希望不是他
SAM: I knew she fucked around.
我知道她在外面乱来
Yeah, she did what she did, and I did what I had to do, but...
她做她做的 我也做我要做的…
Jesus, Nicky was the worst thing she could have done.
可是，天啊 尼奇是她所能做出最糟糕的事
What if he won't stop?
若他不愿停呢？
SAM: It could get us both killed.
我们两个可能都会没命
I can back him off.
我可以让他停
SAM: She was very convincing when she wanted to be.
她在必要时可以很有说服力
And this is how she backed him off.
她是这样让他停的
Hey, Ginger.
嗨，金吉儿
Don't forget, if you're challenged...
别忘了，要是他追问你
if he asks anything, deny everything.
不管他问你什么，你都不要承认
You understand? I don't want him bringing beefs back home.
懂不懂？ 我不想他跟老家那头抱怨
That could really cause a serious problem.
这样麻烦就大了
Got to be careful. He's not dumb, you know?
得小心点 他也不是蠢蛋，懂吗？
You hear what I'm saying, right?
你懂我的意思吧？
I know. You don't have to tell me that.
我知道，你不用告诉我
Do you think I'm stupid?
你当我白痴吗？
Do I think you're stupid? No.
我当你白痴？不
I think you're beautiful. But I gotta go.
我当你是美女，但我得走了
SAM: By this time, Nicky had things so fucked up on the streets...
这时候，尼奇在外的事已经乱到…
that every time Marino went back home, the packages got smaller and smaller.
每次玛雷诺回老家时 皮箱都越来越小
It got to the point, when he walked into the place...
后来甚至严重到 他每走入一个地方…
he didn't know whether he was going to be kissed or killed.
他都不确定会被亲还是被杀
REMO: Frankie, I want to ask you something.
法兰克，我有事问你
It's private.
私人的事
But I want you to tell me the truth.
我要你说实话
Of course, Remo.
当然，利蒙
I want you to tell me the truth, mind you.
我要你说真话
I always tell you the truth, Remo.
我对你一直都很诚实，利蒙
Frankie, the little guy...
法兰克，小矮个…
he wouldn't be fucking the Jew's wife, would he?
他不是在搞犹太人的老婆吧？
Because if he is, it's a problem.
因为若他有，就是个问题
FRANK: What could I say?
我能说什么？
I knew if I gave the wrong answer...
我知道若我答错了…
Nicky, Ginger, Ace, all of them could have wound up getting killed.
尼奇、金吉儿与艾斯全部 都可能被干掉
Because there's one thing about these old-timers.
因为这些老家伙们有个禁忌
They don't like any fucking around with the other guys' wives.
就是他们不能忍受搞别人老婆
It's bad for business.
那很难看
So I lied, even though I knew that by lying to Gaggi...
所以我撒谎 虽然我知道对盖吉撒谎…
I could wind up getting killed, too.
可能会害我也被干掉
-No, I ain't seen anything like that. -Are you sure?
-不，我没见到这种事 -你确定？
I'm positive.
我很确定
Remo, things are very fucked up down there.
利蒙，那边现在可是一团糟
I know. That's why I'm asking.
我知道，所以我才问你
You see, my main concern is Nicky.
我最担心的是尼奇
I want to know if he's doing all right, if he's okay.
我想知道他最近如何 过得好不好
-He's good, he's fine. -I'm asking you to keep an eye on Nicky.
-他很好 -我要你看好尼奇
-Do it for me. -No problem.
-为了我 -没问题
You see, I wouldn't want to be jeopardizing anything for our friends.
你知道，我不想得罪我们的朋友
You understand?
你懂吗？
-I understand. -Okay.
-我懂了 -好
Frankie, you're a good boy.
法兰克，你是个好孩子
Thanks, Remo.
谢了，利蒙
SAM: By now, Nicky and his crew had already hit rock bottom.
这时，尼奇与他那帮人 已经跌到谷底了
Vegas really got to him.
赌城真的改变了他
The booze, the coke, the broads.
酒精、可卡因、女人
I mean, he got sloppy.
我是说，他开始大意
He just wasn't the same Nicky anymore.
他再也不是以前那个尼奇了
FRANK: You must've drank too much. NICKY: Fuck yourself.
-你喝太多了 -去你的
SAM: One night, he had to belt a guy three times...
有晚他对个家伙开了三枪…
before the guy finally went down.
才将他打死
In the old days, Nicky would've decked him with one shot.
要是以前，尼奇只要一枪就够了
You add this into the mix....
加上这些成份…
Maybe Vegas got to all of us.
可能赌城改变了我们全部
His crew followed him right over the edge.
他那帮人随着他一起堕落
They were all tuned up half the time on coke.
他们每天一半的时间 都在吸毒中渡过
They started doing stupid things. The worst was Blue.
他们开始做些蠢事 尤其是布鲁
-What do you guys want? -Police! Stay in the car!
-你们要干嘛？ -警察！别下车！
SAM: He never knew when to keep his mouth shut.
他从不知道何时该闭嘴
COP: Drop the gun! BLUE: Fuck you!
-放下枪！ -去你的！
SAM: The cops shot Blue...
条子朝布鲁开枪…
because they thought his hero sandwich was a gun.
因为他们以为 他手上拿的潜艇堡是手枪
They could have been right, but who knows?
他们也许是对的 但谁知道？
COP: Jesus Christ! What gun? He's got a fucking hero sandwich here.
天啊，什么枪？ 他手上拿的是潜艇堡
COP 2: What do you want? It's pitch black.
不然能怎样？这儿这么黑
COP 2: It's tinfoil. It looked like a gun! COP: You moron!
-是锡箔纸，看来像枪！ -你这智障！
COP: I'll be doing paperwork for two months! COP 2: What'll we do?
-我得办两个月的公文！ -该怎么办？
COP 2: Sorry! COP: You jerk-off!
-抱歉！ -白痴！
SAM: To make matters worse... to get even, Nicky's crew got stoned one night...
更糟的是，为了报仇 尼奇那帮人有天晚上…
and started shooting up the cops' houses.
吸毒后跑去扫射警察的家
It got to the point where they couldn't talk in the Gold Rush anymore...
后来严重到连在掏金热潮里 都不方便讲话…
because the Feds put a wire in the wall.
因为联邦调查局在窃听
Even when they talked outside, they had to cover their mouths...
他们连在外面讲话时 都得捂住嘴
because the Feds brought in lip readers.
因为联邦调查局请来了 读唇语的专家
Nicky found out about it from a teller who owed him money.
尼奇是从一个欠他钱的 银行职员那听说的
FRANK: He asked me again about you and the Jew's wife.
他又问我你跟犹太人老婆的事
NICKY: Walk, walk, walk. What'd you say?
走、走、走 你说什么？
FRANK: He asked me again about you and the Jew's wife.
他又问我你跟犹太人老婆的事
NICKY: What'd you tell him?
你怎么说？
FRANK: I told him I didn't know nothing.
我说我不知道
FRANK: Jiggs and Tony Gorilla said if you did anything, you're fucked up.
杰葛与东尼国理拉说 你要是有做什么就完了
NICKY: You think he's going home making a beef behind my back?
你想他是不是背着我回老家 跟他们抱怨？
FRANK: No, you would have heard something.
不，若有的话 你应该早听到风声
NICKY: What's to stop him? FRANK: I know.
-有什么阻止他这么做？ -是啊
NICKY: I don't trust him anymore, but they'd never okay anything.
我不相信他了 但老大们不会答应我干掉他的
FRANK: But they keep asking about it.
但他们一直在问
NICKY: Sure they're asking. They earn with the prick.
当然会问罗 他们靠他赚钱
NICKY: I got a funny feeling he's gonna start a war or something.
我有种感觉 他好像想引发战争
NICKY: I'm not sure yet. But you know what I want you to do?
我还不确定 但你知道我要你干嘛吗？
NICKY: Who's this guy?
这是谁？
FRANK: That ain't nobody.
谁都不是
NICKY: You know what I want you to do?
你知道我要你干嘛吗？
NICKY: Get some guys to dig a hole in the desert and show you where it's at.
找个人在沙漠挖个洞 要他告诉你在哪儿
FRANK: Angelo and Buster. NICKY: I'm not sure yet.
-安基罗与本斯特 -我还不确定
FRANK: They'll do it. NICKY: When I'm ready, I'll say the words:
-他们肯干的 -我准备好时会跟你说…
"Go see the Jew." And you make it disappear. Know what I mean?
“去找犹太人” 然后你就让他消失，懂不懂？
FRANK: Let me know. But you gotta be ready.
让我知道，但你得准备好
FRANK: You know what I'm talking about?
你懂我的意思吗？
NICKY: Did I say to do anything yet?
我有叫你行动吗？
NICKY: I said I'm not sure. I'll let you know. I want to think about it.
我说了我不确定，我会让你知道 我得再想想
NICKY: Where are these pricks at? They're in the motel?
那些浑蛋呢？ 在旅馆里吗？
FRANK: There or in the fucking bank. I don't know. All over the joint.
那里或是银行 我也不知道，到处都是
I'll be right back.
我马上回来
Any calls for me, give them to Mr. Sherbert.
有我的电话就转给雪伯提先生
-Sure, Mr. Rothstein. -I'm going home for a few seconds.
-好的，罗斯坦先生 -我回家一会儿
He's on his way home.
他要回家了
Okay.
好的
Hello? Ginger?
喂？金吉儿？
AMY: Help, Daddy! SAM: Amy!
-爸爸，救命！ -艾美！
SAM: Amy, open the door! AMY: I can't! I'm tied!
-艾美，开门！ -我不能，我被绑起来了！
AMY: Dad! SAM: What happened?
-爸爸！ -发生什么事！
SAM: Who did this to you? AMY: Mommy.
-是谁？ -是妈妈
I'm gonna get a knife and cut you loose.
我去拿刀把绳子切断
AMY: No, please! SAM: Okay, I'm gonna be right back.
-不要走！ -没关系，我马上回来
SAM: When did this happen, honey? AMY: I don't know.
-什么时候的事，甜心？ -我不知道
What time did your mother do this? When did she leave?
你妈什么时候做的？ 她什么时候走的？
AMY: I don't know.
我不知道
SAM: Hello? NICKY: Sammy.
-喂？ -山姆
SAM: Yeah. Who's this? NICKY: Me.
-你是谁？ -是我
NICKY: You okay? SAM: No, I'm not okay.
-你还好吗？ -我不好
-How'd you know I was here? -I just wanted to talk to you.
-你怎么知道我在？ -我只想跟你谈谈
Ginger's missing. She tied Amy up and locked her in her room.
金吉儿不见了 她将艾美绑在房间并上锁
I don't know where she is.
我不知道她在哪儿
Well, listen, Ginger's here at the Leaning Tower with me.
听着，金吉儿在比萨斜塔 跟我一起
She's there with you?
她在你那儿？
NICKY: Yeah, she's here. SAM: I'll be right over.
-是，在这儿 -我马上来
All right.
好的
-Coming over. -Great.
-过来了 -非常好
Don't make a scene, all right?
别闹事，好吗？
I want to talk to that Irish bitch.
我要跟那爱尔兰婊子说话
She's trying to save your marriage.
她想要挽救你们的婚姻
Nicky, I want to talk to that fucking bitch.
尼奇，我要见那婊子
Be fucking nice. Calm.
客气点，冷静
Be nice. Don't fuck up in here.
客气点，别搞砸了
GINGER: Hi. SAM: Are you out of your mind?
-嗨，山姆 -你疯了吗？
You tie up our kid and lock the door? Are you out of your mind?
你把我们的孩子绑起来还锁门？ 你疯了吗？
That's our child. Are you out of your mind?
那是我们的孩子 你他妈的疯了吗？
It was just for a little while. The baby-sitter wasn't there.
只是一下下而已 褓姆刚好不在
I ought to have you committed. You do that again and I'll--
我真该送你去疯人院 你下次再试试看…
I was just gonna be out for a little while.
我只是出去一会儿
She was asleep. I was gonna be back... SAM: Listen.
-她睡了，我一会就要回去的… -听着
-...before she even woke up. -Listen, you fucking cunt...
-在她醒来前 -听着，你这贱货…
let me tell you something.
让我告诉你
Listen to me. Listen carefully.
听我说，听清楚
You ever touch her again or do anything like that again...
你别想再动她一根汗毛…
I'll fucking kill you, pure and simple.
我会杀了你，就这么简单
SAM: You hear me? Pure and simple.
你听到没？就这么简单
GINGER: Why don't you let me go? SAM: I'll kill you.
-你为何不让我走？ -我会杀了你
SAM: You fucking whore. I'll sign anything you want me to sign.
-你这个婊子 -你要我签什么都行
I just want the key to my jewelry, and you to let me go.
我只要珠宝的钥匙 还有让我走
SAM: Want your jewelry? GINGER: Let me go.
-你想要珠宝？ -放我走
And let you disgrace me, you pig?
然后让你丢我的脸，你这只猪？
SAM: Get up and be a mother.
你给我起来当个母亲
Get in the car and go home right now.
立刻上车回家
Get up and get in....
起来…
-Get up. -I wouldn't do that if I were you.
-起来 -我要是你就不会这样
-I wouldn't do that-- -Get up!
-我要是你就… -起来！
Are you threatening me?
你在威胁我吗？
I'll fucking kill you in this place. Get up and go home.
我现在就可宰了你 起来回家
I'm going!
我要走了！
Now you need approval from him to go home?
你现在要他批准才能回家？
So what? Who blew you in the parking lot before you came in?
那又怎样？你从停车场进来前 又是谁在帮你吹喇叭？
You make me sick, you fuck.
你让我作呕
-Once a hooker, always a hooker. -Oh, fuck you!
-一日为娼，终生为娼 -去你的！
Fuck you, Sam Rothstein!
去你的，山姆罗斯坦！
Billy Sherbert, please. Put him on.
找比利雪伯提
BILLY: Who's this? SAM: Listen, I'll explain later.
-谁啊？ -听好，我待会再解释
You got a gun at home? Bring it over right away.
你家里有枪吗？ 马上带过来
-Take it easy. I'll do it. -Okay.
-冷静点，我带 -好
Leave it where it is!
就留着吧！
Where is he? I want that Jew bastard killed!
他在哪儿？我要杀了那犹太王八蛋！
Hide her car in the back.
把她的车藏到后面去
GINGER: There's no reason to hide my car! He already knows!
不需要藏我的车！ 他早就知道了！
Supposing he goes back home and makes a fucking beef?
他要是回去告状怎么办？
-I gotta know exactly what you said. Tell me. -Me? Nothing. I said....
-我得知道你到底跟他说了什么 -我？我说…
I said, no. Everything he said, I just kept saying no.
我说没有，不管他说什么 我都说没有
I told you this was fucking dangerous.
我早跟你说这很危险
I said, "Ginger, this is a dangerous situation. Be very careful."
我说：   “金吉儿，状况很危险 你一定要小心”
If it's so fucking dangerous, why don't you kill him?
若真这么危险，你为何不杀了他？
I'm not gonna kill him. Shut the fuck up.
我不会杀他，闭上你的嘴
-Have him killed, and get it over with! -Don't be such a fucking smart-ass!
-杀了他，做个了断！ -别自做聪明！
I know the guy 35 years, I'm gonna whack him for you?
我跟他35年的交情 我会为了你干他？
NICKY: Motherfucker.
王八蛋
-I knew it. -What about my money?
-我就知道 -那我的钱呢？
How the fuck am I gonna get your money now?
我现在怎么帮你拿钱？
You think he'll give you money? Are you out of your mind?
你还以为他会给你钱吗？ 你疯了吗？
-Look what you did to this guy. -What?
-看看你怎么对他的 -什么？
If you'd just kept your fucking mouth shut.
你只要闭上你的嘴
What's the use! I should have never got involved--
现在有个屁用！ 我真不该淌混水的…
Hey! You motherfucker, you!
喂！你这浑蛋！
GINGER: You fucker! NICKY: Get the fuck out!
-你浑蛋！ -给我滚！
GINGER: No! NICKY: Get down there! Take it easy!
-不！ -下去，冷静点！
NICKY: I shouldn't have gotten involved with this nut!
我根本不该管这疯子的！
FRANK: You'll kill her. Take it easy.
你会杀了她，冷静点
NICKY: Get her out of here.
把她弄出去
FRANK: Let's go.
走吧
I don't need you! I'll get my own fucking money!
我不需要你！ 我自己会拿到我的钱！
I'm going to the FBI! I'm not scared anymore!
我要去找联邦调查局！ 我不怕你了！
NICKY: All right. Be careful. GINGER: You've fucked with me for the last time!
-好，自己小心 -这是你最后一次玩我！
Okay. Yeah.
好，好
NICKY: Careful.
小心啊
Come on. Get inside.
走吧，进去
Look at this. Motherfucker.
你瞧瞧，他妈的
I fucked up, Frankie. I fucked up good this time.
我错了，法兰克 我这次真的搞砸了
I should never have started with this fucking broad.
我真不该跟那荡妇搞的
Take it easy. What could you do?
冷静点，你能怎样呢？
FRANK: I mean, she threw herself at you, right?
是她自己送上门的，不是吗？
I'm in a bad fucking spot here. You know that?
我现在身处困境了 你知道吗？
A bad fucking spot.
里外不是人
SAM: I left the kid with neighbors.
我将孩子给邻居托管
I had $1 million in cash and jewels...
将近一百万的现金与珠宝…
that I gave to Sherbert to lock up in the hotel.
我交给雪伯提锁在赌场
Put this in the hotel safe and I want you to come back.
把这放进旅馆的保险柜 然后马上回来
She's alone. Take the gun and go into Amy's....
她一个人，拿着枪到艾美房间去…
SAM: Just wait there for me. GINGER: Get down here and talk to me!
-在那儿等我 -下楼见我！
You can't fucking ignore me, you motherfucker!
你不能不理我，浑蛋！
GINGER: I mean it! Come down here right now!
我说真的！ 马上给我下来！
GINGER: Get down here and talk to me, God damn it!
下来见我，妈的！
GINGER: Fuck you! Goddamn you, come out here!
去你的！你给我下来！
GINGER: I'm going to drive this fucking car through the living room!
我要将车开进客厅！
GINGER: You fucking coward! You motherfucker!
你这个懦夫！浑蛋！
GINGER: Come out here and talk to me. SAM: Will you stop it?
-出来见我 -你够了没？
SAM: You're drunk. You're on drugs. GINGER: I am not!
-你喝醉又w药 -我没有！
-You'll be sorry if you don't stop. -Don't you threaten me!
-你再不停就要后悔了 -别威胁我！
GINGER: You're not threatening me anymore!
你无法再威胁我了！
You fuck! I'm sick of you!
王八蛋！我受够你了！
I am fucking Nicky Santoro! He's my new sponsor!
我与尼克山多罗上床！ 他是我的新靠山！
How about that, you fuckhead!
怎么样，王八蛋！
What are you looking at? Fuck off!
你在看什么？滚开！
Go back inside! This is none of your business!
快进去！ 关你们屁事！
GINGER: I don't have to take your shit anymore!
我再也不要每天看你脸色了！
I'm going to the FBI! I'll go to the police!
我要去找联邦调查局！ 我要去找警察！
-I am not protecting you anymore! -Mrs. Rothstein--
-我不会再保护你了！ -罗斯坦夫人…
GINGER: He won't let me inside!
他不让我进去！
Mr. Rothstein, we've been getting some complaints about the noise.
罗斯坦先生，我们接到很多 关于噪音的抱怨
I'm trying to get in my house. He won't let me in.
我试着回我家，但他不让我进门
I won't let her in. I'm sorry, Randy.
我不让她进去，抱歉，蓝帝
I won't, the way she's behaving. GINGER: Won't let me in?
-她那样子，我不能让她进门 -不让我？
SAM: Who knows what you'll do there.
谁知道你进去会干嘛
I've been in the same clothes for two days!
我已经两天没换衣服了！
-I want to get my things! Big deal! -Okay.
-我要收拾东西！什么大不了的！ -好
Let her in to get a few things. That way she'll leave.
让她进去拿点东西，她就会走了
COP: This is half her house. SAM: I'm afraid.
-这房子一半是她的 -我不敢
GINGER: You aren't afraid! SAM: She'll destroy stuff.
-你才不怕！ -她会乱砸东西
-Let me in the house! -Hey!
-让我进去！ -喂！
-Fucker! -Hold on! Please!
-浑蛋！ -请等一下！
GINGER: You should be afraid, the way you treat me!
你这样对我，你是该害怕！
It'll make it easier on everybody.
让大家都好过点
COP: If we let her get her things, we'll be out of your hair.
若让她进去拿东西 我们大家就不打扰你了
If she calms down, I'll let her in.
她要冷静下来，我就让她进来
GINGER: I am calm! SAM: If she calms down...
-我很冷静！ -若她冷静下来…
I will let her in for five minutes...
我让她进来五分钟…
if you gentlemen will escort her out if she won't leave.
如果你们愿意在她不愿走时 护送她出去
-Can I go in? -That's not a problem.
-可以进去了吗？ -这不是问题
-Jeff, would you go in with her? -Yes. Fine! Fuck you!
-杰夫，你跟她去？ -好，好，去你的！
GINGER: You wouldn't believe how mean he is. He's locked up my papers.
你无法相信他多坏 他把我的证件都锁起来
I have to get them. Don't let him come up here...
我要拿它们 别让他上来这儿…
because I know they're in here in the desk. Fuck.
因为它们在这书桌里
GINGER: Pay attention. He could come up here at anytime.
注意点，他随时都会上楼
Are you watching for him?
你有看着他吗？
GINGER: Got them.
找到了
I don't want her in there more than a few more minutes.
我不要她在里头超过五分钟
It'll just be a couple minutes. We got other things to do, too.
很快就好了 我们也有别的事要做
He'll hurry her up.
我们会叫她快点的
-How's everything else? -Fine.
-其他都还好吧？ -很好
-How's your family? -Not bad. In fact, my wife's pregnant again.
-你那边呢？ -不错啊，我老婆又怀孕了
-Congratulations. -Thanks.
-恭喜你 -谢了
We're happy about that.
我们很开心
I just have to get this one more thing, then we can go.
我得再拿一样东西 然后我们就可以走了
GINGER: Shit! Fuck!
妈的！
GINGER: That pisses me off! Don't worry.
气死我了！别管它！
It would be great...
若能…
if you could follow me out of here...
跟我一起出去最好…
because he's been threatening me!
因为他在威胁我！
Take care. Thank you.
保重，谢谢
[Crying] I can't believe this.
我真不敢相信
GINGER: I just need to pick up a little cash. Could you come with me?
我只是需要领一些现金 你可以陪我来吗？
SAM: You've got to stop her. CHARLIE: I'm sorry, Sam.
-你得阻止她 -抱歉，山姆
CHARLIE: What can I do? SAM: She's a junkie. She's out of her mind!
-我无能为力 -她是个毒虫，根本就疯了！
She has the keys. It's still in both your names.
她有钥匙，而且你们两人名字 都在户头上
There's nothing I can do. I'd like to help...
我无能为力，我想要帮忙…
-but I can't. -Legally, she can't take it.
-但我不能 -严格说，她不能拿
SAM: She can't. Half of it is mine. CHARLIE: Listen to me.
-她不能，一半是我的 -听我说
CHARLIE: There's nothing I can do. SAM: I'm coming down.
-我爱莫能助 -我马上到
Shit! God damn it!
妈的！靠！
I'll need a bag. Could you ask the guy for the big bag?
我需要个袋子 你可以帮我要个袋子吗？
COP: Go get a bag, man. GINGER: Here.
-拿个袋吧 -拿去
-Lady, I can't take it. -You can. You've been so nice to me.
-小姐，我不能拿 -你可以，你对我好好
GINGER: Yes, just hold the top open. All right? And I can....
好，帮我打开，好吗？ 这样我就可以…
Oh, God! It's him. You have to stop him.
天啊，是他！ 你们得阻止他
'Cause he said he was gonna kill me.
因为他说他会杀了我
COP: Mr. Rothstein, wait a minute.
罗斯坦先生，等一下
COP: Hold on a second.
请等一下
SAM: She's driving away. COP: There's nothing we can do.
-她开走了 -我们不能做什么
-There's nothing we can do. -Look, look.
-你瞧瞧
You can't stop her for speeding? Look what she's doing.
你们不能抓她超速吗？ 看看她开多快
COP: Nothing we can do. She had the key. COP 2: She's on the account.
-我们不能做什么，她有钥匙 -她的名字在户头上
-Let's pull her over at that Citgo Station. -Okay. Let's do it.
-我们在加油站拦她 -好的，就这么办
-We're placing you under arrest. -For what?
-我们必须逮捕你 -为了什么？
-For aiding and abetting--
-为了协助犯罪…
-I'm just trying to leave.
-我只是要离开
SAM: After all the threats and bullshit...
在这么多威胁之后…
it turned out Ginger didn't tell them anything.
金吉儿什么都没告诉他们
But, by then, the Feds didn't need her anyway.
但那时，他们也不需要她了
They had all the pieces they needed. But I didn't do anything.
-他们已有足够的证据 -但我什么都没做
SAM: Everyone began to tumble, like dominoes. FBI! We have a warrant!
-大家就像牌九一样跟着倒 -联邦调查局！我们有拘捕令！
SAM: Between Piscano complaining on the wire...
不管是窃听器上派斯康的抱怨…
between Nicky, Ginger, me and my license...
还是尼奇、我与我的执照…
paradise. We managed to really fuck it up.
天堂就这样被我们搞砸了
NICKY JR.: Mom. JENNIFER: Someone's at the door now.
-妈 -门口他妈的有人
FBI. We have a federal search warrant.
联邦调查局，我们有搜查令
NICKY: I got wind of the pinches coming down, so I took off.
我马上知道苗头不对 所以我跑路了
Who needs to hang around for that bullshit?
谁要待在那儿找麻烦啊？
-I'm Mark Casper, FBI. -Yeah?
-我是马克凯斯伯，FBI -是吗？
Can I make a fucking phone call?
我可以打个电话吗？
Yes, but you don't have to talk to us like that.
可以，但你不用这样对我们讲话
FBI AGENT: Everybody, out of the room. Over to the alarm.
大家都出去 往警铃的方向走
NICKY: They got almost everybody else. FBI AGENT: This area is seized!
-其他人似乎都被抓了 -这地方被查封了！
-Get the master account list. -I want all those papers seized.
-去拿总户头单 -我要查封所有的文件
FBI AGENT: Put every box on the table.
将每个箱子都放到桌上
Yes. Here we are. Little craps figures.
好，在这儿，所有的数字
SAM: Green? Don't even ask.
葛林？别提了
-...$30,000 of yours. -No. That's why it wasn't valid.
-你的三万元 -不，所以不成立
I was being extorted. I'll tell you what you want to know.
我是被敲诈的 你们想知道什么就问我
PHlLlP: I've got nothing to hide. NICKY: Now for the best.
-我不需要隐藏 -最经典的是
I couldn't believe this shit. Piscano's expense reports took the cake.
我不敢相信派斯康的花费记录 竟然成了关键
Oh, this is good. NICKY: He might as well give them a blueprint.
-这太好了 -他干脆就把蓝图给他们算了
Everybody's names, addresses, dates, everything.
所有人的名字、地址、日期 一切都在上面
Thank you so much, Mr. Piscano. How considerate of you.
真是多谢你了，派斯康先生 你真是体帖
-Those are my mother's books. -You're under arrest.
-那是我妈的账目 -你被逮捕了
NICKY: What a fucking balloon head. ARTIE: What are you doing?
-真是个蠢才 -你在干嘛？
AGENT: Take it easy. WIFE: Wait!
-冷静点 -等一下！
WIFE: Wait! He's sick! COP: Move back.
-等一下，他有病！ -走开
WIFE: It's his heart! Is he breathing? COP 2: CPR now!
-是心脏，还呼吸吗？ -快人工呼吸！
SAM: Artie got so upset he had a heart attack...
艾提被搞到心脏病发…
and dropped dead right in front of his wife.
当他老婆的面就挂了
-Calm down! -No, I won't calm down!
-冷静点！ -我无法冷静！
-He's my husband! Artie! -We can't help him if--
-他是我丈夫，艾提！ -我们也不能…
SAM: At the end of the day...
最后…
they finally came to see me with the pictures.
他们终于拿照片来给我看
FBI AGENT: Why protect a friend who betrayed you?
为什么要保护一个背叛你的朋友？
SAM: But I didn't want to look at them...
但我并不想看它们…
or the guys who brought them.
或是拿照片来的人
COUNSELOR: Your Honor, as you can see, my clients are elderly and infirm.
大人，你可看见，我的客户们 都年事已大并生病
COUNSELOR: Any incarceration could pose a serious health risk.
任何的刑责都将会 严重威胁到他们的健康
NICKY: When they were arrested, some were so old...
当老大们被逮时 有些简直老到…
they needed doctors at their arraignment.
罪状认否程序时都需要医师
COUNSELOR: Pre-trial services recommends that bail remain as set.
预审时建议将保释金额 维持现额
JUDGE: Take recess. NICKY: When it looked like they'd get...
-现在休庭 -当情况看来他们似乎…
25 years to life in prison just for skimming a casino...
得为了抽头而关上25年时…
sick or no fucking sick, you knew people were going to get clipped.
不管有病没病 总有人要倒霉
So the day of the arraignment, they had this meeting in the back of the courthouse.
所以在罪状认否程序那天 他们在法庭后头开会
When something like this happens, you know how things are gonna work out.
当类似的事发生时 你已知道事情会怎样
It's always better with no witnesses. So what about Andy?
最好是不要有目击者 那安迪呢？
He won't talk. Stone is a good kid.
他不会说的，史东是好家伙
Stand-up guy just like his old man.
跟他老爸一样带种
That's the way I see it.
我是这么想的
I agree. He's solid. He's a fucking Marine.
我同意，他很强悍
He's okay. He always was. What do you think?
他没问题，一直都是 你说呢？
Look, why take a chance?
为什么要冒险呢？
At least that's the way I feel about it.
我是这么想的啦
ANDY: Call Artie. Tell him I don't care what...
打给艾提，告诉他不管怎样…
he's gotta be in my office Thursday morning.
他星期四都得来我办公室
It's done.
决定了
It's terribly important. I gotta have a conversation with him.
非常重要 我一定得跟他谈谈
NICKY: As much as they liked him, he wasn't one of us.
不管他们多喜欢他 他还不是家族一员
He wasn't Italian. As far as they knew, he could have talked.
他不是意大利人 对他们来说，他随时可能供出来
Otherwise, he'd still be alive.
要不然他可能还活着
The first one to skip was John Nance.
第一个翘头的就是约翰南斯
He found a nice, warm, secluded place in Costa Rica.
他在哥斯大黎加 找了个又好又隐密的地方
He thought nobody would find him there.
他以为没人找得到他
NICKY: But then his kid got nabbed by the Feds for drugs.
但他孩子随后因犯毒 被联邦调查局逮了
So naturally, the bosses were afraid he'd come out of hiding...
老大们当然怕他会出现…
just to save his kid and give them all up.
为了救孩子而把大家供出来
So....
所以…
Where you going, jag-off?
你想去哪里？
NICKY: But, anyway, they all had to follow.
但大家都得跟着
Everybody went down.
大家都完了
Fuck you.
去你的
NICKY: Before you knew it...
不知不觉…
anybody who knew anything wound up getting whacked.
任何知道一点小事的人 都被干掉了
GINGER: Oh, no! No!
不！不！
SAM: After Ginger took off, she wasn't much help to anybody.
金吉儿走后 她对任何人都没什么用
She found some pimps, lowlifes, druggies, and bikers in L.A.
她在洛杉矶结识了一些 皮条客、败类、毒虫与飞车党
In a few months, they went through all the money and jewels.
几个月内，他们就把 所有的钱跟珠宝花光了
After they found her body...
当他们找到遗体时…
I had a private doctor do another autopsy.
我私下请了个医生验尸
He said they gave her a hot dose.
他说他们给她打了过量的毒品
In the end, all she had left was $3, 600 in mint condition coins.
最终，她身上只剩下 价值三千六百元的全新硬币
No matter what the Feds or the papers said about my car bombing...
不管条子与文件 对我的汽车炸弹有什么评论…
it was amateur night, you could tell.
一看就知道是新手干的
Whoever it was, they put the dynamite under the passenger side.
不管是谁，他们将炸弹装在 副驾驶座下面
But what they didn't know, what nobody outside the factory knew...
他们不知道的是 除了车厂外没人知道的是…
was that, that model car was made with a metal plate under the driver's seat.
那台车的驾驶座下 多加了一块铁板
It's the only thing that saved my life.
全靠了它救我一命
The bombing was never authorized, but I suspect I know who lit the fuse.
那炸弹从没被批准 但我想我知道是谁干的
So did the powers that be.
老大们也知道吧
NICKY: How are you? BOSS: How you doing?
-你好吗？
NICKY: It took months for everything to calm down.
好几个月后一切才平息
But finally, my guys got out on bail.
但我的人终于保释出来了
The bosses wanted me to send my brother Dominick out to Vegas.
老大们要我将我小弟 多明尼送回赌城
Always the fucking dollars.
永远都是为了钱
I mean, it was still too hot for me to even go near Vegas.
我是说，我连赌城都不能踏入
So I set up a meeting with the guys way out in the sticks.
所以我在个鸟不生蛋的地方 安排大家碰面
I didn't want my brother to get fucked around. What's right is right.
我不想害我小弟 对的就是对的
They don't give a fuck about--
他们才不在乎…
THUG: Holy fucking....
去你妈的…
NICKY: What the fuck....
搞什么…
Come on, motherfucker!
来啊，王八蛋！
Tough guys! You and your fucking brother!
不是很猛吗？你跟你哥！
You fucking scumbags! No more!
你们两个浑蛋！够了！
-Frankie! -No more! You see? Watch!
-法兰克！ -够了！你看着！
NICKY: Frankie! You piece of shit! FRANK: Fuck you!
-法兰克！你这王八蛋！ -去你的！
NICKY: Fucking punk! Piece of shit!
王八羔子！狗杂种！
No!
不！
Take this motherfucker out!
把这浑蛋拖走！
He's still breathing. Leave him alone. Frankie.
他还在呼吸 别搞他了，法兰克
FRANK: All right. Strip him.
好了，脱他衣服
NICKY: No balls. You got no fucking balls.
没种，你真他妈的没种
Oh, Dominick!
多明尼！
NICKY: Dominick.
多明尼
FRANK: Come on.
来吧
THUG: Bury them? FRANK: Bury them.
-埋了他们？ -埋
SAM: The word was out.
话放出去了
The bosses had enough of Nicky. They had enough.
老大们受够了尼奇 受够了
How much were they gonna take? So they made an example of him and his brother.
他们还能忍受多久呢？ 所以拿他们兄弟俩杀鸡儆猴
They buried them while they were still breathing.
他们俩被活埋
MAN: You all right? Watch out!
你还好吗？小心！
MAN: Mister, you all right? SAM: Yeah.
-先生，你没事吧？ -没事
SAM: They had other ideas for me.
他们有别的事给我做
MEDIC: We need some help over here!
我们这儿需要帮忙！
MEDIC 2: You sure are lucky, mister.
你真是幸运
SAM: The town will never be the same.
这城市再也不一样了
After the Tangiers, the big corporations took it all over.
在坦吉乐之后，大集团全权掌管
Today it looks like Disneyland.
今日的赌城像是迪斯奈乐园
While the kids play cardboard pirates...
孩子们玩着海盗游戏时…
Mommy and Daddy drop the house payments and junior's college money...
爸爸与妈妈将房贷与大学学费…
on the poker slots.
浪费在吃角子老虎机
In the old days, dealers knew your name, what you drank, what you played.
想当年，庄家知道你的名字 喝什么酒，玩什么牌
Today, it's like checking into an airport.
今天就像是在机场登记一般
If you order room service, you're lucky if you get it by Thursday.
你要是叫客房送餐 星期四给你送到就了不起了
Today it's all gone. A whale shows up with $4 million in a suitcase...
都没了，一个人拎着 装着四百万的皮箱…
and some 25-year-old hotel school kid will want his Social Security number.
就有个25岁的旅游系大学毕业生 想要他的身份字号
After the Teamsters got knocked out of the box...
全美卡车司机工会离开后…
the corporations tore down practically every one of the old casinos.
大集团几乎将所有的旧赌场都拆了
And where did the money come from to rebuild the pyramids?
而盖新金字塔的钱是从哪来的呢？
Junk bonds.
垃圾债券
SAM: Still not sure?
还不确定？
SAM: Probable. Maybe questionable.
有可能，有些质疑
SAM: All right, let me know as soon as you can find out.
好吧，知道后立即通知我
SAM: In the end, I wound up right back where I started.
最后，我又回到了起点
I could still pick winners...
我还是会选赢家…
and I could still make money for all kinds of people back home.
也还是可以为老家 各式各样的人赚钱
And why mess up a good thing?
何必搞砸好事呢？
And that's that!
就是这样！